<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-12T18:40:03+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joining SoundCloud and Moving to Berlin]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-05T18:39:37+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/berlin-reichstag.medium.jpg" width="900"></p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t say exactly when the job search began. It began with the creation of a Note in Evernote (great tool
for this type of task). It was much different than any other job search I&rsquo;ve done, though I haven&rsquo;t done many as I tend
to stick to job for at least 4 years at a time. The key difference with this search was that I wasn&rsquo;t working, and
wasn&rsquo;t in a hurry to find a job. This allowed me to stick to some rules and a manifesto:</p>

<blockquote><p>- Being open to being located anywhere I&#8217;ve been before, and know at least someone there<br/>- Someone I know and respect must have worked there or works there now<br/>- The company must have cloud in the name ;-)</p><footer><strong>Scott Muc</strong> <cite>Job Application Criteria</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>manifesto:</p>

<blockquote><p>- People happiness over company success<br/>- Autonomy** over being embedded in a machine<br/>- Physical and mental health** over product growth<br/>- Access to beer** over location</p><footer><strong>Scott Muc</strong> <cite>Preferred Employer Manifesto</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Those set me up much better to see if the company was a fit for me. It remains to be seen, but I think that being open
about my job search, my principals, and not being in a rush will result in a much better mutual partnership. It was a
zero stress endevour and I wish more people had the same privilege to be more precise about the work they apply for.</p>

<p>After several months I interviewed with a handful of companies, but eventually I narrowed it down.</p>

<h2>Then There Were Two</h2>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/cloudfoundry.jpg" width="300">
<strong><a href="http://cloudfoundry.org/">Cloud Foundry</a></strong> &ndash; Creators of an open source <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Platform_as_a_service">PaaS</a> software that allows for companies to create
their own <a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a>. I&rsquo;m not too familiar with the details of the product. It&rsquo;s not like you take a
piece of PaaS enabling software for a test drive every day. Despite not being knowledgable about their product, my
desire to work with them grew as a result of their fantastic interview process.</p>

<p>Every interview required pairing and coding. For me, this delivered a clear idea on how they work and that they prefered
a show me don&rsquo;t tell me approach to interviewing (which I think is awesome). The first pairing
exercise was pretty simple and I was the navigator. As remote pairing exercises go, this was great.
Because I wasn&rsquo;t driving, I wasn&rsquo;t self-conscious about my IDE skills or typing. <strong>David</strong>, who interviewed me, was
clearly prepared and made the interview smooth and fun.</p>

<p>The other two interviews were both roughly around 3 hours long. I was pairing with someone on some small code change
they were assigned to do. Both of them were with code and libraries I wasn&rsquo;t familiar with (go lang, anguluarJS), but
I was amazed at how much that didn&rsquo;t seem to matter. I asked questions, got the gist of what they were trying to do,
and did my best to keep iterating forward as much as possible given my knowledge constraints. The pairs were fun to work
with and I appreciated how they were able to slow down to my level to include me in the process of solving the issue.
I&rsquo;ve learned a lot on how to conduct an interview from this process.</p>

<p>I came away really feeling like these were people I would love to work with. More than that, I loved their discipline in
XP practices. Working with Cloud Foundry, I could become an expert in this field. They also respected employees work/life
balance and that&rsquo;s crucial for me.</p>

<p>The job would be located in San Francisco, and the pay would reflect that, though the cost of living would offset it.
It&rsquo;s a city I&rsquo;ve lived in before and enjoyed. I have a lot of friends there and would be immersed in beer culture.
My role would be a developer working on pieces of Cloud Foundry. So it&rsquo;s an opportunity to develop my dev chops again.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/soundcloud.png" width="300">
<strong><a href="https://soundcloud.com/">Soundcloud</a></strong> &ndash; The only way I can describe it is Twitter for audio. I&rsquo;ve only used the basic recording
functionality of their service (<a href="https://soundcloud.com/scottmuc">my profile</a>) and do listen to a few podcasts that are hosted by them.</p>

<p>Their interview process felt a bit more ad hoc compared to Cloud Foundry. After the initial screening interview with
<strong>Chris</strong>, who I would correspond with during the whole process, there was a developer assignment.</p>

<p>I had a blast working on the dev assignment! I had the luxury of not having a job so I got to spend a decent amount of
time on it. I&rsquo;m unsure about my code, but what I enjoyed was the process of how I grew the solution. Something that you
can&rsquo;t really demonstrate with a code submission. A pairing interview would have been nice so I could better get to know
how they work on a problem. I never did get any feedback on my submission. It would be nice to receive some just to get
a better feel for how they review code and deliver feedback.</p>

<p>After that I had a few more interviews more related to the role that they had envisioned I would fill and that would be
a member of the <a href="http://continuousdelivery.com/">Continuous Delivery</a> team. When I heard that my reaction was on how that&rsquo;s a bit
of an anti-pattern. After discussing it with them, I could see the team that they have formed aligns very much with I
would do if I were asked to create a &ldquo;Continuous Delivery&rdquo; team. It was great to see a bit of a shared mindset.</p>

<p>The location would be in Berlin, and the pay also reflects that. Though the cost of living is lower. I&rsquo;ve visited Berlin
twice and really enjoyed the city. I only know a handful of people there, but it is closer to people I know from all
around the area. The beer culture is definitely a huge plus, and can be great if I meet up with beer brewers in the
community. Being part of a CD team that&rsquo;s breaking down a monolith should provide some valuable experience and put me in
a position to practice a lot more than I preach.</p>

<h2>What Did I Choose?</h2>

<p>Both opportunities aligned well with my rules and manifesto. After a week of thinking (<strong>cough</strong> over-analyzing) about
it, I decided to accept the offer from <strong>Soundcloud</strong>! That means I&rsquo;ll be moving to Berlin in January 2015.</p>

<p>My mind kept flipping back and forth. Initially I thought for sure I was going to <strong>Cloud Foundry</strong>. I had already told
friends that I was going to San Francisco. The professionalism of the interview process had me convinced
that&rsquo;s where I would be most comfortable.</p>

<p>One of my best friends taught me a trick when it comes to making choices. Flip a coin and assign each choice to a
side. Treat the coin as if it&rsquo;s deciding your fate. If what results makes you feel joy and happiness, that&rsquo;s the right
choice. If you sort of deep down wish that the other side won, then you pick the other one. She suggested it with this
decision and I chickened out. Though what I ended up doing had the same result. I created a poll and posted it on Twitter.
It didn&rsquo;t really matter what the results were, but I noticed something. One, I voted for Berlin. Two, I was cheering on
Berlin while the votes were coming in.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/strawpoll.png" width="800"></p>

<h3>Choosing What Scares You</h3>

<p>SoundCloud felt like the riskier and scarier option to me which usually means a greater chance to grow and learn. Don&rsquo;t
get me wrong, Cloud Foundry would been a great chance to grow and learn, but I felt that it would be focused in the
technology spectrum. There looks to be more potential to grow as a person with SoundCloud.</p>

<h3>Learning a Language (That&rsquo;s Not a Programming Language)</h3>

<p>I have a hidden life goal of learning a second language. When I was a coach at ThoughtWorks University I had some
tough experiences with learners that did not speak English as their first language. I want to feel and understand better
what it&rsquo;s like to speak another language. There&rsquo;s a lot of potential for transfer of knowledge (ooh, applying my
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/">Learning how to Learn</a> lessons already) when translating. SoundCloud provides German lessons as a benefit and I plan on
taking advantage of that perk.</p>

<h3>More F1</h3>

<p>Nearly the entire F1 calendar is accessible from Berlin! I can continue fulfilling my other life goal which is to attend
all F1 races in my life time. These are the tracks that I can reach by train or a short flight that I haven&rsquo;t attended
yet: Monaco, Sochi, Abu Dhabi, Bahrain, Spain, and Austria.</p>

<h3>Access to Beer</h3>

<p>This leads to another life goal. To break off from technology and have a business in the beer domain.
In my Evernote journal I had a grade on each company/location on beer alignment. Of course both locations are
exceptional locations for a beer fan. San Francisco had a bit of a higher score because I know people there that do home
brewing. I&rsquo;m sure I can find a home brew community in Berlin.</p>

<h3>Music/Audio Domain</h3>

<p>Working in the music/audio domain! At CBC it was awesome being surrounded by music nerds. Sorry, but I&rsquo;ll choose
music nerds over tech nerds. Especially as my interest in the tech world is diminishing.</p>

<h3>More Travel</h3>

<p>So many travel opportunities being in central Europe. I hope to visit my relatives in Ukraine and friends in
Switzerland, England, Turkey, Czech Republic, Germany, and Hungary. With 5 weeks of holidays I&rsquo;ll be exploring and
visiting as much as possible.</p>

<p>Also, a part of me doesn&rsquo;t want to live in the USA. Cloud Foundry is also in London, but I would
want to be at the hub of the product development which is primarily in San Francisco. There would have been an option to
move to London after a year though, but my decision making was based more on the immediate change.</p>

<h2>Show Me the Money</h2>

<p>At first I was really concerned about how much less SoundCloud offered compared to Cloud Foundry. I took a look at a
<a href="http://www.numbeo.com/cost-of-living/compare_cities.jsp?country1=United+States&amp;country2=Germany&amp;city1=San+Francisco%2C+CA&amp;city2=Berlin">cost of living</a> website and calculated that to get the equivalent of an SF salary in Berlin, it would
have to be 56.3% percent (eg: making $56,300 in Berlin is equivalent to $100,000 in SF). Comparing the salary I was
offered it&rsquo;s at 55.7%. So it&rsquo;s a little bit lower, but not as crazy low as I thought.</p>

<p>It did take me on a tangent and wonder why we tend to care so much about salaries (I really wish salaries were public, I
don&rsquo;t keep mine much of a secret). My hypothesis is that your salary is a concrete tangible thing, whereas how much you
spend is harder to determine. If you&rsquo;re in Berlin making $56,300 and spend $50,000, then you&rsquo;ve save $6,300. If you make
$100,000 in SF and spend $95,000, you&rsquo;ve actually saved less. Unfortunately figuring out the amount you spend is left to
discipline around budgets.</p>

<h3>What I Don&rsquo;t Like</h3>

<p>This means I&rsquo;m joining a company that is becoming more tied to the big labels and entering the advertising space. I&rsquo;m
hoping to learn more about how this system works so that I can learn to be a more educated critic.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>I just reread <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">my post</a> from the beginning of this career break. This post and that one seem to align really
well and it gives me comfort in my decision. I really love the cadence my life has had for almost the last 20 years.
Keep an eye here for my next steps 5 years from now. Wish me luck!</p>

<h5>Looking for work? Both companies are still hiring:</h5>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://soundcloud.com/jobs">http://soundcloud.com/jobs</a></li>
<li><a href="http://cloudfoundry.com/jobs">http://cloudfoundry.com/jobs</a></li>
</ul>


<p><em>This post took 9 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Siófok/Tihany, Italian Grand Prix, and Istanbul]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/siofok-tihany-italian-grand-prix-and-istanbul/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-02T14:18:21+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/siofok-tihany-italian-grand-prix-and-istanbul</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>August 30th &ndash; September 19</em></p>

<h3>Hungary for More (Siófok/Tihany)</h3>

<p>Remember the woman that I met at the <a href="http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix/">Dream Theater concert</a>? We have kept in touch and she promised to show me around the
Hungarian country side! She recommended <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_Balaton">Balaton Lake</a> area so I found a <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2522686">place to stay</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Si%C3%B3fok">Siófok</a> and worked
on scheduling a day to meet up.</p>

<p>Unfortunately the weather did not cooperate as it rained most of the time I was there. On the plus side, I picked up a
cold on my way from Ukraine and wasn&rsquo;t feeling very adventurous anyways. I spent 3 days enjoying the sound of the rain,
and watching all of the Harry Potter movies. I picked up some groceries the day I arrived and was able to be pretty
self-sufficient.</p>

<p>On the last day my cold was disappearing and the weather outlook was brighter. Just in time for my meet up with <strong>Orsolya</strong> and a tour of
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Veszpr%C3%A9m">Veszprém</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tihany">Tihany</a>. Both places had the European charm that I&rsquo;ve enjoyed so much on this trip.
The sun came out while walking around Inner Lake (pic 3 below). <strong>Orsolya</strong> explained what life is like in rural Hungary
and I shared stories of my life. My favourite question was when she asked how I planned my travels. I never really
thought about it, but I replied saying that it was just a combination of many little trips. With each little trip I had
to plan the transition to the next trip and the opened up opportunities for other little trips.</p>

<p>After the day I was feeling recovered from my cold, and happy to have a new friend. Then I headed back to Budapest to
catch a flight to Milano for the last F1 in my travels.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle2.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle2.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-tihany.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-tihany.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h3>Italian Grand Prix (Milano)</h3>

<p>Figured that I could fit one more F1 race in this trip! I used some points to get a <a href="http://www.marriott.com/hotels/travel/milit-milan-marriott-hotel/">free hotel</a> in Milano. The
commute to the race track is pretty long so I didn&rsquo;t really have much time to explore the city. <a href="https://twitter.com/sragu">Srini</a>, who went
to the <a href="http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix/">British GP</a> with me, got his <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schengen_Area#Schengen_visa">Shengen visa</a> and was finally able to explore outside
of Istanbul and the UK. He couldn&rsquo;t come to the race but we got to hang out in the evenings when our respective daily
activities were done.</p>

<p>At the race track there&rsquo;s an abundance of people playing versions of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shell_game">shell game</a> . I watched it for
a bit and thought it looked pretty easy. I played once and was absolutely sure of my pick and lost 50 euros. I realized
I got scammed and was initially upset. Then I realized why I played the game. I wanted to win some easy money; how was I
any different than the perpetrators of the scam? It reminded me that no matter how &ldquo;good&rdquo; you try to be, temptation is
always there. I thought I could win a quick buck and I was being just as greedy as the scam artists. I laugh at the
experience now, and see it as a valuable lesson. I spent some time watching these games and saw all the tricks they play
and now understand why it&rsquo;s called a &ldquo;confidence game&rdquo;. I could see ways to &ldquo;win&rdquo;, but I would be playing against a
person who plays for hours everyday. I think their confidence will win in the long run.</p>

<p>As I alluded to earlier, the commute to my seat was quite long. My record time to my seat was 1 hour and 40 minutes, but
it was 2 hours most of the time. One of the nice things about F1 is that they aren&rsquo;t too strict about what you can bring
to the track. Each day I bought food from a local grocery store. Below is a picture of my breakfast on race day (yes
beer at 9:00am, don&rsquo;t judge). Buying from the on track vendors is a complete rip-off. For the price of a couple beers, I
was stocked up for the day.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/milano-breakfast.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/milano-breakfast.medium.jpg" width="700"></a></p>

<p>As for the race, the weekend was full of awesome moments. I watched both GP2 and GP3 races, and the F1 race was full of
awesome passes. I was sitting at the first turn which is at the end of a very fast straight (<a href="http://www.formula1.com/races/in_detail/italy_928/circuit_diagram.html">circuit diagram</a>).
Hopefully this historic track doesn&rsquo;t close, but I am so happy that I got to experience Monza before anything happens to
the event.</p>

<p>Of course my travels wouldn&rsquo;t be complete without meeting up with <a href="https://twitter.com/iliasbartolini">Ilias Bartolini</a>, a ThoughtWorker I met when I
was in India. He&rsquo;s on a project in Milano and we caught up over dinner at <a href="http://www.pizzeriamaruzzellamilano.it/">Maruzzella</a>. Again, a reminder of the
network that grew out of working at ThoughtWorks is global and full of such wonderful people.</p>

<h3>Turkish Delight</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-view.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-view.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
The last leg of my European travels is a stay in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Istanbul">Istanbul</a> (<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vsQrKZcYtqg">not Constantinople</a>). There&rsquo;s a big ThoughtWorks
project there and was able to stay in <a href="https://twitter.com/sragu">Srini</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/noppanit">Toy&rsquo;s</a> apartment (picture of the view to the right).
I wasn&rsquo;t sure how long I was going to be there so it was nice to have the flexibility of a ThoughtWorker&rsquo;s accommodation.</p>

<p>The reason for the uncertain length is that I would be applying for my <a href="http://indianvisaonline.gov.in/">Indian visa</a> from here. I won&rsquo;t go
into too much detail, but the process was relatively painless. The website is horrible and doesn&rsquo;t work in all browsers,
but once I got my application submitted, the rest of the process was straightforward. In a little over a week I got my
visa.</p>

<p>At this point in time I was beginning the interview process for several organizations. Much of my time was spent doing
coding exercises and submitting them, or doing calls. I really felt things were going forward and that in some time I&rsquo;ll
actually have figured out where I&rsquo;ll be living after all of this traveling.</p>

<p>It was a bit of a mini reunion with several people too. I met up with <a href="http://davidpetersimon.com/">David Simon</a>, who I climbed Kilimanjaro
with. There was also a bit of a Calgary reunion where I met up with <a href="http://isa.io/">Isa Goksu</a> who was my roommate for
over a year and I probably hadn&rsquo;t seem him in over 2 years! When I met up with Isa, <a href="http://www.cengizhan.com/">Cengiz Han</a>
was also there, smoking sheesha. He too was in Calgary, usually complaining about the cold, yet both of them talked
about how much they miss the Calgary days.</p>

<p>Oh right, I&rsquo;m in Istanbul! In the slack time, I spent many days wandering around this incredible city. My friend
<strong>Rose</strong> has a <a href="http://adidav9.blogspot.in/2014/07/illustrious-istanbul.html">picture filled post</a> that better captures the beauty of the city (and of other European
cities I&rsquo;ve visited).</p>

<p>Most of my day trips started out at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taksim_Square">Taksim Square</a>, which was the space that the <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-22732139">Gezi Park Riots</a> took
place at in 2013. Taking the metro from where I was staying was easy and efficient. From there I went down <a href="http://istiklalstreet.org/">Istiklal Street</a>
which is a big shopping area. My first stop was <a href="http://istanbuleats.com/2009/04/durumzade-wrap-artists/">Dürümzade</a> which was made famous by <strong>Anthony Bordain&rsquo;s</strong>
visit. Let&rsquo;s just say I went there 3 times during my stay! The adana dürüm was one of my favourite meals in Istanbul.
The area is a maze of winding hilly streets and I was content to wander this part of the city for a long time. Some days
I would hangout at <a href="http://kronotrop.com.tr/">Kronotrop</a> which is an excellent coffee bar. There&rsquo;s wifi and friendly people who are
very open to helping out a tourist with their Turkish. The pictures below are of: Istiklal Street, small street leading
to Dürümzade, and outside of Dürümzade.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-large-street.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-large-street.small.jpg" width="385"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-small-street.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-small-street.small.jpg" width="224"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-durumzade.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-durumzade.small.jpg" width="385"></a></p>

<p>On another day I walk down further and crossed the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galata_Bridge">Galata Bridge</a> and navigated through all the
fishermen to the other side (pic 1 below, you can see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galata_Tower">Galata Tower</a> in the background). Once on Old
Istanbul side I follow the meandering alleys in the direction of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hagia_Sophia">Hagia Sophia</a> (pic 2 below). How I arrive there I
don&rsquo;t know because the roads go in many different directions and they are very crowded. I kept on having to back track
as I took many wrong turns. It was a lot of fun to be lost in the shuffle. Unfortunately I arrived there after the
museum was closed so I didn&rsquo;t get to see inside. Last destination was the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sultan_Ahmed_Mosque">Blue Mosque</a> which is probably
one of the most famous landmarks (hard to say because there are so many). I was lucky to arrive in between prayer times
and was able to go inside. It was so majestic on the inside that I believe I sat there for at least 45 minutes just
soaking in the atmosphere. I couldn&rsquo;t get a decent picture inside with my phone (which has been my only camera on this
trip). I did manage to get a decent snap as the sun was getting low on the horizon (pic 3 below).</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-fishing.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-fishing.small.jpg" width="330"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-hagia-sophia.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-hagia-sophia.small.jpg" width="330"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-blue-mosque.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-blue-mosque.small.jpg" width="330"></a></p>

<p>One day walking around beautiful Old Istanbul wasn&rsquo;t enough so I made another walking tour from Taksim Square. This
time, instead of going east to all the great mosques and monuments I kept on going South to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_Bazaar,_Istanbul">Grand Bazaar</a>.
Walking through the bazaar is like being transported in time. I used to think India was a sensory explosion, but this
place comes pretty close. It was also a &lsquo;90s time warp as I couldn&rsquo;t get the following song out of my head:</p>

<div style="width:660px;margin-left:200px;">
<iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/JCye7v79Tz0 " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Never have I felt so immersed in history. I&rsquo;ve seen some historic places in my travels. The throngs of people that
still populate these places made the history feel more alive. At some point I&rsquo;ll have to go back to Turkey when I&rsquo;m not
quite so traveled out and explore more of the countries beauty and friendly people.</p>

<h3>Onward to India</h3>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for my travels in Europe for nearly 3 months. I now have the idea of writing a post about the metrics of this
career break. It&rsquo;ll be a good way to close out the series. But not yet! Now off to India for a few months to hang out
with friends, and get re-invigorated about software development.</p>

<p><em>This post took 10 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Review - a Mind for Numbers by Barbara Oakley]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-26T13:35:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.penguin.com/book/a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/9780399165245"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/book.jpg" width="200"></a>
Over the last 4 weeks I&rsquo;ve been taking the <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a> course <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/learning">Learning how to Learn</a> on the
recommendation of my friend <a href="https://twitter.com/sragu">Srini</a>. The 2nd assignment in the course is to create a presentation or some
form of media to present an understanding of the topics. An accompaniment to the course is the book,
<a href="http://www.penguin.com/book/a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/9780399165245">A Mind for Numbers</a> by <a href="http://www.barbaraoakley.com/">Barbara Oakley</a> (the primary course instructor), which is a short read but very
insightful and full of references. I&rsquo;m thoroughly enjoying the course and love the concept around the assignment. This
blog is my way of trying to synthesize ideas that are flying around in my head, which is exactly the purpose of the
assignment.</p>

<p>Over my education and career, I feel that I have developed some pretty good habits. The book has confirmed some of these
habits and given me an understanding around why they work. It&rsquo;s also able to point out some flaws that I tend to
down-play, but now realize that they are habits I need to deal with.</p>

<h2>Core Concepts</h2>

<p>The material in the book (and the course) were broken up into easy to consume chunks (see what I did there?).
I can&rsquo;t really cover all of it here but these are the 3 concepts that really stuck with me.</p>

<h3>Chunking</h3>

<p>Chunks can be thought of as an abstraction around a collection of specific thoughts. When I speak to another developer
and I say that this code <em>makes a web request</em>, that is a chunk of knowledge that I&rsquo;ve developed. I could break that
phrase down and say: establish a TCP connection with the remote server, using the HTTP protocol send a GET request
message, the server will receive this and route it to an appropriate controller, the application code will send an HTTP
response, the client will take the results and render the HTML to the browser. Woah, that was a lot of detail, and
that&rsquo;s one example of why it&rsquo;s important to chunk knowledge.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/chunking.png"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/chunking.png" title="&#34;chunking&#34;" alt="&#34;chunking&#34;"></a></p>

<p>It wasn&rsquo;t mentioned in the book, but a lot of what I read on chunking looked like reaching the <strong>competent</strong> level on the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dreyfus_model_of_skill_acquisition">Dreyfus Model of Skill Acquisition</a>. I&rsquo;m now curious if <strong>diffuse mode</strong> is an essential part of
becoming <strong>proficent</strong> or an <strong>expert</strong> in a particular topic.</p>

<p>This section of the book has made me realize some flaws in the way I learn and I feel I fall into the trap called
<strong>illusion of competence</strong>. This can be caused by <a href="http://blog.coursera.org/post/93424900982/learning-how-not-to-learn">poor learning practices</a> (below), and I know I am guilty of many of
these. Speaking of the Dreyfus model, <strong>Erik Dietrich</strong> wrote an article about the <a href="http://www.daedtech.com/how-developers-stop-learning-rise-of-the-expert-beginner">Advanced Beginner</a>,
which is another great way of explaining the <strong>illusion of competence</strong>.</p>

<blockquote><p>* Passive rereading<br/>* Letting highlights overwhelm you<br/>* Merely glancing at a problem&#8217;s solution and thinking you know how to do it<br/>* Waiting until the last minute to study<br/>* Repeatedly solving problems of the same type that you already know how to solve<br/>* Letting study sessions with friends turn into chat sessions<br/>* Neglecting to read the textbook before you start working problems<br/>* Not checking with your instructors or classmates to clear up points of confusion<br/>* Thinking you can learn deeply when you are being constantly distracted<br/>* Not getting enough sleep</p><footer><strong>Barbara Oakley</strong> <cite><a href='http://blog.coursera.org/post/93424900982/learning-how-not-to-learn'>Learning How (Not) to Learn</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I&rsquo;ve been lucky to accidentally avoid some of these habits. As a computer savvy person for the last 25 years, I still
prefer taking my notes on paper. I&rsquo;ve always stressed sleep too. I&rsquo;m definitely guilty of passive rereading, but I&rsquo;m
getting much better now. Solving similar problems is another one I need to catch myself doing.</p>

<h3>Diffuse and Focused Modes of Thinking</h3>

<p><strong>Focused Mode</strong> &ndash; When the brain is in this mode, it&rsquo;s busy building up foundations of material for access later. I
like to think of it as going to the gym. You&rsquo;re exercising ideas and building up their strength. If you don&rsquo;t practice
them deliberately, they can lose strength. If you don&rsquo;t focus on concepts with discipline, you don&rsquo;t effectively
chunk the concepts. When you get up from your task and realize that a lot more time has gone by than you had expected,
then you know you&rsquo;ve been in the focused mode.</p>

<p><strong>Diffuse Mode</strong> &ndash; This is where synthesis of multiple ideas (or chunks) happens. Our brain is good at continuing effort, solving
problems, while our bodies are performing activities like going for a walk, running, socializing, and cooking. This is
why when struggling with a problem late at night, sleeping on it, usually results in some new insights in the morning.
You know when you have yesterdays problem figured out in the morning during your shower? That&rsquo;s the diffuse mode kicking in.
Using the workout analogy, this is like using your in-shape body to enjoy life: traveling, playing with your children,
fixing up your garden.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/diffuse-focused.jpg" width="400" title="&#34;diffuse vs focused mode&#34;" alt="&#34;diffuse vs focused mode&#34;">
What&rsquo;s important to understand is that both of these modes can&rsquo;t operate at the same time. I <a href="http://scottmuc.com/going-against-the-flow/">even wrote</a>
about this a while ago and this book has given me the knowledge to better understand what I was observing when I wrote
that post. As a developer, the state of flow (deep focused mode) has its appeal, but breaking that up so that you can
piece together your new knowledge is equally important.</p>

<p>Sometimes you&rsquo;ll hear someone say that they are a great multi-tasker. This usually results in an inability to focus!
If someone is a multi-tasker, then they are taking time away from the <strong>focused mode</strong> of operating, and thus fall into
the many ways <a href="http://blog.coursera.org/post/93424900982/learning-how-not-to-learn">not to learn</a>.</p>

<h3>Procrastination and Habits</h3>

<p>The topic of procrastination was very informative. The explanation of how dopamine effects long term beneficial actions
(<a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/intrinsic-motivation-and-magical-unicorns/201206/procrastination-and-dopamine-receptor-density">reference</a>) is insightful and can be used to influence how we develop habits. The book is full of
ideas on how prevent procrastination and here&rsquo;s my list of tactics:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Zero Notifications</strong> &ndash; this is an easy one for me as I already try to live a notification free life. My phone is
almost always on silent unless I&rsquo;m <em>expecting</em> a call or message. All my applications on my phone and computer have
notifications turned off. It&rsquo;s very hard to think of any reason why any notification would need immediate action.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://pomodorotechnique.com/">Pomodoro Technique</a></strong> &ndash; I&rsquo;ve been a fan of this process for a long time. Procrastination doesn&rsquo;t stand
a chance when the timer is on. I like to use <a href="http://lifehacker.com/pomodoro-one-is-a-free-lightweight-pomodoro-timer-for-1626504270">pomodoro one</a> on my laptop. There are 4 components of
developing a habit, and the first one is the <strong>cue</strong>. Starting the timer triggers me to go into a focused mode.
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/self-control.png"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/self-control.png" width="300"></a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://selfcontrolapp.com/">Self Control</a></strong> (pictured) &ndash; This application does a machine level block of the hostnames that you specify for a
specific time period. It runs outside of the web-browser so it&rsquo;ll block applications that talk to these services and
even killing the process or rebooting your machine won&rsquo;t get the hostname working again. I will use this every time
I&rsquo;m doing a pomodoro.</li>
<li><strong>Process over Product</strong> &ndash; Unless the task is very very small, the time allocated to a single pomodoro should be
process based. As of right now, I have on my task list the following: &ldquo;2 pomodoros of coursera project&rdquo;. This keeps
the focus on the activity and now the anxiety around the outcome. I don&rsquo;t know how long it&rsquo;s going to take to complete
this post, but I know if I chip away at it with time-boxes of focus it&rsquo;ll be completed before I know it.</li>
</ul>


<p>I like reading about other people&rsquo;s techniques and thought <a href="http://jamesclear.com/">James Clear</a> has a good
<a href="http://jamesclear.com/multipliers">blog post</a> and a good list. On my reading list is <a href="http://masoncurrey.com/Daily-Rituals">Daily Rituals</a> which looks very
interesting. One thing that seems clear, is that many productive people have developed a system and it&rsquo;s important to
discover my own.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I began reading the book before taking the course and immediately benefited from a process that is described in the
book. The book on its own is a fantastic resource and is an excellent compliment to the course. I really think taking the
course at the same time instilled a lot of the information far better than if I had only just read the book. I was
surprised when I finished the book because my Kindle reported that I was only 65% complete when I was at the end. Well
that&rsquo;s because the remainder is a massive collection of references of all the research that&rsquo;s been done on all of the
topics! It shows that the content is truly backed by science which is refreshing given all the anecdotal type of
information that&rsquo;s published on the Internet.</p>

<p>Reading the book and taking the course was very meta; as I learned techniques from the
book, I applied them to the course and vice versa. I get the feeling this is going to be a book that I read on a yearly
basis (spaced repetition) to continuously improve these concepts. This post could have been a lot longer, but I&rsquo;d rather
encourage you to read the book yourself and practice the exercises at the end of each chapter.</p>

<h4>Other Resources and References</h4>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://pragprog.com/book/ahptl/pragmatic-thinking-and-learning">Pragmatic Thinking and Learning</a> which is geared more towards software developers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/">HealthyHacker Podcast</a> which talks a lot about memorization techniques and developing positive habits.</li>
<li><a href="http://betterexplained.com/">Better Explained</a> Kalid Azad does an exceptional job of explaining things. In an interview in the
course he describes his method of ADEPT (analogy, diagram, example, plain English, technical).</li>
</ul>


<p>1 &ldquo;diffuse vs focused mode&rdquo; picture <a href="http://tdlc.ucsd.edu/educators/educators%5Fwebinar%5Foakley5%F031213.html">http://tdlc.ucsd.edu/educators/educators%5Fwebinar%5Foakley5%F031213.html</a><br />
2 &ldquo;chunking&rdquo; picture p.56 A Mind For Numbers, Barbara Oakley<br /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - Podcasts]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-podcasts/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-16T11:59:46+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-podcasts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/podcast.jpg" width="300">
It&rsquo;s quite surprising that I haven&rsquo;t really brought up the topic of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Podcast">podcasts</a> on my blog considering that
I&rsquo;ve been consuming them for almost 10 years! My methods and taste have changed a lot over the years. I want a place
to point people when asked about what podcasts I listen to, and with a little more context than just a pure list.</p>

<h2>Software / Tools</h2>

<p>A podcast is such a simple concept (from the technical side) that it allows for a lot of tools and applications to be
created around the idea. Nowadays I pretty much use a single application on my phone. I&rsquo;m generally only concerned with
the mobile experience since I try to listen to podcasts when I&rsquo;m on the move and when I&rsquo;m not focusing on work. Ask me
to listen to a podcast while programming and you&rsquo;ll discover that I won&rsquo;t be able to recall anything from the podcast
(or that I don&rsquo;t do any programming). The application I use is <a href="http://www.shiftyjelly.com/android/pocketcasts">PocketCasts</a>. The homepage is full of
hyperbole and non-truthes (eg: &hellip; deliver the updates instantly&hellip;), but it&rsquo;s an alright application and fits my needs for
now. Most importantly, it allows me to export my subscribed shows as an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opml">OPML file</a> which I&rsquo;ve made
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/podcasts_opml.xml">available to you</a>.</p>

<h2>The List</h2>

<p>Podcasts are a great way to tap into interests of all different types. You&rsquo;ll notice that only a few are related to my
professional life. Listening to podcasts is a wonderful activity and I do get a lot out of them, there becomes a point
where you&rsquo;ve found too much good content and there isn&rsquo;t enough time to listen to them all.</p>

<h2>Economics</h2>

<h3><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/rss.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/econtalk.jpg" width="200">
I begun listening to this show at the beginning of my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a>. The
host, <a href="http://russroberts.info/">Russ Roberts</a>, does a great job of letting the guests speak without pushing his views too often.
It&rsquo;s honestly changed how I think about problems in the world and how to best approach them. Economics is becoming a
tool that I use to help me understand how things are, and how to possibly alter them. The talks are well balanced and
help me see the other side of issues that I normally don&rsquo;t think of. When a new episode appears I look forward to
listening to it regardless of the topic!</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/charles_marohn.html">Charles Marohn on Strong Towns, Urban Development, and the Future of American Cities</a> &ndash; Conversations
around city design always fascinates me. There&rsquo;s a spectrum of that&rsquo;s a lot harder to accomplish than most people
realize. Living in an overly-designed city can be soul crushing, and a zero designed city can be too stressful.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/yuval_levin_on.html">Yuval Levin on Burke, Paine, and the Great Debate</a> &ndash; The difference between the right and left had been
something I hadn&rsquo;t thought deeply about. This conversation made me realize I&rsquo;m more right thinking than I thought. It
also made me understand that neither are &ldquo;bad&rdquo;.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/09/martha_nussbaum.html">Martha Nussbaum on Creating Capabilities and GDP</a> &ndash; There are other conversations around GDP, but this one
really stood out to me. I think Martha does an exceptional job of explaining how GDP is not a sufficient metric and
that we still have a long way to go to get people to the top of Maslow&rsquo;s Hierarchy.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/freakonomics-radio/">Freakonomics Radio</a><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/freakonomicsradio"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/freakonomics.jpg" width="200">
Sometimes hit or miss. Strives to be entertaining more than educational
sometimes, but overall the content is quite good. I identify a bit with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steven_Levitt">Steve Levitt</a> as he&rsquo;s more of an
intrespective quiet person.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/09/04/regulate-this-a-new-freakonomics-radio-podcast/">Regulate This!</a> &ndash; As a user of services like Uber and Airbnb, it&rsquo;s interesting to hear the issues that
these services raise. I find myself leaning towards the side of less regulation, but I still can&rsquo;t figure out where
the balance is. The term &ldquo;sharing economy&rdquo; also drives me nuts, because sharing implies no charge to me. These are
just peer-to-peer market places enabled by technology.</li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/09/25/fitness-apartheid-a-new-freakonomics-radio-podcast/">Fitness Apartheid</a> &ndash; An excellent example of how too little thought around a problem can lead to
bad consequences. It brings the concerns of both sides together and makes the listener understand that nothing is ever
as simple as you think it ought to be.</li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/05/29/the-upside-of-quitting-a-freakonomics-radio-rebroadcast/">The Upside of Quitting</a> &ndash; Very fitting for my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/06/05/failure-is-your-friend-a-new-freakonomics-radio-podcast/">Failure is your Friend</a> &ndash; A follow up to the previous episode.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/">Planet Money</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510289"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/planetmoney.png" width="200">
Short and to the point episodes that focus on very specific topics or issues. I
like this show because the pieces are bite-sized and frequently released. I find myself listening to this show when I
have to wait 15 minutes before something.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2014/09/26/351515481/episode-571-why-raising-money-for-ebola-is-hard">Why Raising Money for Ebola is Hard</a> &ndash; Excellent insights around why we give, and the pychology of charity.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2014/08/22/342232976/episode-562-a-mall-divided">A Mall Divided</a> &ndash; A peak into how economic policy can distrupt small businesses.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2014/07/11/330680385/episode-552-blockbusters-bombs-and-the-price-of-a-ticket">Blockbusters, Bombs, and the Price of a Ticket</a> &ndash; I had never put much thought into the cost of a movie
ticket, this episode explains all the details of why tickets cost the same regardless if it&rsquo;s sold-out or empty.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h2>Startups</h2>

<h3><a href="http://a16z.com/tag/podcast/">a16z</a><a href="http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:62921190/sounds.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/a16z.jpg" width="200">
Getting into the startup world is not something I&rsquo;m terribly interested in, but I am critical
about the tech community, especially startups. This show helps me better understand the world of startups so I can
better understand the mechanics of startups.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://a16z.com/2014/09/05/a16z-podcast-everything-you-need-to-know-about-amazon/">Everything You Need to Know About Amazon</a> &ndash; Explanation of how Amazon re-invests all of its profits to avoid
opportunity costs is a novel concept. Not sure why investors are ok with it. Makes me more curious about what Amazon
will be doing 20-30 years from now.</li>
<li><a href="http://a16z.com/2014/09/30/a16z-podcast-creating-new-silicon-valleys/">Creating New Silicon Valleys</a> &ndash; When something becomes trendy, people always want to figure out how
to replicate it. This episode explains how cultures are emergent, not created. Common sense it would seem, but that
doesn&rsquo;t seem to really stop people. I feel the same around the topic of <a href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops/">DevOps</a>.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://hearstartup.com/">StartUp</a><a href="http://feeds.hearstartup.com/hearstartup"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/startup.png" width="200">
A podcast about a podcast startup. It mixes so many of my favourite things into one show.
Fantastic storytelling about a medium I&rsquo;m passionate about and a domain that I want to learn more of. What connects
me to the show is that <a href="https://twitter.com/abexlumberg">Alex Blumberg</a> just wants to work on something he&rsquo;s passionate about, but has to wade through all
sorts of concerns completely separate from what he really wants to do, because that&rsquo;s business.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://hearstartup.com/episodes/gbm3498ruf7abd4owt4xs20uck1cvn">Startups are Risky Business</a> &ndash; This gave me insight around the different VC models. I used to think
that they are all looking for the 100x payoff. I need to learn more about the more modest investments out there.
Sometimes you can invest in something simply because you want it to exist.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3>Culture and Curiosities</h3>

<h3><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/">99% Invisible</a><a href="http://feeds.99percentinvisible.org/99percentinvisible"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/99pi.png" width="200">
Now one of my favourites. You never know what to expect with this show because the
enigmatic host, <a href="https://twitter.com/romanmars">Roman Mars</a>, always finds something interesting that you likely have no idea about.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites (all of them):</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/thomassons/">Thomassons</a> &ndash; I dare you to listen to this episode and not look for Thomassons wherever you go!</li>
<li><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/the-straight-line-is-a-godless-line/">The Straight Line is a Godless Line</a> &ndash; Given that I was in Vienna and saw the Hundertwasserhaus, it
was very interesting to hear more about the architect. I love the fact that people like him exist, though I may not
want to completely follow his lead.</li>
<li><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/clean-trains/">Clean Trains</a> &ndash; There are so many applications to the lesson of this episode. Frequent and consistent
feedback is necessary to promote any change.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://www.radiolab.org/">RadioLab</a><a href="http://feeds.wnyc.org/radiolab"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/radiolab.png" width="200">
One of the pioneers in story-telling podcasts. I&rsquo;ve been away from it for a while and have re-subscribed as I&rsquo;ve been
missing the excellent stories.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.radiolab.org/story/91500-emergence/">Emergence</a> &ndash; This episode is from 2007 and it still comes up as one
of the more influencial podcast episodes I&rsquo;ve listened to. I&rsquo;m a control freak and find the concept of emergence hard
to understand. A top-down controller is easier for me to understand. This episode reminds me to rethink how things
ought to be and be more flexible.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/programs/ted-radio-hour/">TED Radio Hour</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510298"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/ted-radio-hour.jpg" width="200">
Episodes are themed around TED talks of similar topics. It blends interviews with the speakers along with their talks.
I find this more rich than the talk on its own.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/2013/03/28/175609678/the-violence-within-us?showDate=2014-08-08">The Violence Within Us</a> &ndash; Sort of a scary episode, but it helps me understand that life is always in a
delicate balance. We&rsquo;ll never live in a world where everyone is good. I tend to be utopian in my thinking and this
provides a good dose of reality.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/programs/ted-radio-hour/321797073/what-is-original?showDate=2014-06-27">What is Original</a> &ndash; The thought of being unique and interesting is something everyone craves, but in the
end most of things are derivitive. This episode is good to pair with the 99% Invisible episode:
<a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/duplitecture/">Duplitecture</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/2013/10/06/229879937/identities?showDate=2014-02-21">Identities</a> &ndash; The next few generations of humans are going to have a much different concept about their
identity. We are more global and cross-cultural than ever before.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/tapestry/index.html">Tapestry</a><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/includes/tapestry.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/tapestry.jpg" width="200">
Getting into the spiritual side a bit. This show talks about culture and religion with an
open mind. The show reminds me to appreciate the differences between all of us on this rock. I used to listen to this
show all the time when I lived in Canada. I just recently subscribed to the podcast.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/tapestry/episode/2014/10/24/being-alone-views-from-a-mormon-feminist-poet-nikki-giovanni/">Being Alone</a> &ndash; The 2nd portion with <strong>Nikki Giovanni</strong> is so delightful. It&rsquo;s a candid conversation that
has so many quotable verses. I was walking the streets of Bangalore while listening to it and I had a huge smile on my
face the whole time.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/whitecoat/index.html">White Coat Black Art</a><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/includes/whitecoat.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/whitecoat.jpg" width="200">
The health care system is usually a bit of a black box and this show provides some visibility into how things work. Like
tapestry, this was a show I used to listen to all the time when I lived in Canada. Recently subscribed to feel that
connection back to where I came from.</p>

<br style="clear:both;" />


<h2>Music</h2>

<h3><a href="http://music.cbc.ca/radio3/">CBC Radio 3</a><a href="http://www.cbcradio3.com/podcast/"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/cbcradio3.jpg" width="200">
It&rsquo;s likely that I&rsquo;m a bit biased, but this is where I discover new music. I worked
there from 2005-2009 during the rise of the podcast. I can attest to the quality of the curation of the content coming
from the folks at Radio 3. The superfeed subscribes you to all the different podcasts published by Radio 3, though I
don&rsquo;t think there are as many shows as there used to be.</p>

<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://songexploder.net/">Song Exploder</a><a href="http://songexploder.libsyn.com/rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/songexploder.png" width="200">
This show satifies my curiosity about how a song gets made. It also makes me
appreciate songs that I wouldn&rsquo;t have given a second listen. By listening to this show, you can disover new artists, and
you&rsquo;ll learn how to listen to music and grow appreciation for the more subtle elements of song composition.</p>

<br style="clear:both;" />


<h2>Tech / Programming</h2>

<h3><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/spark/index.html">Spark</a><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/includes/spark.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/spark.jpg" width="200">
A Canadian look into the technical world. Always nice to hear a Canadian perspective of what&rsquo;s going on. Hopefully
because it&rsquo;s created by the CBC, there isn&rsquo;t any product/partner agenda.</p>

<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://podcasts.thoughtbot.com/giantrobots">Giant Robots Smashing into Other Giant Robots</a><a href="http://podcasts.thoughtbot.com/giantrobots.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/giantrobots.jpg" width="200">
Not quite a technical podcast, but it shares stories from the software development world. I became a fan of
<a href="https://twitter.com/r00k">Ben Orenstein</a> when I saw him do a play-by-play screencast. He strikes me as someone I would enjoy working with.</p>

<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://theshipshow.com/">The Ship Show</a><a href="http://theshipshow.com/podcast.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/shipshow.jpg" width="200">
Co-started by an old on-line friend of mine, <a href="https://twitter.com/buildscientist">Youssuf Elkalay</a>.
I like the conversational style of this show as a way to keep me in the loop in the world of <a href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops/">DevOps</a>.</p>

<br style="clear:both;" />


<h3><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/">HealthyHacker</a><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/feed.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" style="border:none;padding-left:5px;" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/healthyhacker.png" width="200">
This one is fairly new and I&rsquo;ve already become a fan. <a href="https://twitter.com/chrishunt">Chris Hunt</a>
delivers his show in a charming style. He discusses being healthy, and what&rsquo;s interesting in the software world. All to
the tune of a catchy theme song. Now I just need to get into the habit of doing the workout of the week.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/2014/08/04/pineapple-in-your-pocket/">Pineapple in Your Pocket</a> &ndash; I try and use this memorization technique as frequently as possible!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/2014/09/29/codecation/">Codecation</a> &ndash; The story of Chris and Ben meeting up for a codecation was inspiring. I would like to do
something similar at some point.</li>
</ul>


<br style="clear:both;" />


<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>There are a lot of podcasts here and I&rsquo;m constantly re-evaluating which ones should remain. Finding the balance of time
and value is hard to figure out. Currently I&rsquo;m unemployed making it a lot easier to consume this much content. I also
listen to tech specific podcasts when I&rsquo;m spending some time in that technology. A good example of that would be the
<a href="http://rubyrogues.com/">ruby rogues</a> podcast. Or, I may take a look at <a href="http://hanselminutes.com/">HanselMinutes</a> to see if something
interesting has come up.</p>

<p>To subscribe to all the same podcasts that I do, import this <a href="http://scottmuc.com/podcasts_opml.xml">OPML</a> file into your favourite podcast
listening software.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Review - Learning Continuous Integration With TeamCity by Manoj Mahalingam]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/book-review-learning-continuous-integration-with-teamcity-by-manoj-mahalingam/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-13T17:34:30+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/book-review-learning-continuous-integration-with-teamcity-by-manoj-mahalingam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong> &ndash; I personally know Manoj and have worked with him in the past. I was asked to review his book,
<a href="http://goo.gl/5wUy3v">Learning Continuous Integration with TeamCity</a>, by <a href="https://www.packtpub.com/">Packt Publishing</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://goo.gl/5wUy3v"><img class="left" src="https://www.packtpub.com/sites/default/files/9518OT%5f0.jpg" width="200"></a>
As someone who had spent many years consulting around the benefits of CI and implementing build and release strategies,
I was interested in how the minutiae would be brought up in a book.</p>

<p>The book begins by going through the creation and configuration of a similar build process for 3 specific tech stacks:
Java, .Net, and Ruby. At first it feels rather repetitive but the repetition actually helps reinforce the importance of
consistency. With all tech stacks, the procedure is pretty much the same: <code>Checkout, Build, Test, Package, Deploy, Run
UI Tests</code>. This pattern really stands out after going through chapters 4, 5 and 6 and builds up a foundation for the
reader so that the rest of the material makes sense.</p>

<p>After setting the stage with these build configurations, he then dives into content that&rsquo;s a bit more TeamCity
specific. This area was much more interesting to me as I&rsquo;m already experienced with build and release concepts, but it
was nice to see TeamCity specific features explained in a little bit more depth.</p>

<p>One piece that felt a little out of place was the topic on Continuous Delivery. It&rsquo;s really hard to introduce a concept
that has a massive book dedicated to the subject. Not sure if its inclusion will help out the beginner that this book
appears to be targeting.</p>

<p>What I enjoyed the most was raising operational concerns around running a CI server system. It was likely
deliberately left out, but I would have liked to see a mention of automated configuration management. There&rsquo;s something
incredibly powerful around automation around your automation.</p>

<p>It became clear to me that this book is meant for the absolute beginner. Manoj hints at better ways of implementing
his example configurations (eg: using wrapper scripts over the built in runners) but doesn&rsquo;t distract the reader
with these possibly subjective tangents. I would recommend this book if you&rsquo;ve never worked with any CI tool and like
to have a guidebook as you try and set it up yourself. Despite being over 250 pages, the book is packed with
screenshots so that it&rsquo;s absolutely clear and won&rsquo;t take too long to go through the whole book. If you&rsquo;re already
experienced with some tools the principles around CI and good build hygiene, this book is useful to skim to see what&rsquo;s
new with TeamCity and some context of the usage of TeamCity specific features.</p>

<p>You can find more information about Manoj at his <a href="https://twitter.com/manojlds">twitter account</a>, on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/526535/manojlds">stackoverflow</a>, or his
<a href="http://stacktoheap.com/">website</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visiting the Motherland - Ukraine]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/visiting-the-motherland-ukraine/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-06T20:01:12+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/visiting-the-motherland-ukraine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>August 17th &ndash; August 29th</em></p>

<h3>Ukraine</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
The next leg of the journey was a long slog from Vienna to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lviv">L’viv</a>. I took a noon train to Budapest and had to pass
some time there for a little while. From Budapest it was an overnight journey with many frequent stops in the
middle of the night for immigration and customs. If you’ve ever played <a href="http://papersplea.se/">Papers, Please</a>, it felt like that. Ukraine
isn’t part of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schengen_Agreement">Schengen agreement</a> so you can’t just cross the border without a documents check. Around a few
hours from L’viv the attendant asks me about my purpose in Ukraine. She then points at my &ldquo;ringless&rdquo; ring finger and
smiles. I knew of the Russian/Ukrainian bride thing, but found it crazy that her first guess was for that purpose.
I thought it was a hyped up, but after watching a few <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8wW7c58nMI4">youtube documentaries</a> about it, I learned
it’s sadly alive and well.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train2.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train2.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
Even with such a long journey the train pretty much arrived on time within a couple minutes. When I exited the train I
immediately could recognize my cousin <a href="https://twitter.com/RusalkaUA">Lilia</a>. She ran up to me and gave me a proper family style hug. Looks like I’m
home! We took a bus to her home in the Northern part of the city. I was introduced to her roommate,
<a href="https://twitter.com/uPadavan">Vitalik</a>. He and I got along really well. He’s a web designer and looks to have a knack for it!
Lilia had to go back to work so I unpacked and made myself at home. Later that evening Lilia’s sister, Natalia, arrived
by train from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ternopil">Ternopil</a>. She had a huge package of food from her parents and we all enjoyed a feast as I
did my best to tell the story of myself and the Myц family Canadian history.</p>

<h2>L&#8217;viv</h2>

<p>I felt immediately comfortable in L’viv. As Lilia was at work, Vitalik and Natalia guided me around the city. Here
are some of the noteworthy places we checked out:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-high-castle.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-high-castle.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;High Castle&#34;" alt="&#34;High Castle&#34;"></a>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lviv_High_Castle">High Castle</a> &ndash; On my first day in L&#8217;viv I was antsy to go out and explore. I never feel comfortable
  in a location until I spend at least a whole day walking around exploring and knowing my surroundings. Natalia likes
  to sleep in (she&rsquo;s going to kill me), so instead of waiting for her to wake up, I decide to explore L&#8217;viv on my own.
  The high castle name is more of a memory as the castle isn&rsquo;t there anymore. Getting to the top of the hill was
  good exercise and rewarded me with a beautiful 360 degree view of the city.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-dim-legend.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-dim-legend.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Dim Legend&#34;" alt="&#34;Dim Legend&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://ukraineallaboutu.com/travel-in-ukraine/hotels-and-restaurants/lviv/house-of-legends/">Dim Legend (House of Legend)</a> &ndash; There are a collection of restaurants owned by a company that&rsquo;s doing some interesting
  setups. Dim Legend has a room for every story (or a story for every room). The restaurant takes
  the entire building and you can go up to the roof top where there&rsquo;s patio with a car, and a chimney with a ladder so
  that you can climb to the top. There&rsquo;s something refreshing about being in a country that doesn&rsquo;t have the same
  restrictive safety regulations of most western countries.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-rynok.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-rynok.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Rynok Square&#34;" alt="&#34;Rynok Square&#34;"></a>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Market_Square_(Lviv)">Rynok Square</a> &ndash; Like most Eastern European cities, L&#8217;viv has a beautiful (albeit touristy) city
  square. You&rsquo;ll find the &ldquo;floating&rdquo; statue people and dudes making giant bubbles. Overall though, the atmosphere is
  quaint and relaxing. Ukrainian culture is inviting so it&rsquo;s pretty hard to feel like you&rsquo;re too far out of place.
  This is probably where I spent the most time as all the coffee shops and restaurants are all near this location.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-chocolate-chili.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-chocolate-chili.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Melted Chocolate with Chili&#34;" alt="&#34;Melted Chocolate with Chili&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://ukraineallaboutu.com/travel-in-ukraine/hotels-and-restaurants/lviv/lviv-handmade-chocolate/">Lviv chocolate</a> &ndash; One of the most unique experiences I had in L&#8217;viv was drinking melted chocolate
  flavoured with a whole whack load of chili powder! This place was not good for any thought about losing weight. Not
  sure how everyone here stays so fit! At least I was getting a lot of walking in, but not sure if it&rsquo;s enough for
  all the sweets I&rsquo;ve been having.</p>

<p>&nbsp;
&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.lvivbeermuseum.com/uk/muzey">Lviv brewery</a> &ndash; On my own I stopped by the brewpub to sample a few of their beers. I was really
intrigued by the style of beer they make there. In general, I found Ukrainian beer sweeter than most beers I&rsquo;ve
had around the world. I visited the brewery a second time with Natalia and Vitalik. We took a brewery tour but
it was done in Ukrainian. I&rsquo;ve never heard Ukrainian spoken so fast, but it was pretty comprehensive. She started
the tour talking about the origins of beer in Egypt.</li>
<li><a href="http://trumitlu.virtual.ua/?lang=en">Try Mitly (3 Brooms)</a> &ndash; My cousins are huge Harry Potter fans and they said that there&rsquo;s a place to have
butter beer in L&#8217;viv! A lot of places were kitschy but that didn&rsquo;t bother me in this environment. I found them a lot
of fun. It could be that I felt like I was in an environment where people aren&rsquo;t as judgemental about such kinds
of establishments.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.justlviv.it/en/1714/gas-lamp.html">Gas lamp</a> &ndash; Owned by the same person as Dim Legend, this restaurant had a unique feel for every floor
and was a fun environment to take some time and relax in.</li>
<li><a href="http://visittoukraine.com/en/unique-ukraine/lviv-coffee-mine">Lviv coffee manufacture</a> &ndash; L&#8217;viv is the coffee capital of Ukraine. Normally tea is the hot beverage
choice, but here coffee rules. A proper L&#8217;viv coffee is hot water mixed with the coffee grounds without a filter.
You wait a few minutes and the grounds settle to the bottom and you&rsquo;re left with a rich, flavourful cup of coffee.
The best part is that you don&rsquo;t need any fancy expensive equipment to make it! It&rsquo;s really the quality of the beans
that matter.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lychakiv_Cemetery">Lychakiv Cemetery</a> &ndash; I wanted to go somewhere outside the center and old gothic cemeteries seem to appeal
to me for some reason. The day that I visited Lychakiv Cemetery was sunny and warm. The whole area is like a maze and
it was nice to wander around witnessing the beautiful scenery.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-beer.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-beer.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Beer Museum&#34;" alt="&#34;Beer Museum&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-butterbeer.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-butterbeer.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Butterbeer!&#34;" alt="&#34;Butterbeer!&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-books.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-books.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Book Market&#34;" alt="&#34;Book Market&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-alley.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-alley.small.jpg" width="190"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-cemetary.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-cemetary.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Cemetary&#34;" alt="&#34;Cemetary&#34;"></a></p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-tram.jpg" width="70">
L&#8217;viv is a city rich in culture, architecture, and friendly people. It&rsquo;s accessible with its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trams_in_Lviv">120 year old tram</a>
system, but remember to punch your ticket yourself (pictures to the left) and has all the things you need as a traveler.
The city is sort of a dream land for me. It has excellent beer, chocolate, coffee, books, and food. The people are
friendly and accomodating, I can&rsquo;t wait to be back!</p>

<h2>Ternopil</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-home.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-home.small.jpg" width="200"></a>
For the weekend, Lillia had planned a trip to Ternopil to visit her parents and other relatives. Apparently they don’t
get many foreigners on the train and the attendant on the train made an effort to ask if I wanted tea or coffee in
English. He sort of chuckled and so did my cousins, not sure why. We took a bus from the train station to the outer area of Ternopil
where Lilias’s parents live. It was a classic pre 90’s looking apartment block. The door opens to their apartment and
I’m welcomed with a feast on the table! Lilia’s parents didn’t speak much English so poor Lilia had to spend a lot of
time translating (she eventually could tell me whole life story without me having to say a word). The meal started with
a shot of vodka. When Ivan offered me another, I replied “tak, bud laska!” (translation: yes, please!). That moment
signified me as an authentic family member.</p>

<p>First, I need to digress and talk about Lilia and Natalia’s parents, Ivan and Mariia. They are the sweetest couple and
so generous. I loved how they didn’t let the language barrier prevent us from getting to know each other. One of my
favourite moments was sitting with Ivan as he showed me pictures and we had a conversation. Lilia was busy packing
for the trip back and after she was done she asked what the heck we could possibly talk about. I’m not quite sure
myself, but we laughed a lot and didn’t let language stop us from at least trying to communicate. We even enjoyed
watching the Belgian GP (and what an awesome race!) with some Ukrainian craft beers. One day I hope to learn more
Ukrainian so we can communicate even more the next time we meet.</p>

<p>Mariia could easily be mistaken as a sister of her daughters. She’s actually my
cousin (Lilia and Natalia are my 2nd cousins 1st removed) and the family bond was definitely felt. She’s also an
amazing cook! The meals included home made: cabbage rolls, varenyky (perogies), shkvarky (pork rind), sour cream, borscht, milk, and juice.
I’m pretty sure I gained 5 kilos over those few days.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-beer1.jpg" width="180">
<img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-beer2.jpg" width="180">
The next day was spent driving to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Velyki_Birky">Velyki Birky</a>, a village outside of Ternopil. Our first stop was at Mariia’s parents (Hanna and
Fedoz). First we stopped by a house which was a family run brewery (business card pictured). One of the sons of the owner was there and he
happily (in excellent English) explained the whole operation. The beer was fresh, un-pasterized, un-filtered, and
very tasty. We then arrived and had a big family lunch (with more shots of vodka). Hanna is my dad’s cousin as she
is the daughter of Eve Myц who is the sister of Petro Myц, my dad’s father. The meal was of course fantastic and I
did my best to update them on my family back in Canada. During the afternoon, Lilia, Natalia, and I walked over to
where Hanna&rsquo;s other children live. Lilia gave her best rendition of my life story and we had fun playing more Q&amp;A
with more of my family. One of the big questions was on how Canada was receiving the news about the events going
on in Ukraine. Unfortunately I couldn&rsquo;t quite adequatley answer the question but from a generalized perspective I
could say that the West has been pretty weak in it&rsquo;s response.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family.medium.jpg" width="510"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.medium.jpg" width="510"></a></p>

<p>In the evening I went out with the girls to meet up with some of their friends. It was fun introducing them to some
of the games I played at TWU (eg: numbers game, and one-up one-down). The next day was a holiday for independence day
so we went walking around the city for a bit. The city had some very pretty areas and some interesting looking playgrounds.
After our walk we went to the train station (pic: don&rsquo;t we look like an intimidating group?).</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-playground.medium.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-playground2.medium.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-departing.medium.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<h2>Back to L&#8217;viv</h2>

<p>After an amazing weekend we headed back to L&#8217;viv. Lilia&rsquo;s roommate was returning so I had find a <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.in/rooms/451524">place of my own</a>
to for a few days. I wasn&rsquo;t prepared for how much I would miss being in the same place as my cousins and Vitalik (I&rsquo;m
considering him family). I did feel some sense of relief to give Lilia some time without having to worry
about entertaining me and it gave me a chance to practice my Ukrainian all on my own. The few days I spent on my
own was focused on hanging out in coffee shops and working on a browser plugin. I realized there&rsquo;s a reason why
people smiled when I asked for the wifi password when I hung out at a venue. Trying to be Ukrainian I would say
&ldquo;Internet bud laska&rdquo;. This is the equivalent of ordering the Internet off of a menu. My cousins got a good laugh
from this, and apparently so did all the wait staff I said this to.</p>

<p>Anyways, over a couple days I got the the basic functionality of a plugin working called <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/blockworthy">BlockWorthy</a>.
It scrubs links to viral websites and issues you a warning if you happen to go to one of those websites. It felt good
to be writing some code and exploring some ideas.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>Leaving Ukraine I thought about the bond of family. I had been watching Game of Thrones and seeing how important
bloodlines are in that show probably had some affect on me. I was really touched that my cousins would openly accept
me into their home and all because we share common ancestry (my great grandfater, their great great grandfather).
I didn’t even know who were my cousins were until my aunt
in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biggar,_Saskatchewan">Biggar</a> informed me there are relatives in Ukraine who would love to meet me. The thought about the subconscious
bond with family made me think about why we have countries and lines on maps. It’s like a higher level view of the
bond. Patriotism is like a larger version of nepotism. I can’t help connect more easily with someone from Canada than
I would USA. My bond with my cousins exists because of who my parents are. My ability to nearly walk into any country
is simply because of the country I was born in.</p>

<p>What I’m really trying to say is that I’m so freaking lucky to be born into an awesome family and country. Because
of these uncontrollable events (on my part), I’ve been afforded so many luxuries.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rome, Switzerland, and Vienna]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/rome-switzerland-and-vienna/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T17:39:31+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/rome-switzerland-and-vienna</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 30th &ndash; August 17th</em></p>

<h2>When in Rome</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-fountain.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-fountain.medium.jpg" width="900"></a></p>

<p>When I learned that my uncle and his family would be in Rome I looked at my schedule to see if I could make seeing them
work. It turned out it fit perfectly! The last time I saw them was in London while they were doing their 2013 summer
trip and I was on my Belgian Grand Prix vacation. My aunt and uncle are well versed in the world of business so we had
many evenings discussing what I&rsquo;ve learned from the economics courses and floating ideas of what&rsquo;s next for my life. Of
course I got to catch up with my cousins too. Can&rsquo;t believe how quickly they are growing up (I won&rsquo;t mention that I
remember seeing them in diapers to avoid their embarassment).  They had rented a flat near the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Steps">Spanish Steps</a>
which made it easy for me to cram in a bunch of sight-seeing in a short amount of time.</p>

<p>Touring Rome is pretty easy because all you have to do is step outside. Even on my first walk I stumbled across many
interersting sites. I did a couple free walking tours, but they weren&rsquo;t organized by Sandeman and weren&rsquo;t nearly the
same quality. Still, it was good to have a guided walk to the Colloseum and to the Vatican. My favourite place was the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Gallery_of_Maps">Hallway of Maps</a> in the Vatican Museum. Ever since I was a kid, I&rsquo;ve always loved looking at maps. On
roadtrips I would be the navigator, and my favourite thing about Ultima VII is the cloth map that was packaged with the
game</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-colosseum.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-colosseum.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-square.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-square.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-st-peters.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-st-peters.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>As beautiful as Rome was, I knew my time as a tourist was ending. I was at the point where I didn&rsquo;t want to elbow my
way through tourists anymore. Nor was I as interested as I was before in exploring musuems and historical places. The
brain can only hold so much. One thing I enjoyed immensely were the flavour of the tomatoes! Every meal I had I was sure
to have tomatoes as a part of it.</p>

<h2>Watching Time Go By in Switzerland</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-home.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-home.medium.jpg" width="900"></a></p>

<p>The other part that made Rome convenient was that I could travel to Switzerland to meet up with fellow ex-ThoughtWork
<a href="https://twitter.com/mhoefi">Marc Hofer</a>, who I worked with in India in ThoughtWorks University (TWU), and who&rsquo;s balcony view is displayed above.
He had a 1L bottle of scotch ready (we numbed our heads with scotch nearly every evening during TWU). Thankfully he was
generous enough to give me a couch for as long as I needed one. I ended up spending 10 days in beautiful <a href="http://www.myswitzerland.com/en/thun.html">Thun</a>!</p>

<p>Over the those days I did the following:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Dinners and chats with Marc</strong> &ndash; Catching up with Marc was a lot of fun. During the day I would accrue a lot of ideas and
he became my wall to bounce them off of. One such idea was my new currency that I called &ldquo;Sunset&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s a time based
currency where you determine the exchange rate of the base amount which is a Day. If your daily expenses are $100USD,
then that&rsquo;s the exchange rate into Days. If you have $1400 in the bank than you have 2 Weeks saved. It&rsquo;s a completely
personal currency because everyone&rsquo;s exchange into Days will be different. We of course
talked about our time in India and software development in Switzerland. We never really lacked of things to talk about
the whole time I was there.</li>
<li><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bern.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bern.small.jpg" width="300"></a> <strong>Bern
Excursion</strong> &ndash; Marc had a meetup with some of his colleagues and invited me out. I took a train out to Bern a few
hours before the meetup started so I could wander around a bit. It didn&rsquo;t take long for me to find the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kindlifresserbrunnen">Kindlifresserbrunnen (Child Eater Fountain)</a> which is probably the most bizarre statue I&rsquo;ve ever seen. The old
town was beautiful (like Antwerp, Bruges, Heidelberg, Prague, etc&hellip;) and of course I found a nearby
<a href="http://www.altestramdepot.ch/htm/home.htm">brewery</a> to quench my thirst for a bit before heading to meet up with Marc and his colleagues.</li>
<li><strong>Coffee shops</strong> &ndash; During the day I looked to find cafes to hang out in and work on my blog (these posts seem to take me a
heck of a lot of time). There was <a href="https://plus.google.com/106555922181396502598/about?hl=en">one cafe</a> that I really liked. The staff were friendly, played good music, and the
coffee and beers available were very tasty. During this period I was getting working on my <a href="http://careers.stackoverflow.com/scottmuc">CV</a> and getting
excited about working again!</li>
<li><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bike.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bike.small.jpg" width="300"></a> <strong>Bike
around Lake Thun</strong> &ndash; The weather was hit-and-miss, but for one day there was excellent weather. I rented a bike and
rode it to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interlaken">Interlaken</a> and back to Thun for a total of 60km. It was a beautiful ride, but I could feel that I&rsquo;m a bit
out of shape.</li>
<li><strong>Train tour</strong> &ndash; There were spare days on my Eurail pass so I decided to check out all the main city centers in the
country. I started by going to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geneva">Geneva</a>, then <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zurich">Zurich</a>, and finished in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lucerne">Luzern</a>.
Mike Wong, a ThoughtWorker from SF, was on vacation and we met up for dinner. Seriously, ThoughtWorkers are everywhere!</li>
<li><strong>Oberhofen Castle and Clock Museum</strong> &ndash; Over the weekend Marc played tourist with me and we headed over to Oberhofen. The
purpose of the trip was to go the <a href="http://www.myswitzerland.com/en/museum-of-clocks-and-mechanical-musical-instruments.html">clock museum</a> but it didn&rsquo;t open for a few hours. We walked around and decided to
tour the <a href="http://www.schlossoberhofen.ch/en/home">castle</a>. After a bit of walking and a quick snack we went back to the clock museum. They
didn&rsquo;t do tours in English so Marc played translator. Even in Swiss-German it was a fun tour. The guide was clearly
passionate about the watches and the music devices.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-spiez.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-spiez.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-thun-canal.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-thun-canal.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bridge.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bridge.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>Since I was in the land of clocks I was hoping to purchase a watch there. Something to be a symbol of taking time to
enjoy life (a principle of my career break) and something to keep me from looking at my phone for the time. I was
inspired by the intricate work that goes into making a watch and thought having one on my wrist would remind me to take
pride in my work and take the necessary time to do it well. Unfortunately all the watch stores were posh and displayed
ideas around prestige and fashion more than engineering. It switched off my idea of purchasing a watch for now.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-currency.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-currency.small.jpg" width="180"></a>
It was hard to leave Switzerland because I was growing comfortable there. The people were friendly and forgiving of my
inability to speak any of the 4 official languages. Then again, paying over $30 (0.3 Days) was quickly draining my money
reserves. At least the best part of Switzerland is free; the scenery. Oh, and I also like how the currency folded nicely
in my money clip. The notes are sized in such a way that the denomination of the note aligns in such a way that you can
see all of your notes when folded! I can&rsquo;t say how many times I&rsquo;ve had a roll of US notes and found that they were all
$1 bills and I only had a total of $30 on me.</p>

<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h2>Composing my Thoughts in Vienna</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-cats.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-cats.medium.jpg" width="900"></a></p>

<p>The next leg of my journey is a long train trip to L&#8217;viv, Ukraine. I decided to break up the trip with a stop in Vienna
for a couple days. With only a couple days I had to pack in the sight-seeing. This was made easier with me being
museumed-out so I was mostly checking things out from the outside. To make things easy, I found a
<a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/1531563">great location</a> with a host with a couple cats (pictured above).</p>

<p>My first day was spent checking out the two largest palaces in Vienna. The highlight was a stop at a <a href="http://www.salmbraeu.com/index.php?id=2&amp;L=1">brewery</a> just
outside the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belvedere_(palace)">Belvedere</a> palace. The service was great, the food yummy, and every beer tasty. After 1.5L of beer I was set
for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sch%C3%B6nbrunn_Palace">Schönbrunn</a> palace. I took the metro there and climb up the hill to Gloriette and had a little nap on the grass there.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-belvedere.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-belvedere.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-schunbrunn.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-schunbrunn.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-center.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-center.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>The next day I used a city bike rental. I&rsquo;m glad I did because I saw a very different Vienna. First stop was to checkout
the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hundertwasser_Haus">Hundertwasserhaus</a>. It was so interesting and pretty that I wondered why beautiful buildings
like it had to be the exception to the rule. His <a href="http://www.hundertwasser.com/">website</a> is full of interesting ideas. His 5-skins
concept is one I find myself conflicted about. I wonder what it would have been like to have him and
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gene_Roddenberry">Gene Roddenberry</a> had a conversation.</p>

<p>I then went through <a href="http://www.wien-vienna.com/prater.php">Prater</a> which was a scary amusement park. The weather was a bit gloomy and there were some
giant clown shaped buildings that made me think of the book IT.</p>

<p>Since I was on a bike I could cover
a bit more distance so I went towards the bridge and crossed North to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donau_City">Donaucity</a>. It was like riding into a dystopian
story! The streets were stark and there was a cold feeling to the area. I rode away to the nearby park and found it odd
to see such a large expanse of greenery vacant on a Saturday afternoon. It reminded me again that big design up front
for cities does not work. What you end up with is something functional but complete devoid of any human feel. After
riding back to the center I parked the bike at another area and checked out another <a href="http://www.1516brewingcompany.com/cms/">brewery</a>. I think I
went there during shift change because it took a long time to get the attention of a waitress. The beer and the currywurst was really
good, but the poor service at the obnoxious sounding Australian behind me (probably was just my mood) was wearing me
down and I took the metro back to the apartment and hung out in the flat with Roman and his cats.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-hundertwasser.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-hundertwasser.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-donaucity.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-donaucity.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-golden-boy.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-golden-boy.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>After one more sleep it&rsquo;s time for me to leave Vienna and head to L&#8217;viv, Ukraine!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Growing an Open Source Project: The Pester Story]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/growing-an-open-source-project-the-pester-story/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-07T21:20:58+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/growing-an-open-source-project-the-pester-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/github-pester.png"></a></p>

<h3>In the Beginning</h3>

<p>In 2010 I was on a project that focused on build and release software for a bunch of .Net projects (and a few Java
projects). Our &ldquo;glue&rdquo; was written in PowerShell because of the wonderful remoting capabilities and it&rsquo;s integration with
Windows automation. Our code was untested and our code base was growing over time because our tools proved to be useful and
we were getting more and more feedback. Thus, the code required change more frequently. Without the safety net of tests
for the most basic logic, our feedback loop was slow as it required us to run builds and deploys to adequately cover our
bases.</p>

<p>It was January 1st, 2011. I was a touch hungover from the previous night and was chilling in my apartment in Calgary.
The difficulty in changing our PowerShell code was bothering me enough that I got a bunch of coffee from
<a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/caffe-beano-calgary">Cafe Beano</a> and attempted to make an <code>rspec</code> like testing tool for PowerShell. The next day I was able to make a <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester/commit/a1d6a0e01f58375175ed090647ab8245a049f1a6">commit</a>
with actual working code! A few days later I was able to <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/PowerYaml/commits/master?page=1">add tests</a> to PowerYaml. That&rsquo;s how
<a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester">Pester</a> was born.</p>

<p>In the next couple months I integrated Pester into our project. It was a real superficial integration as we didn&rsquo;t have
too much time to retroactively add a lot of tests. So for me, my consumption of Pester was a few months in early 2011!</p>

<h3>The Early Days (2011 &ndash; 2012)</h3>

<p>Over the course of the year, the tool seemed to be adopted by a few. A <a href="http://mrtn.nrd.io/">friend in Vancouver</a> apparently had begun using it
in one of his projects. He&rsquo;s also the first <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester/commits/master?author=mrtns">contributor</a> to the project! It wasn&rsquo;t until the next year
that <a href="https://twitter.com/ferventcoder">Rob Reynolds (aka ferventcoder)</a> used Pester in the <a href="http://chocolatey.org/">Chocolatey</a> project. That was my
first hint that there&rsquo;s potential in this project.</p>

<p>In 2012 there wasn&rsquo;t much going on until <a href="https://twitter.com/mwrockx">Matt Wrock</a> added mocking support and contributed a whole lot of fixes.
It was then that Pester got a new core maintainer. It was very cool to meet him during my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a>
in Seattle and give him a proper thank you for the work that&rsquo;s done. I believe he also wrote the <a href="http://www.mattwrock.com/post/2012/11/15/Unit-Testing-Powershell-and-Hello-Pester.aspx">earliest post</a>
on Pester. I then noticed a comprehensive post on the <a href="http://blogs.endjin.com/?s=pester">endjin.com</a> blog website.</p>

<p>Seeing other people use Pester was a massively ego boosting thing. I&rsquo;m afraid I&rsquo;m one of those people in the software
community that does feed off of this kind of thing. For some reason it made me feel validated as a professional in the
software community. Despite the pleasure I got from Pester being associated with me, I decided to move Pester from my
personal github user to a Pester organization. I&rsquo;m really happy I did that, because it made it feel more like a
community project than a personal one. A <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/pester">google group</a> was eventually created too as to not clutter
Github with conversations in the issue tracker.</p>

<p>Later on I would find out that it&rsquo;s been used in several <a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/">ThoughtWorks</a> projects! These use cases weren&rsquo;t
even initiated by me. Someone wanted to test their PowerShell code, found Pester, and started using it. They would find
out I also worked for ThoughtWorks and would ping me on our internal chat and ask me questions.</p>

<h3>The Year of Change (2013)</h3>

<p>While I was living in India I had several months with some extra time that I used to update Pester. Throughout the year
I spent quite a bit of time maintaining the project. There definitely was a motive for this activity. I knew that
projects that have activity in the codebase are usually favoured by other devs. I still haven&rsquo;t used Pester on a project
since early 2011! There&rsquo;s no functionality that I could possibly need out of Pester but I carved out time to take care
of a few niggling design flaws and close some issues. This resulted in a <a href="http://scottmuc.com/powershell-pester-2-and-1-dot-2-released/">major release</a> which is pretty
much the last time I really did anything to the code. It was great to see another <a href="http://johanleino.wordpress.com/2013/09/13/pester-unit-testing-for-powershell/">quality blog post</a> by
Johan Leino appear on the Web.</p>

<h3>The Year of Transition (2014)</h3>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/LogicalDiagram/status/461638955725631488"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/pester-mention.png"></a>
2014 marked a large surge in Pester interest. During the PowerShell Summit it was rumoured that the creator of
PowerShell, <a href="http://www.jsnover.com/blog/">Jeffrey Snover</a>, mentioned Pester in one of his talks! Heck, I was even <a href="http://powershell.org/wp/2014/03/23/episode-262-powerscripting-podcast-scott-muc-on-testing-with-pester/">interviewed</a> for the
PowerScripting Podcast!</p>

<p>Another contributor by the name of <a href="https://twitter.com/nohwnd">Jakub Jareš</a> was very active and soon became a core member of the Pester team. During
my travels on my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a> I got to meet up with him in Prague! He also wrote a
<a href="http://www.powershellmagazine.com/author/jjakub/">couple</a> great articles too.</p>

<p>Now it looks like there&rsquo;s another one joining in too. Welcome <a href="https://twitter.com/MSH_Dave">Dave</a> to the Pester team!</p>

<p>Looking at the logs of the Beta branch, it&rsquo;s wonderful to see my commit percentage diminishing. I&rsquo;ve now only committed
30% of the code base!</p>

<h3>Lessons Learned</h3>

<p>Though not a big project, I can say I learned a lot maintaining this open source project. There&rsquo;s something very
different than working with a colocated team and random contributors around the world. Colocated teams develop unwritten
rules (a culture) and there&rsquo;s less debate over small issues. I didn&rsquo;t realize how much brace alignment, trailing
whitespace, tab stops, and other petty things would annoy me. What&rsquo;s harder is that I didn&rsquo;t want to complain about it
to the community afraid that I would come across as an OCD control freak. My biggest mistake with Pester was thinking
too much on how it reflected upon me, and not what is good for the community. If I had lived and breathed Windows
projects over the last few years, I think that would have been different. I&rsquo;m happy that Pester has a few excellent
maintainers now and that I&rsquo;ve participated in an open source project from first commit to stepping away.</p>

<p>Another lesson was that empowering would be contributors was an investment well worth doing. It&rsquo;s hard to say, but I
feel that doing this is what&rsquo;s enabled me to lessen my involvement over time.</p>

<p>This talk also resonated with me a bit (the last 4-5 minutes):</p>

<iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UIDb6VBO9os " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h3>Stepping Down</h3>

<p>The adventure of watching a project grow and have a life on its own has been a wonderful experience. Looking at the
project history and correspondance it&rsquo;s pretty easy to see that I&rsquo;m not nearly as active. That&rsquo;s really thanks to Jakub
and Dave doing nearly all the maintenance.</p>

<p>That being said, I&rsquo;m &ldquo;officially&rdquo; stepping down and retiring from Pester. This will be done by unsubcribing from any
e-mail notifications (the google group, and the github project).</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://pesterbdd.com/images/Pester.png">
I would like to shout a big thank you to everyone who made this project so wonderful. Especially to <a href="https://twitter.com/manojlds">Manoj
Mahalingam</a> who did some great work in the early days and really helped me get this project off the ground.
Another shout out to <a href="http://vant.ca/">Stefan Vant</a> for the excellent logo!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prague, Budapest, and the Hungarian Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T17:53:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 22nd &ndash; July 29th</em></p>

<h3>Prague</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>Next portion of the trip is to Eastern Europe! I had a nice simple itinerary to Prague: <strong>Heidelberg &ndash;> Munich &ndash;> Prague</strong>.
Unfortunately something was going on with the brakes on the train and I missed my train in Munich so it
turned into: <strong>Heidelberg &ndash;> Munich &ndash;> Neurberg &ndash;> Cheb &ndash;> Prague</strong>. By now I&rsquo;m a seasoned itinerary refactorer so this
didn&rsquo;t phase me. These little <em>adjustments of the universe</em> can sometimes end up with interesting things happening. At
the Plzen stop, a woman sat across from me in the couchette. She started speaking to me in Czech and my response was the
standard Canadian response: I&rsquo;m sorry?</p>

<br />


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry?&rdquo; or &ldquo;sowry&rdquo; in the short form is Canadian for: I apologize that I don&rsquo;t speak your language and I&rsquo;m embarassed to
ask you to repeat yourself in English because I&rsquo;ve never had to deal with speaking and understanding multiple languages. Of course
I&rsquo;m also making the assumption that you can speak English because a world without English is just unfathomable. Again,
I&rsquo;m sorry</p></blockquote>

<p>Then in English she said I looked Czech and was just inquiring about the train. Turns out
she spoke excellent English, lives in San Diego and was just in the country to visit her family. Eventually we
started chit chatting and the conversation about my trip became the focus of interest. I had fun demoing her the <a href="http://scottmuc.com/twinery/independent-accord.html">cargo ship tour</a>
and got some usability feedback as a result. Next thing I knew we were in Prague. Even with my limited
social ability to pick up on body language, I think she was flirting with me! In my usual fashion I dropped the ball. We
parted ways with a handshake and me wishing her a pleasant visit with her family.</p>

<p>After hitting my head against a wall for what seemed like a decade, I continued on to a rendezvous point in the
train station where I was to meet up with <a href="https://twitter.com/nohwnd">Jakub Jareš</a>. He&rsquo;s a core contributor to <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester">Pester</a>,
who in the last 6 months, has taken pretty much all the maintenance burden off of my shoulders. He offered to take me out for beers and I obviously
couldn&rsquo;t resist an offer like that. It was the rainiest day of the summer and he guided me to the <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2094840">airbnb</a>
where I was to stay for the next couple days. Then we proceeded to a <a href="http://www.pivovarskyklub.com/">bar</a> (and got soaked in the process). We enjoyed many beers,
discussed much about software development, and my ineptness with the woman on the train was soon forgotten.</p>

<p>Sandeman operates in Prague too so I did a couple tours:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague-castle.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague-castle.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/daily-tours/new-prague-free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: I can&rsquo;t really talk about this tour without talking about the guide. <a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/our-guides/pavel.html">Pavel</a>
was quite the character. He had an entertaining dry wit and personalized the tour with stories of his own family. I
was blown away when he said is grandmother has lived in the same flat her whole life and has lived in 9 different
countries as a result. It was a good reminder on the craziness humans have to deal with all the time.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/daily-tours/prague-castle-tour.html">Castle Tour</a>: Fortunately, Pavel was the guide for this tour too! He sort of stumbled over a
little late and asked the group if we could deviate from the standard tour itinerary and visit a
<a href="http://europeupclose.com/article/st-norberts-brewery-in-prague/">monastery</a> where some award winning beer is brewed. No one was opposed and I got to have a fantastic
beer at the beginning of the tour. The castle was very different than other castles I&rsquo;ve seen. The distictive
feature was the cathedral but the surrounding buildings were much different. At the end of the tour, I really
enjoyed walking through the <a href="http://www.hrad.cz/en/prague-castle/guidepost-for-visitors/gardens-of-the-prague-castle.shtml#a5">garden around the ramparts</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Overall, I really enjoyed Prague. You really need to avoid the square as much as possible. Once out of the tourist area,
everything is quite afforable and less hectic. Even though my stay was short, I felt that I got the most out of it. I
would like to go back and explore further and do some hacking with Jakub though.</p>

<h3>Arriving in Budapest</h3>

<p>My stay was short in Prague because I had to get to Budapest for the last of my Grand Prix adventure. Fortunately it was
a direct train! The <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/1767274">airbnb</a> was close to the station and was able to take the metro there. I was really happy with the
location, and the host was exceptional in responding to my queries. One interesting thing about taking the train around
Europe is that you start to see patterns in the train stations from different countries. There was quite a difference
between the stations in Czech Republic and Slovakia compared to Germany and Hungary. Now I want to create an archive of
train stations so I can do more comparing and contrasting.</p>

<h3>Hungarian Grand Prix</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-bags.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-bags.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>Getting to the race track was a fairly painless experience in Budapest. The transit workers were also extremely helpful
and knowledgable about the logistics of the race. The track was located in a beautiful area just outside Budapest. I
spent the Friday walking around the track (in 35C weather). The track area was super clean and I think that&rsquo;s owed to
the fact that bright blue garbage bags were never more than 20ft away from you. Overall, I would say this Grand Prix had
the most pleasant logistics experience. More importantly though, this was an <a href="http://www.autoblog.com/2014/07/28/race-recap-2014-hungarian-grand-prix-a-thrilling-wet-mess/">incredible race</a>! A cloud burst occured
around 60 minutes before the race began. All the drivers had to change their strategies and start with wet tyres. Then
an accident occured a few laps in that caused some pit lane confusion resulting in the leaders being in the middle of
the pack. Nearly every lap had battles going on from all positions. I think this ranks up there as one of the best races
of the year (Bahrain was pretty close). I&rsquo;m sort of sad that my stream of F1 races is over, but also happy because now
the rest of my time is entirely unscheduled. Who knows, maybe I&rsquo;ll do a quick detour to Belgium and go to the race there
at the end of the month.</p>

<br />


<br />


<h3>Dream Theater in Budapest</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dream-theater.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dream-theater.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>As a bonus I saw posters stating that <a href="http://www.dreamtheater.net/">Dream Theater</a> is playing nearby! I&rsquo;ve been a fan of them since 1998 and have never
seen them live! Everything looked too perfect: the venue was a beautiful tram ride away, it starts after the majority of
the F1 events are done, it ended at a decent hour so I could be rested for race day, and tickets were still available!
After freshening up after another hot day at the track I walk to the tram and arrive at the venue around an hour before
the show starts. I was in line to grab some food when the woman next to me asks me a question in Hungarian. Here we go
again! I respond with &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry?&rdquo;. She switches to English and asks if I was
ahead of her. I had no idea, and it didn&rsquo;t really matter to me so I said she was first. As I get my food, she asks where
I&rsquo;m from. I tell her I&rsquo;m going to find some beer and she offers to show me where I can sample some
proper Hungarian liquor. I follow her lead and she orders me palinka which is a fruit brandy. Fortunately I&rsquo;m well
adapted to plum whiskey from hazy memories of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G7Eb7a8-LvQ">ThoughtBoarder</a> trips (thanks <a href="http://www.yycapps.com/2012/09/developer-interview-radu-muresan/">Radu</a>), so the shot goes down easy. She says
she needs to bring the food back to her group and I bid farewell and find a spot in the crowd to watch the show. Ten or
fifteen minutes pass and she finds me in the crowd. We continue to chat about music, travel and Hungary. It turns out
that her dad brought her to the concert (coolest dad in the world!), and she asked if it was ok to hang out with me
during the show (you had to ask?!). You would think that I would have learned my lesson from my previous female
encounter&hellip; nope. Though I did do a bit better. I wrote down my website and she asked if she could find me on Facebook
(I wasn&rsquo;t sure if my profile was searchable, but I said yes). The show was fantastic and made better by having her company.
I got a message from her a few days later and we&rsquo;re still corresponding! Clearly something supernatural was going on as
you can tell from this image of the show.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-view.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-view.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>The weather following the race was not so good. I managed to explore a little bit around the vicinity of where I was
staying, but spent most of the time catching up with Coursera. Sandeman did not have any presence in Budapest so I took
a free tour by another organization. I can&rsquo;t say it was up to the same standard, but it was still informative
nevertheless. It ended near the castle and I enjoyed a relatively rain free walk back to my flat and prepared for my
next destination, Rome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glasgow, Berlin, Heidelberg and the German Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/glasgow-berlin-heidelberg-and-the-german-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-21T18:14:37+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/glasgow-berlin-heidelberg-and-the-german-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 7th &ndash; July 21st</em></p>

<h3>Reunions in Glasgow</h3>

<p>Since my train didn&rsquo;t leave until after noon, I decided to go back to Bletchley Park and spend the
morning there. It was so nice to just spend some idle time in the park and not hurry through the
exhibits. Unrushed, I made my way to the train station for a direct train to Glasgow.
Upon arrival at the station I was greeted by Derek and <a href="http://adidav9.blogspot.cz/">Rose</a> who I know from back in the Calgary
days. They&rsquo;ve been super generous and hosting me at their apartment which is close to the train station.
It was fun to look back at the tough project we worked on together and look at the experience with
fondness and nostalgia. Rose was my concert buddy and Derek was probably the only person I know
that likes <a href="http://www.sundance.tv/series/greenporno">Green Porno</a> as much as I do.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/glasgow-necropolis.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/glasgow-necropolis.small.jpg" width="300"></a> During my first
day I wandered around the city center and then went up to the <a href="http://www.glasgownecropolis.org/">Necropolis</a>. It was
a beautiful place and had a view over the city. Had I been more prepared I would have spent more time
there in search of graves of noteworthy people. On my walk back to the apartment I saw an e-mail from
the company that chartered my cargo ship cruise. Apparently BBC&rsquo;s Travel Show was looking for people
to interview! I got in touch with someone from the BBC, and was scheduled for an interview the next
day. <strong>Update</strong> The interview is <a href="http://www.bbc.com/travel/feature/20140908-taking-cruises-by-way-of-cargo-ship">online</a> now.</p>

<p>The next day I spent the morning doing laundry, and then walked over to the BBC for the interview (<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p0232gkn">the clip is online now</a>).
The camera man was a really cool dude named James Allen. He said he enjoyed the interview
because it was a break from more monotonous stuff he was doing earlier in the day (filming people cooking). Of course
I had to talk about my CBC experience with him and he revealed that he&rsquo;s in a band! They are called
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cJIndPO4OqE">Mummy Short Arms</a>, which is so fitting given the pun I posted on Facebook the day before! After the
interview and lots of walking, I met up with a bunch of ThoughtWorkers for dinner. It became very
clear to me that evening that I miss ThoughtWorkers a lot, but ThoughtWorks not as much.</p>

<h3>Edinburgh</h3>

<p>My last day was spent on a day trip to Edinburgh. People have always said that it&rsquo;s a beautiful city and
they are right. It was more beautiful than I expected and spent the day taking a couple tours. A big
thank you to Rose for telling me about <a href="http://www.neweuropetours.eu/">Sandeman</a> tours. I did the following:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/edinburgh-free-tour.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/edinburgh-free-tour.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newedinburghtours.com/daily-tours/new-edinburgh-free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: After this first tour, I was hooked on this style. The guides were young and
full of enthusiasm. My picture of a guided tour was of a slow moving parade of old people getting bombarded
with facts and dates. This tour group does a great job of keeping the energy up. One thing I observed was how focused
the audience got when the guide mentioned that something was a feature or inspiration for a movie, myself included.
It&rsquo;s interesting how pop culture somehow makes things more relevant to your mind.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newedinburghtours.com/daily-tours/castle-tour-edinburgh.html">Castle Tour</a>: Since I liked the free tour so much, I decided to do the castle tour. The guide
was a <a href="http://www.newedinburghtours.com/our-guides/billy.html">charismatic Scotsman</a> and told a story about the castle and Edinburgh in such a way that you could transport
yourself to that era.</li>
</ul>


<p>I was sad to leave Scotland because it&rsquo;s such a friendly place. Unfortunately it&rsquo;s also expensive,
although I guess it&rsquo;s cheaper than London, but that&rsquo;s not saying much.</p>

<h3>Berlin</h3>

<p>I had to wake up at 3:30am to begin my trip to Berlin! The interary was a bit complex: Glasgow &ndash;> London &ndash;> Brussels
&ndash;> Koln &ndash;> Berlin. Here I was going to stay with an ex-ThoughtWorker, <a href="https://twitter.com/pcalcado">Phil Calcado</a>. The interesting
thing about Phil is that I barely know him! I had a couple beers with him
the year before, but he happily hosted me in his awesome flat for several days. I eventually made it to
his place at around 11:00pm (I didn&rsquo;t quite navigate the Berlin metro optimally that evening). There
was a little <a href="https://soundcloud.com/">SoundCloud</a> gathering going on and another ex-ThoughtWorker, <a href="https://twitter.com/tomczarniecki">Tom Czarniecki</a>, was
there too! It seems the world has ThoughtWorks affiliates everywhere.</p>

<p>It appears I timed things well as I got to be in Germany for the world cup final! Myself and Phil went
down to <a href="http://www.pratergarten.de/d/">Prater Biergarten</a>. Tom joined us a bit later. Then for some odd reason, I got interviewed by
a Mexican journalist. I&rsquo;m not making it up, because Phil and Tom will vouch for me. The whole city turned
into a party and we stayed out til around 4:00am. I still can&rsquo;t get the Uber Deuchstland song out of my head.</p>

<p>Like in Edinburgh, Sandeman does tours in Berlin. I did these three:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/potsdam-tour.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/potsdam-tour.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newberlintours.com/daily-tours/free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: Like in Edinburgh, the guide was passionate and energetic. It was fascinating to
see the Jewish memorial, and place related to the war.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newberlintours.com/daily-tours/potsdam-city-of-emperors.html">Potsdam</a>: I was craving something different and this tour looked to offer that. I got the same
guide as the day before. I didn&rsquo;t know a single thing about the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prussia">Prussian empire</a> before and this tour made me start
reading tons of Wikipedia articles about it. My favourite part of this tour was wandering the gardens created by
emperors, especially <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sanssouci_Park">Sanssouci Park</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newberlintours.com/daily-tours/sachsenhausen-memorial.html">Sauchsenhausen</a>: I wasn&rsquo;t sure what to expect in a tour of a concentration camp. The
guide impressed me by how he approached the subject matter. I&rsquo;m glad I saw the camp, even
though it can&rsquo;t really be described as a pleasant tour. It&rsquo;s a reminder that normal people can do terrible things.</li>
</ul>


<p>Before I left I had one more evening of beers with yet another <a href="https://twitter.com/dtemme">ex-ThoughtWorker</a>, Daniel Temme!</p>

<h3>Heidelberg</h3>

<p>Travel from Berlin to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heidelberg">Heidelberg</a> was a direct train. I made my way to my <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2337045">airbnb</a>
and got settled for spending some time in this beautiful town. I purposely planned to have a free day before the F1. I wandered throughout
the old town and the castle. My favourite thing about this part of the trip are the picnics I had; the top one being
on a bench in Philospher&rsquo;s Way. The weather was so hot that I didn&rsquo;t really want to stay inside a restaurant, nor a
patio. It was really nice to simply purchase some groceries and wander around looking for a nice spot in the town to
eat.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-bridge.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-bridge.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-philosophersweg.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-philosophersweg.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-castle.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-castle.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<h3>German Grand Prix</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hockenheim-podium.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hockenheim-podium.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
Getting to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hockenheim">Hockenheim</a> was pretty straighforward. There&rsquo;s a bus from the train station, or I can take a
train with a single connection in Manheim. The race weekend was super hot with the air temperature around
35C and they said the track temperature was around 55C! I need to learn what exactly track temperature
means, but I&rsquo;m guessing it&rsquo;s how hot it is in you&rsquo;re sitting in the sun.</p>

<p>So far this race is where I&rsquo;ve had the best seats. I was amazing to actually see the cars start the race
and watch them go through the first turn. It was scary to see Massa&rsquo;s car flip during the start of the race but
was relieved to see him walk out of the car. The picture here is a first for me; I actually made it to the podium area for
the awards ceremony!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belgium, France, London and the British Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-08T18:12:19+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>June 24th &ndash; July 7th</em></p>

<h3>Shipment Delivered</h3>

<p>Upon arrival in Antwerp I saw my taxi from the deck. I had all my belongings ready and made my way down
to the port. The ship crew was busy with the offloading of containers so I decided it probably wasn’t a good idea
to disturb them to say farewell. It was a long drive to the immigration office, and there I found out that I needed
a passenger manifest to get the stamp of approval. This meant going all the way back to the ship and back. This
added around an extra hour of taxi travel. The chief mate was ready for my return as he had the document in his
hand. After that confusion, I made it to central Antwerp and found a hotel near the train station.</p>

<p>Antwerp is a fairly small city. The port area takes up more space than the actual city. After a quick nap I wandered
around old Antwerp and in the evening found a little pub. I ended up having more drinks than necessary with a couple
that were a lot of fun. The lady has been in the shipping industry and even knew the ship that I came in on!</p>

<h3>In Bruges</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/bruges.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/bruges.small.jpg" width="300"></a> The trip
from Antwerp to Bruges was pretty easy. As was finding the <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/2176619">residence</a> I was going to stay in. The house was
just outside the old town so after getting some travel logistics out of the way I set out to do a walking tour.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bruges">Bruges</a> is one of the prettiest towns I’ve ever seen. It’s like a snapshot
in time of Belgium several hundred years ago.  In some spots it was insanely crowded, but in other spots it
was quiet and peaceful, which made me stick to those areas. When I got back, I met Lander, the
host of the house. He was very personable and enjoyed conversing with him about my travels.</p>

<p>The next day I did another self guided walking tour. My favourite moment was just relaxing having a couple beers at the
<a href="http://fr.yelp.be/biz/caf%C3%A9-vlissinghe-brugge">oldest tavern</a> in Bruges. After a full day in the town I went back to the house where Lander invited some friends over for
the game. We then headed out to watch the Belgium game in the town square. It was so much fun! I lost the group for a
bit so I gave my round of beers to some random strangers in the crowd. That seemed to make people happy. Next thing I
know it&rsquo;s 5:00am and I&rsquo;m chatting away with a fellow drunk.</p>

<p>These are the beers I had in Belgium:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.dekoninck.be/en">De Koninck</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.boon.be/en/our-beers/geuze-boon-old-style">Gueze Boon</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.rodenbach.be/">Rodenbach</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.trappistwestmalle.be/en/page/dubbel.aspx">Westmalle Trappist Dubbel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.duvel.com/en-us">Duvel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.orval.be/en/58/How-Orval-beer-is-made">Orval</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.abbaye-de-leffe.be/the_beer/en_5_varieties_of_beer_article200.html">Leffe Dark</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/index.php?id=15&amp;L=2">Brugse Zot</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bestbelgianspecialbeers.be/main_eng.html">Tripel Karmeliet</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/index.php?id=14&amp;L=2">Straffe Hendrik</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.achouffe.be/en/beers#la-chouffe">La Chouffe</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Of all of these, I would say the <strong>Tripel Karmeliet</strong> and <strong>Orval</strong> were my favourites. There are so many beers to try
that I really want to come back and spend several weeks sampling all the wonderful beers. There&rsquo;s something about
a country where the monks participate in the brewing process. The day before I got to Bruges, the <a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/">De Halve Maan</a>
had a priest come in and bless their new brewing equipment!</p>

<h3>Dieppe Thoughts</h3>

<p>The next leg of my trip is to Dieppe, France. Unfortunately I woke up hungover and slept through my alarm. This meant
I missed my train which had the best connections to Dieppe. Armed with the
<a href="http://www.eurail.com/plan-your-trip/rail-planner-app">Eurail app</a>, I tried to make a new itinerary.
Due to my decisions of last night, I slept through my connection and passed Brussels. Turned out it didn’t really matter
because at the following station I learned it was the first day of holidays in France and all reservation trains were booked.
Using the app, I figured out an itinerary that could get me to Dieppe without reserved seating. One of the trains was delayed
and I just made my only connecting train with only a minute to spare. Last part of the journey was the walk to to where
I <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/1157655">stayed</a>. The only issue was that I forgot to cache the map, but at least I had a star showing where it
was and functional gps.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dieppe.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dieppe.small.jpg" width="300"></a> My primary motivation
for visiting Dieppe was to see the beaches the Canadian troops attempted to invade in WWII. The
invasion of Dieppe preceded D-Day and was used as an information gathering invasion. Essentially they learned a lot at
the expenses of thousands of lives. I’m not a patriotic person, but I couldn’t help but feel moved by the lives that were lost
there. You can read more at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dieppe_Raid">Wikipedia</a> (notice that my picture of the beach
is very close to the image in Wikipedia!</p>

<p>After my walk about, I walked some more! I headed down to where all the restaurants were and had a nice meal and then
proceeded to hang around the beach area to catch the sunset. It was definitely worth it.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dieppe-sunset.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dieppe-sunset.medium.jpg" width="1024"></a></p>

<h3>A Boat Time</h3>

<p>At 3:30am I left the residence and walked to the ferry terminal. Luckily I walked there the day before so I knew how long
it would take, and that I had to be there at 4:30am. I wasn’t initially planning on being there that early so I’m glad I did
my exploratory research. The ferry was pleasant, but spent the majority of the journey falling asleep and hitting my head against the window.</p>

<h3>London Calling</h3>

<p>The ferry arrived in Newhaven on time. I had a nice chat with the immigration officer who supported my goal of seeing
all the Formula 1 races. I got my luggage and took a series of trains to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hitchin">Hitchin</a> where
I met up with <a href="https://twitter.com/zoodor">Mark</a>, a old ThoughtWorks colleague. It was quite refreshing to see a familiar face!</p>

<p>My next few days were lunch and dinner plans with people I know in London. I got a chance to talk about where my mind
is at regarding my future. It was also nice to see more familiar faces. I really like London, but all the tubing around I was
doing unfortunately left me with a cold before I left.</p>

<h3>Milton Keynes</h3>

<p>This was to be my face for the first F1 on my trip. My <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/1433999">hosts</a> picked up from the
train station. They were amazing hosts and were very pleasant to talk to. I had a lot of fun talking shop
with them as they run an <a href="http://evidencetalks.com/en/">IT business</a> in the city centre.
Their <a href="http://mxcl.github.io/">son</a> is also note-worthy as he created <a href="http://brew.sh/">Homebrew</a>!</p>

<p>The city of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milton_Keynes">Milton Keynes</a> was interesting because it was a planned city.
It was easy to get around, there were plenty of trails that made walking around the periphery quite pleasant.</p>

<h3>This Place is the Bombe!</h3>

<p>I planned for a free day before the race so I could visit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bletchley_Park">Bletchley Park</a>.
It was such an amazing experience to see where
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing">Alan Turing</a> worked and observing a working Colossus, WITCH, and
Bombe machines (in the <a href="http://www.tnmoc.org/">National Museum of Computing</a>)! While visiting the grounds it made
me think about NSA’s involvement in security. If the NSA had a facility that celebrated its ability to crack codes, I don’t think
people would have the same feeling. WWII was great a creating a binary view of activities. Bletchley Park was also
dismantled after the war. I guess things were simpler and less ambiguous then.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what the Colossus sounds like! I wish I recorded a lot more audio because I can hear a song wanting to come out.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no"
src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/157140660&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;visual=true"></iframe>


<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h3>Race 1 of 3</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/british-gp.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/british-gp.small.jpg"></a> The commute to the
track was quite reasonable, but Friday was a bit much for me as I was in the worst part of my cold.
Saturday had the most comfortable weather and I spent a lot of time at the track enjoying different vantage points. Race
day was a big spectacle as it was the 50th race at Silverstone. Before the race there was an air display by the Red Arrows.
It was far better than I had expected. Afterwards I went up to me seat and watched a great race. Lots of drama on the first
lap as Raikonnen had an accident. This red flagged the race as they had to repair a barrier on the track. The rest of the
race was rather uneventful, but the battle between Alonso and Vettel (below) was a show of great driver talent. It was
a shame Roseberg had a malfunction because the battle for 1st could have been just as great.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="640" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/jyhz5c0mR4c" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h3>To Glasgow</h3>

<p>The journey continues to Glasgow, Scotland! The write up for that will have to wait though as this post is long
enough. I was going to write about my learnings over the last few weeks, but will hold that thought for a bit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossing the Atlantic via Container Ship]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/crossing-the-atlantic-via-container-ship/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-24T09:32:51+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/crossing-the-atlantic-via-container-ship</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned in my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america/">last post</a>, I finished the crossing of the Atlantic ocean via container ship. It was a great
experiene that I&rsquo;ll happily do again. 11 days wasn&rsquo;t enough, and would be happy to spend a month next time around.</p>

<h3>Too Much Twine on my Hands</h3>

<p>A blog post probably wouldn&rsquo;t due the experience justice so I decided to play around with a basic word game engine to
give you a more <a href="http://scottmuc.com/twinery/independent-accord.html">self-directed tour</a>. Hope you enjoy it!</p>

<p>Working with <a href="http://twinery.org/">Twine</a> was quite enjoyable and I could see myself using it a lot in many different lines of work. If I was
still consulting, it would become a prominent tool in my tool-belt. My biggest complaint with it is that the
documentation is all online so I couldn&rsquo;t figure out how to do anything more sophisticated than what I created.</p>

<h3>Man Over-bored</h3>

<p>Honestly, that header was just for the pun factor. What amazed me about the voyage was how quick it went by. I didn&rsquo;t
think <strong>once</strong> that I wanted it to end and that I was bored. I savoured not being in a rush to do anything. The only structure to my
days revolved around meals which were at: 07:30, 12:30, and 17:30. That set my rythym for the 11 days.</p>

<h3>Crew Man Group</h3>

<p>The ship was run by a crew of 21, all male. The captain was Romanian and the rest of the officers were Croation. The chief
engineer was Ukrainian and the rest were Filipino. Everyone was very nice, but when asked for their name, they simply
asked to be addressed by their position (Third, Chief, etc&hellip;).</p>

<h3>Retrospective</h3>

<p><strong>What Went Well</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Scotch &ndash; Sipping 18yo Glenlivet was a wonderful way to be even <em>more</em> relaxed</li>
<li>Jambox &ndash; This dependable gadget has been filling rooms with tunes well for several years now</li>
<li>Offline Wikipedia &ndash; Wow! I cannot believe how much I perused Wikipedia while I was on this trip.</li>
<li>11 days of no expenses &ndash; Being disconnected is a good way to not spend money.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Not So Well</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Gym clothes &ndash; There&rsquo;s an exercise room with a stationary bike. I wasn&rsquo;t always allowed on the main deck (to do laps
around the ship) so being able to do 30min of hard cardio would have been good to stave off the belly I grew.</li>
<li>Scotch &ndash; One bottle was definitely not enough.</li>
<li>Offline map &ndash; I would have liked to better explorer the route and plan the rest of my trip better.</li>
<li>Making Twine tour at the last minute &ndash; I wish I had a skeleton of it done much earlier so I could get more details
from the crew.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Action Items</strong>: I&rsquo;ll definitely do this again and I&rsquo;ll be sure to come with a fitness plan. Though that directly opposes the action to
bring more liquor.</p>

<h3>Offline By Default</h3>

<p>Being disconnected from the world for 11 days was a far better experience than I had expected. It&rsquo;s made me realize I
need to create a habit of disconnecting. It brought me back to the era when your computer was offline by default, and
you had to explicitly connect to see what&rsquo;s going on in the rest of the Internet universe. This experience has showed me
that I like that. It may sound backwards to a lot of people, but the computer has always been a tool, not an
entertainment device (gaming being the exception). My phone may eventually be the only always-connected device, but even
then, I turn off all notifications and keep it silent.</p>

<h3>Let the Eurotrip Begin</h3>

<p>After a 140 euro ride through immigration and into Antwerp, I can begin the next phase of my journey!</p>

<p><strong>Update</strong> I was later interviewed by the BBC and the video is <a href="http://www.bbc.com/travel/feature/20140908-taking-cruises-by-way-of-cargo-ship">online</a> now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaving Vancouver and North America]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-13T18:40:36+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After another relaxing two weeks in Vancouver (and attending <a href="http://www.sasquatchfestival.com/">Sasquatch</a>), it&rsquo;s time to leave. Here&rsquo;s the
last sunset I watched from the beach. If you can believe it, the weather in Vancouver was 99% rain free!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/kits-sunset.jpg"></p>

<h3>Schools Out for Summer</h3>

<p>During my downtime I&rsquo;ve enrolled in the <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/money">Economics of Banking and Money</a> on <a href="https://www.coursera.org">Coursera</a>. I never
thought I would find learning this stuff so much fun! To supplement the course material, I&rsquo;ve been listening to the
following podcasts too:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/">Planet Money</a></li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/radio/">Freakanomics Radio</a></li>
</ul>


<p>This is the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course">MOOC</a> I&rsquo;ve taken and I really enjoy the format. It could be the fact that I&rsquo;m older and have
already been established in a career for a while that my approach to learning is different. School always seemed to be
about grades to me growing up. With this course, I&rsquo;m more focused on learning and developing an intuition for the
subject.</p>

<p>From this course I&rsquo;ve learned that the banking and money system is a lot more complicated than I thought. I also now
feel that the system itself isn&rsquo;t altogether evil, it&rsquo;s just trying to facilitate trade the best that it can. I&rsquo;m still
not confident in my ability to summarize what I&rsquo;ve learnt so far, but I think I&rsquo;m going to come out of this much more
empowered.</p>

<h3>Ship Happens</h3>

<p>Today I finally start my voyage on a container ship! You can track where I am on this <a href="http://www.marinetraffic.com/ais/details/ships/636091353/vessel:INDEPENDENT_ACCORD">Facebook for ships</a>
website. If you search for the name &ldquo;Independent Accord&rdquo; in your favourite online search website
you&rsquo;ll see there are dozens of websites that have databases of ships. The websites are pretty well done too. I had no
idea this shipping world can be so interesting. I&rsquo;m sure the captain and crew are going to be sick of my questions over
the next 11 days.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested, <a href="http://www.cruisepeople.co.uk/">here&rsquo;s</a> that I booked my travel through. If you&rsquo;re nostalgic for the 90&rsquo;s you&rsquo;ll
enjoy it a lot.</p>

<h3>Map Reduce</h3>

<p>Since I have all this time on my hands, I&rsquo;ve started journalling the places that I&rsquo;m staying (and coffee shops I leech
Internet off of) in this <a href="https://mapsengine.google.com/map/edit?mid=znoHAqfzfPKU.k2lUp8fKHDCg">online map</a>. It&rsquo;s work in progress and will be fleshed out more as I go.</p>

<h3>Back to Life, Back to Reality</h3>

<p>One question I&rsquo;ve been getting asked frequently is &ldquo;when are you coming back to reality?&rdquo;. I find it an odd question.
This is reality. There&rsquo;s nothing to get back to (unless I could travel in time). Sure, I&rsquo;ll be figuring out what to do
work wise. Not sure how that&rsquo;s coming &ldquo;back&rdquo; to reality though. I think we&rsquo;re living in an era where social norms are
shifting all over the place. Hopes and aspirations appear to be more varied than before. One persons normality is
another persons exceptionality. So when I hear this question my interpretation is &ldquo;when are you coming back to the
lifestyle of yours that I consider normal?&rdquo;.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m starting to feel the career break settling in. I&rsquo;ve slowed things down a lot. My favourite thing to do now is leave
my phone behind and go for a wander. Writing blog posts like this is much more fulfilling than a series of micro-blogs
(aka tweets) that lack context, albeit they are more timely.</p>

<p>See you on the other side!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing Powershell Code That Talks to CLR Objects]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/testing-powershell-code-that-talks-to-clr-objects/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-06T06:09:41+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/testing-powershell-code-that-talks-to-clr-objects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several months ago someone posted an excellent question on the <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/pester/Y8UzSiNlcSE">Pester Group</a> about a certain problem area
in testing PowerShell with <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester">Pester</a>.  He brings up a relevant example of the difficulties that can occur when writing tests
is done afterwards. It also reveals a missing feature of Pester.</p>

<p>First let me display the code that needed tests:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/e5abe37881628f13cd0a.js?file=Get-FromSFtp.ps1'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>Add-Type -Path (Join-Path -Path $psScriptRoot &quot;Renci.SshNet.dll&quot;)

function Get-FromSFtp {
    $fileList=$null
    try {
        $sftp=New-Object Renci.SshNet.SftpClient(&quot;127.0.0.1&quot;,&quot;test&quot;,&quot;test&quot;)
        $sftp.Connect()
        if($sftp.IsConnected) {
            $sftp.ChangeDirectory(&quot;/test&quot;)
            $fileList=$sftp.ListDirectory(&quot;.&quot;)
        }
        return $fileList
    } catch [Exception] {
        Write-Host $_.Exception.ToString()
    } finally {
        if(($sftp -ne $null) -and ($sftp.IsConnected)) {
            $sftp.Disconnect()
        }
    }
}
</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>Here are a couple reasons why this code is difficult to test:</p>

<ul>
<li>Line 4 returns a CLR object that actually does SFTP</li>
<li>Many parameters are hard coded</li>
</ul>


<h3>Start With Integration</h3>

<p>I started this exercise with the intention of not changing a single character of the code submitted. Here&rsquo;s the story of
how the changes took place (I had a git repo of this, but the files got corrupted). First thing to do was to make the
existing code pass a test as is. In order to do that, I needed an integration environment for it to talk to. So I used
<a href="http://www.vagrantup.com/">Vagrant</a> to spin up a local linux box. I manually configured the box such that the credentials in the code
work. Here&rsquo;s the Vagrantfile</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/e5abe37881628f13cd0a.js?file=Vagrantfile'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># -*- mode: ruby -*-
# vi: set ft=ruby :

# Vagrantfile API/syntax version. Don&#39;t touch unless you know what you&#39;re doing!
VAGRANTFILE_API_VERSION = &quot;2&quot;

Vagrant.configure(VAGRANTFILE_API_VERSION) do |config|
  config.vm.box = &quot;precise64&quot;
  config.vm.box_url = &quot;http://files.vagrantup.com/precise64.box&quot;
  config.vm.network &quot;forwarded_port&quot;, guest: 22, host: 22
end
</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>and here&rsquo;s the passing test. I&rsquo;m happy with it because I could change the code or the environment and cause the test to
fail, thus giving me confidence that the test is good enough to tell if me I broke anything.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="n">Describe</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Get-FromSFtp Integration&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;returns the 2 default dir entries&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">Get-FromSFtp</span> <span class="p">|</span> <span class="k">ForEach</span><span class="n">-Object</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nv">$_</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Name</span> <span class="p">}</span> <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Be</span> <span class="s2">&quot;.&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;..&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Happy that I have a feedback loop going now, I begin to start testing the code in isolation. I start by writing the
contexts and specifications:</p>

<h3>Follow Up With Isolated Tests</h3>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="n">Describe</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Get-FromSFtp&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">Context</span> <span class="s2">&quot;when connected&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;attempts to connect to an sftp server&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;changes to the directory /test&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;gets the contents listing of the directory&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;disconnects from the sftp server&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">Context</span> <span class="s2">&quot;when not connected&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;returns 0 files&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">Context</span> <span class="s2">&quot;when an error happens&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;prints out the error to the user&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I was stumped for a bit because I realized Pester didn&rsquo;t have the power necessary to do this easily. It didn&rsquo;t mean it
couldn&rsquo;t be tested though. The Mocking functionality came to the rescue as I was able to mock <code>New-Object</code> and decouple
my tests from the <code>Renci.SshNet</code> library. The hard part was hand-rolling the mock object to be used in the tests.</p>

<p>One by one, I made each spec pass. The beginning of each <code>Context</code> was the setup, and each <code>It</code> asserted something from
after that setup and action had been taken. The nice thing that resulted was I could break a specific piece of the
production code, and the specific test would tell me that it&rsquo;s broken at that place (eg: change the directory the
production code goes to).</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the complete test file for the code:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/e5abe37881628f13cd0a.js?file=Get-FromSFtp.Tests.ps1'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>$here = Split-Path -Parent $MyInvocation.MyCommand.Path
$sut = (Split-Path -Leaf $MyInvocation.MyCommand.Path).Replace(&quot;.Tests.&quot;, &quot;.&quot;)
. &quot;$here\$sut&quot;

$mockSFtpCode = @&quot;
public class MockSFtp {
    public bool ConnectCalled { get; private set; }
    public bool DisconnectCalled { get; private set; }
    public bool IsConnected { get; set; }
    public string ChangeDirectoryParam { get; private set; }
    public string ListDirectoryParam { get; private set; }

    public void Connect() {
        this.ConnectCalled = true;
    }

    public void Disconnect() {
        this.DisconnectCalled = true;
    }

    public void ChangeDirectory(string directory) {
        this.ChangeDirectoryParam = directory;
    }

    public string[] ListDirectory(string path) {
        this.ListDirectoryParam = path;
        return new string[] { &quot;test1&quot; };
    }
}
&quot;@

$throwingMockSFtpCode = @&quot;
public class ThrowingMockSFtp {
    public void Connect() {
        throw new System.Exception();
    }
}
&quot;@

Add-Type -TypeDefinition $mockSFtpCode
Add-Type -TypeDefinition $throwingMockSFtpCode

Describe &quot;Get-FromSFtp&quot; {
    Context &quot;when connected&quot; {
        $mockSFtp = New-Object MockSFtp
        $mockSFtp.IsConnected = $true
        Mock New-Object -MockWith { $mockSFtp }
        $files = Get-FromSFtp

        It &quot;attempts to connect to an sftp server&quot; {
            $mockSFtp.ConnectCalled | Should Be $true
        }

        It &quot;changes to the directory /test&quot; {
            $mockSFtp.ChangeDirectoryParam | Should Be &#39;/test&#39;
        }

        It &quot;gets the content listing of the directory&quot; {
            $mockSFtp.ListDirectoryParam | Should Be &#39;.&#39;
            $files | Should Be @(&quot;test1&quot;)
        }

        It &quot;disconnects from the sftp server&quot; {
            $mockSFtp.DisconnectCalled | Should Be $true
        }
    }

    Context &quot;when not connected&quot; {
        $mockSFtp = New-Object MockSFtp
        $mockSFtp.IsConnected = $false
        Mock New-Object -MockWith { $mockSFtp }
        $files = Get-FromSFtp

        It &quot;returns 0 files&quot; {
            $files | Should BeNullOrEmpty
        }
    }

    Context &quot;when an exception happens&quot; {
        $mockSFtp = New-Object ThrowingMockSFtp
        Mock New-Object -MockWith { $mockSFtp }

        It &quot;prints out the error to the user&quot; {
            # I do not think this is a good test, but until
            # mocking of Write-Host can be done, this is all
            # that we can really do.
            { Get-FromSFtp } | Should Not Throw
        }
    }
}

Describe &quot;Get-FromSFtp Integration&quot; {
    It &quot;returns the 2 default dir entries&quot; {
        Get-FromSFtp | ForEach-Object { $_.Name } | Should Be &quot;.&quot;, &quot;..&quot;
    }
}
</code></pre></noscript></div>


<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I can&rsquo;t say this is the best test code out there. I think testing PowerShell is in a different place than testing C# or
other OO languages. It seems like the best you can do is test the function logic and test the composition of it all in
an integrated way. The first refactoring change I would likely do to this function is make the connection a parameter.
That way I wouldn&rsquo;t need to mock <code>New-Object</code>, but passing a mock object is still an issue. Perhaps Pester needs a mock
object builder of some kind, though writing mocks by hand wasn&rsquo;t too difficult either. It&rsquo;s something I would expect a
testing framework to be able to do for me though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Weeks Living Off the Clock]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/two-weeks-living-off-the-clock/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-23T04:44:14+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/two-weeks-living-off-the-clock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the last two weeks I&rsquo;ve been house sitting for a friend in the beautiful area of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kitsilano">Kitsalano</a> in Vancouver. The
goal for the two weeks was to figure out the rest of my travel plans and to meet up with a lot of my friends and
acquaintances that I haven&rsquo;t seen for a while.</p>

<h3>According to Plan?</h3>

<p>The two weeks went by quickly. I mainly organized myself around other people&rsquo;s clocks. This meant meeting people for
lunch or after work the majority of the time. Since I had gaps in time between meet ups, I spent a lot of time walking
everywhere (and sometimes biking). Experiencing many modes of transportation ends up being an influence on me later on.
It was refreshing to not be the dictator of my time, albeit my intentions did dictate who to meet. So by a transitive
relationship, I was still directing my time?</p>

<h3>Natural Time Management</h3>

<p>As an experiment I decided to not turn my morning alarm clock on. I&rsquo;ve always thought of myself as a morning person and
wanted to see if that held true. What ended up happening was that I rolled out of bed around 8:30pm every morning
regardless of when I went to bed (range: 11:00pm &ndash; 1:00am). I&rsquo;m curious about whether or not work pressure (or pressure
in general) has been the cause of my normal much earlier natural wake up time.</p>

<p>Another normal time structure that I thought my body adhered to strictly was when to eat. I started to eat when I was hungry
and found that some days I only ate 1 meal, or my lunch ended up happening at 4pm. There wasn&rsquo;t any natural rhythm to my
eating times.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s interesting to start following nature&rsquo;s conventions rather than socially, and I guess structurally imposed ones.</p>

<h3>Career Ideas</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s nice when part of my &ldquo;mission&rdquo; with this career break moves forward in some dimension. During my many walks along
the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seawall_(Vancouver)">seawall</a> I&rsquo;ve listened to many episodes of <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a>. One in particular got me a little bit
inspired. The episode was about <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/charles_marohn.html">Strong Towns</a>, and revealed that I have a lot of interest in urban
development. Shortly after that, I had dinner with a colleague, and conversation with his girlfriend got me inspired
too. It turns out she works for <a href="http://www.translink.ca/">TransLink</a> and she mentioned there&rsquo;s work available for someone with my
skills. What fascinated me was my initial feeling of joy to chat with someone regarding this topic.</p>

<p>Did I mention that I&rsquo;m slowing getting addicted to <a href="http://www.positech.co.uk/democracy3/">Democracy 3</a>?</p>

<h3>Speaking of Transport</h3>

<p>Being mobile via foot, bike, bus, train, and car share has reinforced my thoughts on urban planning. Another part of my
&ldquo;mission&rdquo; is to figure out where to live. Being mobile, while having a low impact, is an opinion that has been further
strengthened while being here. The bicycle is such a wonderful piece of engineering that has changed, relatively, little
over the years. It&rsquo;s an efficient form of transport and it&rsquo;s fun. I can&rsquo;t imagine living anywhere where I wouldn&rsquo;t feel
comfortable riding a bike much of the time.</p>

<h3>Discovering the Source of My Anxiety</h3>

<p>In my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month/">previous post</a> I alluded to a sense of anxiousness that I was feeling. It dawned on me that I was spending a lot of
time coordinating what was going to be a hurried and expensive road trip across the continent. Eventually I realized
that I didn&rsquo;t have to do that trip. I&rsquo;m already going to be doing plenty of travel in the coming months. It also
occurred to me that I spent a good amount of my &ldquo;relaxing&rdquo; time trying to make this trip work. So I&rsquo;ve canceled the
road trip and am going to spend an extra two weeks in Vancouver!</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the list of reasons that convinced that this was the right decision:</p>

<ul>
<li>Not providing ample time to truly enjoy the trip</li>
<li>Not being able to spend a proper amount of time visiting each and every person</li>
<li>Going to be more expensive than the cargo ship cruise!</li>
<li>Goes against the principles of this career break which is to take things slowly and this road trip would be a dash to Wilmington, NC</li>
<li>Lessons learned from the SF road trip (I should have slowed it down)</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m not doing any of the tech related practice I&rsquo;ve wanted to do</li>
</ul>


<p>Not sure if the software analogy fits, but it felt like removing scope from an unfinished project.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>Responding to feedback is important. On my road trip to San Francisco I learned that I&rsquo;m not going slow enough during my
time off. During the last two weeks in Vancouver I learned that it&rsquo;s nice to stand still and I wasn&rsquo;t doing too much of
that. The speed of the journey and the complexity in coordinating amongst many people and locations was resulting in an
energy level overhead that was creating anxiety (and how can someone who&rsquo;s not working possibly feel anxious about
anything). Responding to this feedback by canceling the road trip made me feel like a weight was lifted off of my
shoulders.</p>

<p>Along with the negative feedback, I&rsquo;m going to explore the positive feedback my mind felt when pondering ideas around
urban planning and public transport.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I won&rsquo;t get to see a lot of people that I wanted to, but I realized the quality of the interactions is more
important than the quantity of the interactions. This touches on my principle of doing things slowly during this break.
No better way to go slow than to stand still. Queue the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dMSFqXGZ5TQ">Rush</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections of Being Unemployed and Homeless for 1 Month]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-13T07:43:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For some context, you may want to read my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">previous post</a> about quitting my job.</p>

<p>I am homeless and unemployed in probably the most priveleged meaning of the terms. Both states of being are choices I&rsquo;ve
explicitly made. From what I&rsquo;ve read, I&rsquo;m not really on a sabbatical, but I&rsquo;m on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Career_break">Career Break</a>, except the homeless
aspect of it is not as conventional.</p>

<p>So here are the reflections:</p>

<h3>Where Am I Sleeping Tonight</h3>

<p>On September 1st 2012 I gave up my awesome apartment in Calgary as I prepared for an assignment in India (without
really knowing where I was going after that). I changed my mailing address to my brothers place and really didn&rsquo;t feel
much had changed. I had already been travelling weekly for my work assignments since April 2011, and I picked up my life
and departed <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/a-new-beginning-or-goodbye-20-s-hello-30-s/">Vancouver to Calgary</a> in January 2010.</p>

<p>In the last month I&rsquo;ve spent 13 nights in different beds. One of those nights was part of a 30 hour trip from
Johannesburg to Vancouver, and another night was one where I lost my dignity in Vegas (ask me to show you the scar one
day). I&rsquo;ve learned there&rsquo;s a lot of overhead in figuring out where you&rsquo;re going to sleep (and I have it easy compared to
those who aren&rsquo;t homeless by choice).</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s hit me those most is the disappearance of the sense of belonging. For 8 months I &ldquo;lived&rdquo; in a Residence Inn in
Bellevue, Washington and it was as much of a home as anywhere. I belonged there, had my routine haunts, and knew where I
was going to be for weeks on end. Nowadays I&rsquo;m either imposing on friends and family, or spending too much for a
hotel&hellip; ok, and using home sharing websites which is like a hybrid of the two.</p>

<p>So I guess this break has been successful in teaching me something already. I need to find a place to live. I do like
the traveling lifestyle, but only when I have a home base.</p>

<h3>Talk Talk Talk</h3>

<p>For some reason, this first month break started off strong with lots of conversations with people in the tech industry.
Maybe I was seeking the familiar so these conversations fit in my comfort zone. I&rsquo;ve probably spoken to over 10 or so
companies and am journaling my pursuits as I go. I&rsquo;ve added a constraint on my life that I won&rsquo;t work for 6 months so
it&rsquo;s hard to not jump on what seem to be great opportunities.</p>

<h3>No Startup For Me</h3>

<p>As a technologist, I&rsquo;m passionate about open standards and infrastructure that makes the Internet work. The last thing I
would want as a startup is for my company name to be a verb (eg: Uber, Tweet). Technology like: SMTP, HTTP, HTML, DNS
aren&rsquo;t corporate brand names. I like to live in abstractions, and as a business owner, I think that&rsquo;s probably the worst
characteristic I could probably have in order to be successful.</p>

<p>In fact, I&rsquo;ve challenged myself to minimize the brands names I speak unless it&rsquo;s trully an endorsement for the brand.
Here are some of the translations I&rsquo;m attempting to do:</p>

<ul>
<li>Tweet &ndash;> microblog</li>
<li>Uber &ndash;> rideshare</li>
<li>Nexus 4 &ndash;> phone</li>
<li>Coke &ndash;> cola</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://www.marriott.com/">Marriott</a>, on the other hand, is a brand I&rsquo;m happy to publicly endorse.</p>

<p>So yeah&hellip; given that one aspect of success for a startup is something I&rsquo;m not advocating, I think it&rsquo;ll be hard for me
to be part of a startup. Though, I think this really depends on the state of the startup.</p>

<h3>I&rsquo;m Super Lucky</h3>

<p>Part of what has made this break possible is the amazing network of friends and aquaintances I&rsquo;ve made over the years. There
are couches available to me all over the world and that&rsquo;s something I feel super blessed about. I really have to thank
<a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/join">ThoughtWorks</a> for enabling me to meet people from everywhere and make these connections.</p>

<h3>A Hint of Concern</h3>

<p>You would think after 1 month of not working I would feel stress free. For some reason there&rsquo;s still a hanging anxiety.
Part of it is probably my first point about finding a home. The other is that I feel there&rsquo;s something bigger that I
should be doing. Being in Vancouver for the last little while has sparked a stream of nostalgia and reflections on a
simpler and a more naive past.</p>

<h3>Familiar is Good</h3>

<p>This probably isn&rsquo;t a surprise to anyone that knows me, but I&rsquo;m a fan of the familiar. When I drove down to Seattle, I
visited <a href="http://www.oobatooba.com/">Ooba Tooba</a> and <a href="http://bathtubginseattle.com/">Bathtub Gin</a>. In San Francisco I went to the <a href="http://www.beresford.com/beresford/restaurant.htm">White Horse Tavern</a>. Anytime I go back to a place I
haven&rsquo;t been to in a while, I favour hitting the familiar places rather than trying something new. This is clearly part
of who I am and find it something I can&rsquo;t negotiate.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I have no idea how to summarize anything right now. The focus is on data ingress and going to delegate the analysis to a
later time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaving a Dream Job and Going on an Adventure]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-26T23:58:28+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On January 4th 2010 I joined <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/a-new-beginning-or-goodbye-20-s-hello-30-s/">ThoughtWorks</a> and it has been an amazing journey. I&rsquo;ve seen more systems,
worked with more people, and seen more countries than the entire 30 years that preceded that date. I still can&rsquo;t believe
how lucky I&rsquo;ve been to have such a wonderful opportunity. That&rsquo;s why it took me a long time to decide to leave it, and
go on a bit of an adventure.</p>

<h2>Why Leave Such a Good Thing?</h2>

<p>For some reason I&rsquo;ve had every job I&rsquo;ve had for 4 years since I was 12 years old, so I&rsquo;m just keeping to my routine! To
be honest though, there were a few things that instigated this change.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Consulting Fatigue</strong> &ndash; It&rsquo;s hard work always coming in as an outsider and trying to convince people to change their
ways. You never know if what you suggest is correct, and there&rsquo;s always so much context to process. One thing that I&rsquo;ve gotten
out of this though is becoming much more of a critical thinker. I&rsquo;ve learned to hold off on knee-jerk reactions and to
actively listen to the problem at hand. This has been something I apply on a day-to-day basis.</li>
<li><strong>Product Complacency</strong> &ndash; Though, I&rsquo;ve worked on some interesting projects (the latest being very cool), I can&rsquo;t shake
the satisfaction I got from working at <a href="http://music.cbc.ca/radio3/">CBC Radio 3</a> where I got to essentially build the product I wanted to
build on my own anyways. This may have been mitigated but the following reason adds to this one.</li>
<li><strong>Miss Small Teams</strong> &ndash; For some reason people thought I was great at working on large programs of work. While I thought
the challenges were interesting, I&rsquo;m more a small business person at heart. Some may be surprised by this because I&rsquo;ve
been on small teams, but they were in these large programs of work. I&rsquo;ve learned that I&rsquo;m more of a system thinker than I
thought and I find myself getting lost in the system thinking and see myself as this tiny insignificant cog just
wanting to make some impactful change.</li>
</ul>


<p>Though I&rsquo;m listing things related to ThoughtWorks, a lot of my weariness is more from IT in general. It could be an age
thing, but I&rsquo;ve been around long enough to see a lot of terrible things going on in this industry. No one seems to care
about security, and the innovation that is making billions in the stock market are consumer products that mean almost
nothing to me. It&rsquo;s hard to be optimistic after <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Snowden">Edward Snowden</a> revealed the NSA privacy issues.</p>

<p>In the last few years I&rsquo;ve managed to save some money, and given that I&rsquo;m still relatively young and healthy, I thought
now is the time to take a break before I get too cynical.</p>

<h2>What am I Going to do?</h2>

<p>The plan right now is pretty loose, but I have made a rough 6 month itinerary:</p>

<ul>
<li>Head back to North America. This will involve crashing at my brother&rsquo;s places and spend some time with family
and friends.</li>
<li>Do some roadtrips in Canada and the USA.</li>
<li>Taking a cargo ship across the Atlantic.</li>
<li>July is the month of Formula 1! I have tickets for the British GP and the German GP.</li>
<li>Visit Eastern Europe.</li>
<li>Hang out in India for a couple months.</li>
</ul>


<p>Along with the travels, I will be taking some mental journeys</p>

<ul>
<li>I want to study economics and capitalism. If we&rsquo;re in this prison of a system, I want to be an educated prisoner.</li>
<li>Get back to the basics of software development and attempt to unlearn all this &ldquo;Enterprise&rdquo; cruft I&rsquo;ve picked up.
Hoping to to this by learning a few new languages, doing code katas daily and releasing tiny side projects.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a stretch, but I would like to do some athletic training (mainly running).</li>
</ul>


<p>Like most things, I&rsquo;m probably thinking about it too much, but in this case it&rsquo;s the planning that&rsquo;s been valuable and
not the plan itself.</p>

<h2>Sounds Awesome, but That Cannot Last Forever</h2>

<p>During this time I&rsquo;m attempting to figure out future career ideas. At the end I&rsquo;ll
figure out a place to live and what on my list of interesting domains to pursue:</p>

<ul>
<li>Formula 1</li>
<li>Health care</li>
<li>Beer / Cocktails</li>
<li>Golf</li>
<li>Energy</li>
<li>Public Transportation</li>
<li>Music Distribution</li>
<li>Billiards</li>
<li>Space Exploration</li>
<li>City Planning</li>
<li>Software Delivery</li>
</ul>


<p>Heck, I haven&rsquo;t ruled out re-applying to ThoughtWorks.</p>

<h2>ThoughtWorks Made Me Do This</h2>

<p>The irony is that that ThoughtWorks has opened up my mind in such a way that it&rsquo;s empowered me to make this decision.
The ingress of information, concerns, cultures, opinions and experience is a storm brewing in my head trying it&rsquo;s best to
synthesize itself the best it can. If you&rsquo;re thinking about applying at ThoughtWorks, please ping me. It&rsquo;s an awesome
place to work, and full of great people. During this sabbitcal I plan on visiting as many ThoughtWorkers as I can!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking forward to reading this post a year from now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - Devops]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T07:47:52+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Valuable Links for Devops</h2>

<p>TL;DR &ndash; Watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3KpPBnEtRj4">this</a> video</p>

<p>Since I first learned the term devops 4 years ago I&rsquo;ve gone through many leaps in understanding. I really wish I saw
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o7-IuYS0iSE">this video (history of devops)</a> before I got involved. As a software developer, I find delivering
frequently highly motivating. Devops is a set of principles and practices that aim to ensure delivery goes as smooth
as possible. I found this post, <a href="http://blog.devopsguys.com/2014/02/25/a-scientific-basis-for-devops-success/">A Scientific Basis For Devops Success</a>, to be a great introduction
to why devops is important.</p>

<h2>People</h2>

<p>This list isn&rsquo;t comprehensive, but you can&rsquo;t go wrong by reading what these people have to say:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://jedi.be/">Patrick Debois</a> &ndash; coined the term devops</li>
<li><a href="http://www.noahsussman.com/">Noah Sussman</a> &ndash; provides excellent insights around QA</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kitchensoap.com/">John Allspaw</a> &ndash; has many excellent posts on the culture of devops</li>
<li><a href="http://itrevolution.com/">Gene Kim</a> &ndash; co-author of The Phoenix Project</li>
<li><a href="http://continuousdelivery.com/">Jez Humble</a> &ndash; co-author of Continuous Delivery</li>
</ul>


<h2>Devops is not a Role</h2>

<p>It took me a while to realize that devops is not a role played on a team and that it&rsquo;s got more in commong with Agile in
the fact that it&rsquo;s a collection of principles rather than straight up proceesses.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.getchef.com/blog/2010/07/16/what-devops-means-to-me/">CAMS</a> &ndash; <a href="https://twitter.com/botchagalupe/">John Willis</a>&lsquo; posts a list of principles</li>
<li><a href="http://blog.lusis.org/blog/2013/06/04/devops-the-title-match/">Lusis&#8217; rant</a> &ndash; an excellent rant about the absurditity of devops being a role</li>
</ul>


<h2>Must Watch Videos</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3KpPBnEtRj4">The Devops Transformation</a> &ndash; <a href="https://twitter.com/benr/">Ben Rockwood</a> does a most
enlightening talk on the subject.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h5E--QSBVBY">Devops Demystified</a> &ndash; Another <strong>Ben Rockwood</strong> talk that is awesome</li>
</ul>


<h2>Events</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/">DevOpsDays</a></li>
<li><a href="http://devopssummit.com/">DevOps Summit</a></li>
<li><a href="http://web.experiencedevops.org/">Experience DevOps</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Mailing Lists</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://code.google.com/p/devops-toolchain/">Devops Toolchain</a></li>
<li><a href="http://devopsweekly.com/">Devops Weekly</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Tools</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://devops-bookmarks.herokuapp.com/">Devops Bookmarks</a> &ndash; This is the ultimate one stop shop for all tools</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Developer Resolutions for 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T10:45:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was tempted to not write this post. My motivations are changing a bit and growing strong technically isn&rsquo;t one of
my top priorities nowadays.</p>

<h2>Reflections on <a href="http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2013/">2013</a></h2>

<p>Last year was very interesting for me. It&rsquo;s the first time I didn&rsquo;t really have a home. I&rsquo;ve split my time between
India, United States, and South Africa, (ok, I was in Toronto for a few weeks too). During that time I&rsquo;ve reflected a
lot (probably too much). My work was split between training new software developers and developing tools to deploy
the largest and most complex distributed system I&rsquo;ve ever worked on.</p>

<p>First, let&rsquo;s look back at 2013 and see how I did with my resolutions:</p>

<ul>
<li>Read 7 Languages in 7 Weeks &ndash; This was a massive fail. I never even got past chapter 1!</li>
<li>More Presentations &ndash; I would give myself a passing grade here. I&rsquo;ve started doing more internal presentations, but
I&rsquo;m sure that there&rsquo;s expectation for me to do more. The problem here is that I really don&rsquo;t enjoy delivering
presentations, but I do struggle when I believe I have interesting things to say and they&rsquo;re stuck in my head. I
definitely need an outlet and will have to figure this out going forward.</li>
<li>Expand my Ops Toolbelt &ndash; This one was definitely a success. I&rsquo;ve picked up Puppet, Ansible and MCollective. Also, I
feel that I&rsquo;ve grown quite adept at Continuous Delivery pipelines and Vagrantizing development environments.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Development Goals for 2014:</h2>

<p>2014 is going to be a different year for me. I don&rsquo;t really care about goals as much, but want to build better habits. I&rsquo;ve reached
many of my goals only to regress behaviour after the goals have been achieved. I&rsquo;ve realized that many of my technical
goals were due more to my ego and fear of looking dumb in front of colleagues and clients. I&rsquo;ve realized that I actually
have a pretty good personal brand, and that people respect my abilities. I&rsquo;ve proven myself over and over again, and
it&rsquo;s time for me to believe it myself.</p>

<h3>Increase Signal to Noise Ratio</h3>

<p>Social media tax is too high for me right now. It&rsquo;s time to start culling the amount of inputs I have. At least I&rsquo;ve
deleted my LinkedIn account. I&rsquo;m going to have a daily unfriend/unfollow 1 person, until I feel things are a bit more
manageable. One small victory in 2013 was deleting my LinkedIn account.</p>

<p>Improving my e-mail habits are up there as well. Things like not checking my e-mail before work is a habit that I plan
on picking up. I also need to write less e-mails. E-mails beget more e-mail.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Facebook Friends at end of 2013</strong> == 480</li>
<li><strong>Following on Twitter at of 2013</strong> == 627</li>
</ul>


<h3>Learn Docker</h3>

<p>OK, I&rsquo;ll sneak in a technical goal. I want to simply understand what the hype is around <a href="https://www.docker.io/">Docker</a>. I tend to be very slow
to catch onto trends. There&rsquo;s enough hype around Docker that I think I should at least understand what I&rsquo;m missing if I
do miss that boat.</p>

<h3>Do Meaningful Work</h3>

<p>4 years ago I left <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/">CBC</a> for <a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/">ThoughtWorks</a>. I don&rsquo;t regret the decision at all, but I now understand what it&rsquo;s like to do
meaningful work. Working on <a href="http://music.cbc.ca/#/blogs/2009/12/Today-on-Lanarama-Techie-Tuesday-A-Fond-Farewell-to-Scott-Muc">Radio 3</a> was fulfilling work, and I&rsquo;m still proud of what was created, and have strong
connections with the people I worked with there.</p>

<p>The tough part about the consulting business is that you can potentially work for money hungry
organisations. I personally don&rsquo;t want to help retail vendors sell more shirts, or banks earn more interest.
ThoughtWorks does do a lot of meaningful work, and I&rsquo;m going to do something I find more fulfilling. Another
stint in India doing ThoughtWorks University would be something that would satisfying this need.</p>

<p>Being a competent developer, I think I owe it to society to do what I can for a greater good. So I&rsquo;m looking at
contributing to <a href="http://www.mailpile.is/">MailPile</a> as a first step. The open government space is something I would like to explore as
well.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I think 2013 was a bit of a downer because of what&rsquo;s been revealed by <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/interactive/2013/nov/01/snowden-nsa-files-surveillance-revelations-decoded#section/1">Edward Snowden</a>. The numerous large scale
<a href="http://thinkprogress.org/security/2013/12/31/3108661/10-biggest-privacy-security-breaches-rocked-2013/">theft of e-mail addresses and passwords</a> have also lowered confidence in IT as a whole. Let&rsquo;s not talk about <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/10/20/4859316/healthcare-gov-woes">Obama Care</a>.
It&rsquo;s frustating to see the industry that I love so much do so much harm, and become so untrustworthy.
2014 is going to shape to be an interesting year as a result of these events.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - Vim]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-vim/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-03T19:31:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>First Off &ndash; Introducing Valuable Links</h2>

<p>Today I&rsquo;ve decided to start something new. I tend to send my friends and colleagues
links about all sorts of things. Usually when they are pertinent to a problem they are
having, or to supplement a conversation I&rsquo;ve had with them. My usual process to reproduce
these links ends up being a search in: <a href="https://twitter.com/scottmuc/" title="My Twitter Feed">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://getpocket.com/users/scottmuc" title="My Pocket Feed">Pocket</a>, History, and my Bookmarks.</p>

<p>Also, when I share my links I tend to write a few sentences about them. It adds a personal
touch and a bit of context, so that&rsquo;s why I&rsquo;m exploring this channel for displaying them.
As opposed to using a bookmarking website.</p>

<h2>Valuable Links for Vim</h2>

<p>I would say I&rsquo;m a moderate <a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a> user. I have a simple <code>.vimrc</code> with few plugins. Learning
to be competent at <code>vim</code> has made my computing experience so much better. Here are a few
websites that have helped me out:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.danielmiessler.com/study/vim/" title="Daniel Miessler's Vim Primer">Vim Primer</a> &ndash; I can&rsquo;t think of a more thorough primer. Even after knowing
vim for a while I learned a lot from this article. Not only that, it helped reinforce
the things I knew already to better explain them.</li>
<li><a href="http://statico.github.io/vim.html" title="Vim After 11 Years">Vim After 11 Years</a> &ndash; A good story on someone&rsquo;s journey learning
vim for the last 11 years.</li>
<li><a href="http://vimgolf.com/" title="Vim Golf">Vim Golf</a> &ndash; Try and do the editing exercises in the minimum number of keystrokes.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/" title="Destroy All Software">Destroy All Software</a> &ndash; Watching <a href="https://twitter.com/garybernhardt" title="Gary's Twitter Feed">Gary Bernhardt</a> is a great
way to learn vim. His excellent screencasts have 3 episodes focused on Vim:
<a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts/catalog/file-navigation-in-vim" title="File Navigation in Vim">File Navigation in Vim</a>, <a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts/catalog/some-vim-tips" title="Some Vim Tips">Some Vim Tips</a>, and
<a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts/catalog/the-vimrc" title="The vimrc">The vimrc</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h3>My Own Tips</h3>

<ul>
<li>Disable the arrow keys. They just encourage bad habits. For me, I had to use the
<code>h</code>, <code>j</code>, <code>l</code>, and <code>l</code> out of necessity. I travel a lot, and writing code on an
airplane is difficult if you have to move your hand to the arrow keys. The key is
not to do this too early otherwise you&rsquo;ll be frustrated like <a href="http://yehudakatz.com/2010/07/29/everyone-who-tried-to-convince-me-to-use-vim-was-wrong/">Yehuda Katz</a>.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t use a premade vim configuration. Things like <a href="https://github.com/carlhuda/janus" title="Janus">Janus</a> make it easy
for vim to behave more like <a href="http://macromates.com/" title="TextMate">TextMate</a> or <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/" title="Sublime Editor">Sublime</a> (both great
editors), but if that&rsquo;s what you want, why not just use them? Instead, strive to
keep your <code>.vimrc</code> your own and rely on plugins to get the benefits of the excellent
work that&rsquo;s been done by other people. <a href="http://blog.clifreeder.com/blog/2012/07/08/leaving-janus-for-vim/" title="Leaving Janus">Clif Reeder</a> articulates when
to leave Janus quite well.</li>
<li>Keep it simple! The more you stray from default, the more dependant you are on
your own configuration. Use plugins in order to extend functionality. If you can&rsquo;t
explain every line of your own <code>.vimrc</code> then either figure it out, or remove it.</li>
<li>As you grow more comfortable, start using vim everywhere. If you use <strong>gmail</strong>, turn
on the keyboard shortcuts (some of them are vim like). If you&rsquo;re using Chrome,
install <a href="http://vimium.github.io/">Vimium</a>. It allows you to navigate the browser
as if it&rsquo;s vim. There&rsquo;s even
<a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/59ca71b3-a4a3-46ca-8fe1-0e90e3f79329">VsVim</a>
for Visual Studio users!</li>
</ul>


<p>Admittedly, I still have a lot to learn. I&rsquo;m by no means an expert.</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong> &ndash; I&rsquo;m a &ldquo;learn it the hard way&rdquo; type of person. So that may explain
my thoughts on the subject.</p>

<p>Hope you enjoyed the first of what could be many &ldquo;valuable links&rdquo; posts.</p>

<h3>Addendum</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://dougblack.io/words/a-good-vimrc.html">A Good Vimrc</a></li>
<li><a href="http://nvie.com/posts/how-i-boosted-my-vim/">How I Boosted My Vim</a></li>
<li><a href="http://stevelosh.com/blog/2010/09/coming-home-to-vim/">Coming Home to Vim</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
