<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-05T16:35:48+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prague, Budapest, and the Hungarian Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T14:23:50+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 22nd &ndash; July 29th</em></p>

<h3>Prague</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>Next portion of the trip is to Eastern Europe! I had a nice simple itinerary to Prague: <strong>Heidelberg &ndash;> Munich &ndash;> Prague</strong>.
Unfortunately something was going on with the brakes on the train and I missed my train in Munich so it
turned into: <strong>Heidelberg &ndash;> Munich &ndash;> Neurberg &ndash;> Cheb &ndash;> Prague</strong>. By now I&rsquo;m a seasoned itinerary refactorer so this
didn&rsquo;t phase me. These little <em>adjustments of the universe</em> can sometimes end up with interesting things happening. At
the Plzen stop, a woman sat across from me in the couchette. She started speaking to me in Czech and my response was the
standard Canadian response: I&rsquo;m sorry?</p>

<br />


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry?&rdquo; or &ldquo;sowry&rdquo; in the short form is Canadian for: I apologize that I don&rsquo;t speak your language and I&rsquo;m embarassed to
ask you to repeat yourself in English because I&rsquo;ve never had to deal with speaking and understanding multiple languages. Of course
I&rsquo;m also making the assumption that you can speak English because a world without English is just unfathomable. Again,
I&rsquo;m sorry</p></blockquote>

<p>Then in English she said I looked Czech and was just inquiring about the train. Turns out
she spoke excellent English, lives in San Diego and was just in the country to visit her family. Eventually we
started chit chatting and the conversation about my trip became the focus of interest. I had fun demoing her the <a href="http://scottmuc.com/twinery/independent-accord.html">cargo ship tour</a>
and got some usability feedback as a result. Next thing I knew we were in Prague. Even with my limited
social ability to pick up on body language, I think she was flirting with me! In my usual fashion I dropped the ball. We
parted ways with a handshake and me wishing her a pleasant visit with her family.</p>

<p>After hitting my head against a wall for what seemed like a decade, I continued on to a rendezvous point in the
train station where I was to meet up with <a href="https://twitter.com/nohwnd">Jakub Jareš</a>. He&rsquo;s a core contributor to <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester">Pester</a>,
who in the last 6 months, has taken pretty much all the maintenance burden off of my shoulders. He offered to take me out for beers and I obviously
couldn&rsquo;t resist an offer like that. It was the rainiest day of the summer and he guided me to the <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2094840">airbnb</a>
where I was to stay for the next couple days. Then we proceeded to a <a href="http://www.pivovarskyklub.com/">bar</a> (and got soaked in the process). We enjoyed many beers,
discussed much about software development, and my ineptness with the woman on the train was soon forgotten.</p>

<p>Sandeman operates in Prague too so I did a couple tours:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague-castle.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague-castle.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/daily-tours/new-prague-free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: I can&rsquo;t really talk about this tour without talking about the guide. <a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/our-guides/pavel.html">Pavel</a>
was quite the character. He had an entertaining dry wit and personalized the tour with stories of his own family. I
was blown away when he said is grandmother has lived in the same flat her whole life and has lived in 9 different
countries as a result. It was a good reminder on the craziness humans have to deal with all the time.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/daily-tours/prague-castle-tour.html">Castle Tour</a>: Fortunately, Pavel was the guide for this tour too! He sort of stumbled over a
little late and asked the group if we could deviate from the standard tour itinerary and visit a
<a href="http://europeupclose.com/article/st-norberts-brewery-in-prague/">monastery</a> where some award winning beer is brewed. No one was opposed and I got to have a fantastic
beer at the beginning of the tour. The castle was very different than other castles I&rsquo;ve seen. The distictive
feature was the cathedral but the surrounding buildings were much different. At the end of the tour, I really
enjoyed walking through the <a href="http://www.hrad.cz/en/prague-castle/guidepost-for-visitors/gardens-of-the-prague-castle.shtml#a5">garden around the ramparts</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Overall, I really enjoyed Prague. You really need to avoid the square as much as possible. Once out of the tourist area,
everything is quite afforable and less hectic. Even though my stay was short, I felt that I got the most out of it. I
would like to go back and explore further and do some hacking with Jakub though.</p>

<h3>Arriving in Budapest</h3>

<p>My stay was short in Prague because I had to get to Budapest for the last of my Grand Prix adventure. Fortunately it was
a direct train! The <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/1767274">airbnb</a> was close to the station and was able to take the metro there. I was really happy with the
location, and the host was exceptional in responding to my queries. One interesting thing about taking the train around
Europe is that you start to see patterns in the train stations from different countries. There was quite a difference
between the stations in Czech Republic and Slovakia compared to Germany and Hungary. Now I want to create an archive of
train stations so I can do more comparing and contrasting.</p>

<h3>Hungarian Grand Prix</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-bags.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-bags.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>Getting to the race track was a fairly painless experience in Budapest. The transit workers were also extremely helpful
and knowledgable about the logistics of the race. The track was located in a beautiful area just outside Budapest. I
spent the Friday walking around the track (in 35C weather). The track area was super clean and I think that&rsquo;s owed to
the fact that bright blue garbage bags were never more than 20ft away from you. Overall, I would say this Grand Prix had
the most pleasant logistics experience. More importantly though, this was an <a href="http://www.autoblog.com/2014/07/28/race-recap-2014-hungarian-grand-prix-a-thrilling-wet-mess/">incredible race</a>! A cloud burst occured
around 60 minutes before the race began. All the drivers had to change their strategies and start with wet tyres. Then
an accident occured a few laps in that caused some pit lane confusion resulting in the leaders being in the middle of
the pack. Nearly every lap had battles going on from all positions. I think this ranks up there as one of the best races
of the year (Bahrain was pretty close). I&rsquo;m sort of sad that my stream of F1 races is over, but also happy because now
the rest of my time is entirely unscheduled. Who knows, maybe I&rsquo;ll do a quick detour to Belgium and go to the race there
at the end of the month.</p>

<br />


<br />


<h3>Dream Theater in Budapest</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dream-theater.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dream-theater.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>As a bonus I saw posters stating that <a href="http://www.dreamtheater.net/">Dream Theater</a> is playing nearby! I&rsquo;ve been a fan of them since 1998 and have never
seen them live! Everything looked too perfect: the venue was a beautiful tram ride away, it starts after the majority of
the F1 events are done, it ended at a decent hour so I could be rested for race day, and tickets were still available!
After freshening up after another hot day at the track I walk to the tram and arrive at the venue around an hour before
the show starts. I was in line to grab some food when the woman next to me asks me a question in Hungarian. Here we go
again! I respond with &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry?&rdquo;. She switches to English and asks if I was
ahead of her. I had no idea, and it didn&rsquo;t really matter to me so I said she was first. As I get my food, she asks where
I&rsquo;m from. I tell her I&rsquo;m going to find some beer and she offers to show me where I can sample some
proper Hungarian liquor. I follow her lead and she orders me palinka which is a fruit brandy. Fortunately I&rsquo;m well
adapted to plum whiskey from hazy memories of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G7Eb7a8-LvQ">ThoughtBoarder</a> trips (thanks <a href="http://www.yycapps.com/2012/09/developer-interview-radu-muresan/">Radu</a>), so the shot goes down easy. She says
she needs to bring the food back to her group and I bid farewell and find a spot in the crowd to watch the show. Ten or
fifteen minutes pass and she finds me in the crowd. We continue to chat about music, travel and Hungary. It turns out
that her dad brought her to the concert (coolest dad in the world!), and she asked if it was ok to hang out with me
during the show (you had to ask?!). You would think that I would have learned my lesson from my previous female
encounter&hellip; nope. Though I did do a bit better. I wrote down my website and she asked if she could find me on Facebook
(I wasn&rsquo;t sure if my profile was searchable, but I said yes). The show was fantastic and made better by having her company.
I got a message from her a few days later and we&rsquo;re still corresponding! Clearly something supernatural was going on as
you can tell from this image of the show.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-view.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-view.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>The weather following the race was not so good. I managed to explore a little bit around the vicinity of where I was
staying, but spent most of the time catching up with Coursera. Sandeman did not have any presence in Budapest so I took
a free tour by another organization. I can&rsquo;t say it was up to the same standard, but it was still informative
nevertheless. It ended near the castle and I enjoyed a relatively rain free walk back to my flat and prepared for my
next destination, Rome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glasgow, Berlin, Heidelberg and the German Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/glasgow-berlin-heidelberg-and-the-german-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-21T14:44:37+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/glasgow-berlin-heidelberg-and-the-german-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 7th &ndash; July 21st</em></p>

<h3>Reunions in Glasgow</h3>

<p>Since my train didn&rsquo;t leave until after noon, I decided to go back to Bletchley Park and spend the
morning there. It was so nice to just spend some idle time in the park and not hurry through the
exhibits. Unrushed, I made my way to the train station for a direct train to Glasgow.
Upon arrival at the station I was greeted by Derek and <a href="http://adidav9.blogspot.cz/">Rose</a> who I know from back in the Calgary
days. They&rsquo;ve been super generous and hosting me at their apartment which is close to the train station.
It was fun to look back at the tough project we worked on together and look at the experience with
fondness and nostalgia. Rose was my concert buddy and Derek was probably the only person I know
that likes <a href="http://www.sundance.tv/series/greenporno">Green Porno</a> as much as I do.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/glasgow-necropolis.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/glasgow-necropolis.small.jpg" width="300"></a> During my first
day I wandered around the city center and then went up to the <a href="http://www.glasgownecropolis.org/">Necropolis</a>. It was
a beautiful place and had a view over the city. Had I been more prepared I would have spent more time
there in search of graves of noteworthy people. On my walk back to the apartment I saw an e-mail from
the company that chartered my cargo ship cruise. Apparently BBC&rsquo;s Travel Show was looking for people
to interview! I got in touch with someone from the BBC, and was scheduled for an interview the next
day.</p>

<p>The next day I spent the morning doing laundry, and then walked over to the BBC for the interview (<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p0232gkn">the clip is online now</a>).
The camera man was a really cool dude named James Allen. He said he enjoyed the interview
because it was a break from more monotonous stuff he was doing earlier in the day (filming people cooking). Of course
I had to talk about my CBC experience with him and he revealed that he&rsquo;s in a band! They are called
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cJIndPO4OqE">Mummy Short Arms</a>, which is so fitting given the pun I posted on Facebook the day before! After the
interview and lots of walking, I met up with a bunch of ThoughtWorkers for dinner. It became very
clear to me that evening that I miss ThoughtWorkers a lot, but ThoughtWorks not as much.</p>

<h3>Edinburgh</h3>

<p>My last day was spent on a day trip to Edinburgh. People have always said that it&rsquo;s a beautiful city and
they are right. It was more beautiful than I expected and spent the day taking a couple tours. A big
thank you to Rose for telling me about <a href="http://www.neweuropetours.eu/">Sandeman</a> tours. I did the following:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/edinburgh-free-tour.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/edinburgh-free-tour.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newedinburghtours.com/daily-tours/new-edinburgh-free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: After this first tour, I was hooked on this style. The guides were young and
full of enthusiasm. My picture of a guided tour was of a slow moving parade of old people getting bombarded
with facts and dates. This tour group does a great job of keeping the energy up. One thing I observed was how focused
the audience got when the guide mentioned that something was a feature or inspiration for a movie, myself included.
It&rsquo;s interesting how pop culture somehow makes things more relevant to your mind.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newedinburghtours.com/daily-tours/castle-tour-edinburgh.html">Castle Tour</a>: Since I liked the free tour so much, I decided to do the castle tour. The guide
was a <a href="http://www.newedinburghtours.com/our-guides/billy.html">charismatic Scotsman</a> and told a story about the castle and Edinburgh in such a way that you could transport
yourself to that era.</li>
</ul>


<p>I was sad to leave Scotland because it&rsquo;s such a friendly place. Unfortunately it&rsquo;s also expensive,
although I guess it&rsquo;s cheaper than London, but that&rsquo;s not saying much.</p>

<h3>Berlin</h3>

<p>I had to wake up at 3:30am to begin my trip to Berlin! The interary was a bit complex: Glasgow &ndash;> London &ndash;> Brussels
&ndash;> Koln &ndash;> Berlin. Here I was going to stay with an ex-ThoughtWorker, <a href="https://twitter.com/pcalcado">Phil Calcado</a>. The interesting
thing about Phil is that I barely know him! I had a couple beers with him
the year before, but he happily hosted me in his awesome flat for several days. I eventually made it to
his place at around 11:00pm (I didn&rsquo;t quite navigate the Berlin metro optimally that evening). There
was a little <a href="https://soundcloud.com/">SoundCloud</a> gathering going on and another ex-ThoughtWorker, <a href="https://twitter.com/tomczarniecki">Tom Czarniecki</a>, was
there too! It seems the world has ThoughtWorks affiliates everywhere.</p>

<p>It appears I timed things well as I got to be in Germany for the world cup final! Myself and Phil went
down to <a href="http://www.pratergarten.de/d/">Prater Biergarten</a>. Tom joined us a bit later. Then for some odd reason, I got interviewed by
a Mexican journalist. I&rsquo;m not making it up, because Phil and Tom will vouch for me. The whole city turned
into a party and we stayed out til around 4:00am. I still can&rsquo;t get the Uber Deuchstland song out of my head.</p>

<p>Like in Edinburgh, Sandeman does tours in Berlin. I did these three:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/potsdam-tour.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/potsdam-tour.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newberlintours.com/daily-tours/free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: Like in Edinburgh, the guide was passionate and energetic. It was fascinating to
see the Jewish memorial, and place related to the war.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newberlintours.com/daily-tours/potsdam-city-of-emperors.html">Potsdam</a>: I was craving something different and this tour looked to offer that. I got the same
guide as the day before. I didn&rsquo;t know a single thing about the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prussia">Prussian empire</a> before and this tour made me start
reading tons of Wikipedia articles about it. My favourite part of this tour was wandering the gardens created by
emperors, especially <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sanssouci_Park">Sanssouci Park</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newberlintours.com/daily-tours/sachsenhausen-memorial.html">Sauchsenhausen</a>: I wasn&rsquo;t sure what to expect in a tour of a concentration camp. The
guide impressed me by how he approached the subject matter. I&rsquo;m glad I saw the camp, even
though it can&rsquo;t really be described as a pleasant tour. It&rsquo;s a reminder that normal people can do terrible things.</li>
</ul>


<p>Before I left I had one more evening of beers with yet another <a href="https://twitter.com/dtemme">ex-ThoughtWorker</a>, Daniel Temme!</p>

<h3>Heidelberg</h3>

<p>Travel from Berlin to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heidelberg">Heidelberg</a> was a direct train. I made my way to my <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2337045">airbnb</a>
and got settled for spending some time in this beautiful town. I purposely planned to have a free day before the F1. I wandered throughout
the old town and the castle. My favourite thing about this part of the trip are the picnics I had; the top one being
on a bench in Philospher&rsquo;s Way. The weather was so hot that I didn&rsquo;t really want to stay inside a restaurant, nor a
patio. It was really nice to simply purchase some groceries and wander around looking for a nice spot in the town to
eat.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-bridge.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-bridge.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-philosophersweg.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-philosophersweg.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-castle.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-castle.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<h3>German Grand Prix</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hockenheim-podium.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hockenheim-podium.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
Getting to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hockenheim">Hockenheim</a> was pretty straighforward. There&rsquo;s a bus from the train station, or I can take a
train with a single connection in Manheim. The race weekend was super hot with the air temperature around
35C and they said the track temperature was around 55C! I need to learn what exactly track temperature
means, but I&rsquo;m guessing it&rsquo;s how hot it is in you&rsquo;re sitting in the sun.</p>

<p>So far this race is where I&rsquo;ve had the best seats. I was amazing to actually see the cars start the race
and watch them go through the first turn. It was scary to see Massa&rsquo;s car flip during the start of the race but
was relieved to see him walk out of the car. The picture here is a first for me; I actually made it to the podium area for
the awards ceremony!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belgium, France, London and the British Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-08T14:42:19+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>June 24th &ndash; July 7th</em></p>

<h3>Shipment Delivered</h3>

<p>Upon arrival in Antwerp I saw my taxi from the deck. I had all my belongings ready and made my way down
to the port. The ship crew was busy with the offloading of containers so I decided it probably wasn’t a good idea
to disturb them to say farewell. It was a long drive to the immigration office, and there I found out that I needed
a passenger manifest to get the stamp of approval. This meant going all the way back to the ship and back. This
added around an extra hour of taxi travel. The chief mate was ready for my return as he had the document in his
hand. After that confusion, I made it to central Antwerp and found a hotel near the train station.</p>

<p>Antwerp is a fairly small city. The port area takes up more space than the actual city. After a quick nap I wandered
around old Antwerp and in the evening found a little pub. I ended up having more drinks than necessary with a couple
that were a lot of fun. The lady has been in the shipping industry and even knew the ship that I came in on!</p>

<h3>In Bruges</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/bruges.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/bruges.small.jpg" width="300"></a> The trip
from Antwerp to Bruges was pretty easy. As was finding the <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/2176619">residence</a> I was going to stay in. The house was
just outside the old town so after getting some travel logistics out of the way I set out to do a walking tour.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bruges">Bruges</a> is one of the prettiest towns I’ve ever seen. It’s like a snapshot
in time of Belgium several hundred years ago.  In some spots it was insanely crowded, but in other spots it
was quiet and peaceful, which made me stick to those areas. When I got back, I met Lander, the
host of the house. He was very personable and enjoyed conversing with him about my travels.</p>

<p>The next day I did another self guided walking tour. My favourite moment was just relaxing having a couple beers at the
<a href="http://fr.yelp.be/biz/caf%C3%A9-vlissinghe-brugge">oldest tavern</a> in Bruges. After a full day in the town I went back to the house where Lander invited some friends over for
the game. We then headed out to watch the Belgium game in the town square. It was so much fun! I lost the group for a
bit so I gave my round of beers to some random strangers in the crowd. That seemed to make people happy. Next thing I
know it&rsquo;s 5:00am and I&rsquo;m chatting away with a fellow drunk.</p>

<p>These are the beers I had in Belgium:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.dekoninck.be/en">De Koninck</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.boon.be/en/our-beers/geuze-boon-old-style">Gueze Boon</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.rodenbach.be/">Rodenbach</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.trappistwestmalle.be/en/page/dubbel.aspx">Westmalle Trappist Dubbel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.duvel.com/en-us">Duvel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.orval.be/en/58/How-Orval-beer-is-made">Orval</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.abbaye-de-leffe.be/the_beer/en_5_varieties_of_beer_article200.html">Leffe Dark</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/index.php?id=15&amp;L=2">Brugse Zot</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bestbelgianspecialbeers.be/main_eng.html">Tripel Karmeliet</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/index.php?id=14&amp;L=2">Straffe Hendrik</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.achouffe.be/en/beers#la-chouffe">La Chouffe</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Of all of these, I would say the <strong>Tripel Karmeliet</strong> and <strong>Orval</strong> were my favourites. There are so many beers to try
that I really want to come back and spend several weeks sampling all the wonderful beers. There&rsquo;s something about
a country where the monks participate in the brewing process. The day before I got to Bruges, the <a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/">De Halve Maan</a>
had a priest come in and bless their new brewing equipment!</p>

<h3>Dieppe Thoughts</h3>

<p>The next leg of my trip is to Dieppe, France. Unfortunately I woke up hungover and slept through my alarm. This meant
I missed my train which had the best connections to Dieppe. Armed with the
<a href="http://www.eurail.com/plan-your-trip/rail-planner-app">Eurail app</a>, I tried to make a new itinerary.
Due to my decisions of last night, I slept through my connection and passed Brussels. Turned out it didn’t really matter
because at the following station I learned it was the first day of holidays in France and all reservation trains were booked.
Using the app, I figured out an itinerary that could get me to Dieppe without reserved seating. One of the trains was delayed
and I just made my only connecting train with only a minute to spare. Last part of the journey was the walk to to where
I <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/1157655">stayed</a>. The only issue was that I forgot to cache the map, but at least I had a star showing where it
was and functional gps.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dieppe.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dieppe.small.jpg" width="300"></a> My primary motivation
for visiting Dieppe was to see the beaches the Canadian troops attempted to invade in WWII. The
invasion of Dieppe preceded D-Day and was used as an information gathering invasion. Essentially they learned a lot at
the expenses of thousands of lives. I’m not a patriotic person, but I couldn’t help but feel moved by the lives that were lost
there. You can read more at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dieppe_Raid">Wikipedia</a> (notice that my picture of the beach
is very close to the image in Wikipedia!</p>

<p>After my walk about, I walked some more! I headed down to where all the restaurants were and had a nice meal and then
proceeded to hang around the beach area to catch the sunset. It was definitely worth it.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dieppe-sunset.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dieppe-sunset.medium.jpg" width="1024"></a></p>

<h3>A Boat Time</h3>

<p>At 3:30am I left the residence and walked to the ferry terminal. Luckily I walked there the day before so I knew how long
it would take, and that I had to be there at 4:30am. I wasn’t initially planning on being there that early so I’m glad I did
my exploratory research. The ferry was pleasant, but spent the majority of the journey falling asleep and hitting my head against the window.</p>

<h3>London Calling</h3>

<p>The ferry arrived in Newhaven on time. I had a nice chat with the immigration officer who supported my goal of seeing
all the Formula 1 races. I got my luggage and took a series of trains to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hitchin">Hitchin</a> where
I met up with <a href="https://twitter.com/zoodor">Mark</a>, a old ThoughtWorks colleague. It was quite refreshing to see a familiar face!</p>

<p>My next few days were lunch and dinner plans with people I know in London. I got a chance to talk about where my mind
is at regarding my future. It was also nice to see more familiar faces. I really like London, but all the tubing around I was
doing unfortunately left me with a cold before I left.</p>

<h3>Milton Keynes</h3>

<p>This was to be my face for the first F1 on my trip. My <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/1433999">hosts</a> picked up from the
train station. They were amazing hosts and were very pleasant to talk to. I had a lot of fun talking shop
with them as they run an <a href="http://evidencetalks.com/en/">IT business</a> in the city centre.
Their <a href="http://mxcl.github.io/">son</a> is also note-worthy as he created <a href="http://brew.sh/">Homebrew</a>!</p>

<p>The city of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milton_Keynes">Milton Keynes</a> was interesting because it was a planned city.
It was easy to get around, there were plenty of trails that made walking around the periphery quite pleasant.</p>

<h3>This Place is the Bombe!</h3>

<p>I planned for a free day before the race so I could visit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bletchley_Park">Bletchley Park</a>.
It was such an amazing experience to see where
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing">Alan Turing</a> worked and observing a working Colossus, WITCH, and
Bombe machines (in the <a href="http://www.tnmoc.org/">National Museum of Computing</a>)! While visiting the grounds it made
me think about NSA’s involvement in security. If the NSA had a facility that celebrated its ability to crack codes, I don’t think
people would have the same feeling. WWII was great a creating a binary view of activities. Bletchley Park was also
dismantled after the war. I guess things were simpler and less ambiguous then.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what the Colossus sounds like! I wish I recorded a lot more audio because I can hear a song wanting to come out.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no"
src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/157140660&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;visual=true"></iframe>


<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h3>Race 1 of 3</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/british-gp.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/british-gp.small.jpg"></a> The commute to the
track was quite reasonable, but Friday was a bit much for me as I was in the worst part of my cold.
Saturday had the most comfortable weather and I spent a lot of time at the track enjoying different vantage points. Race
day was a big spectacle as it was the 50th race at Silverstone. Before the race there was an air display by the Red Arrows.
It was far better than I had expected. Afterwards I went up to me seat and watched a great race. Lots of drama on the first
lap as Raikonnen had an accident. This red flagged the race as they had to repair a barrier on the track. The rest of the
race was rather uneventful, but the battle between Alonso and Vettel (below) was a show of great driver talent. It was
a shame Roseberg had a malfunction because the battle for 1st could have been just as great.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="640" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/jyhz5c0mR4c" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h3>To Glasgow</h3>

<p>The journey continues to Glasgow, Scotland! The write up for that will have to wait though as this post is long
enough. I was going to write about my learnings over the last few weeks, but will hold that thought for a bit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossing the Atlantic via Container Ship]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/crossing-the-atlantic-via-container-ship/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-24T06:02:51+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/crossing-the-atlantic-via-container-ship</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned in my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america/">last post</a>, I finished the crossing of the Atlantic ocean via container ship. It was a great
experiene that I&rsquo;ll happily do again. 11 days wasn&rsquo;t enough, and would be happy to spend a month next time around.</p>

<h3>Too Much Twine on my Hands</h3>

<p>A blog post probably wouldn&rsquo;t due the experience justice so I decided to play around with a basic word game engine to
give you a more <a href="http://scottmuc.com/twinery/independent-accord.html">self-directed tour</a>. Hope you enjoy it!</p>

<p>Working with <a href="http://twinery.org/">Twine</a> was quite enjoyable and I could see myself using it a lot in many different lines of work. If I was
still consulting, it would become a prominent tool in my tool-belt. My biggest complaint with it is that the
documentation is all online so I couldn&rsquo;t figure out how to do anything more sophisticated than what I created.</p>

<h3>Man Over-bored</h3>

<p>Honestly, that header was just for the pun factor. What amazed me about the voyage was how quick it went by. I didn&rsquo;t
think <strong>once</strong> that I wanted it to end and that I was bored. I savoured not being in a rush to do anything. The only structure to my
days revolved around meals which were at: 07:30, 12:30, and 17:30. That set my rythym for the 11 days.</p>

<h3>Crew Man Group</h3>

<p>The ship was run by a crew of 21, all male. The captain was Romanian and the rest of the officers were Croation. The chief
engineer was Ukrainian and the rest were Filipino. Everyone was very nice, but when asked for their name, they simply
asked to be addressed by their position (Third, Chief, etc&hellip;).</p>

<h3>Retrospective</h3>

<p><strong>What Went Well</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Scotch &ndash; Sipping 18yo Glenlivet was a wonderful way to be even <em>more</em> relaxed</li>
<li>Jambox &ndash; This dependable gadget has been filling rooms with tunes well for several years now</li>
<li>Offline Wikipedia &ndash; Wow! I cannot believe how much I perused Wikipedia while I was on this trip.</li>
<li>11 days of no expenses &ndash; Being disconnected is a good way to not spend money.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Not So Well</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Gym clothes &ndash; There&rsquo;s an exercise room with a stationary bike. I wasn&rsquo;t always allowed on the main deck (to do laps
around the ship) so being able to do 30min of hard cardio would have been good to stave off the belly I grew.</li>
<li>Scotch &ndash; One bottle was definitely not enough.</li>
<li>Offline map &ndash; I would have liked to better explorer the route and plan the rest of my trip better.</li>
<li>Making Twine tour at the last minute &ndash; I wish I had a skeleton of it done much earlier so I could get more details
from the crew.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Action Items</strong>: I&rsquo;ll definitely do this again and I&rsquo;ll be sure to come with a fitness plan. Though that directly opposes the action to
bring more liquor.</p>

<h3>Offline By Default</h3>

<p>Being disconnected from the world for 11 days was a far better experience than I had expected. It&rsquo;s made me realize I
need to create a habit of disconnecting. It brought me back to the era when your computer was offline by default, and
you had to explicitly connect to see what&rsquo;s going on in the rest of the Internet universe. This experience has showed me
that I like that. It may sound backwards to a lot of people, but the computer has always been a tool, not an
entertainment device (gaming being the exception). My phone may eventually be the only always-connected device, but even
then, I turn off all notifications and keep it silent.</p>

<h3>Let the Eurotrip Begin</h3>

<p>After a 140 euro ride through immigration and into Antwerp, I can begin the next phase of my journey!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaving Vancouver and North America]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-13T15:10:36+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After another relaxing two weeks in Vancouver (and attending <a href="http://www.sasquatchfestival.com/">Sasquatch</a>), it&rsquo;s time to leave. Here&rsquo;s the
last sunset I watched from the beach. If you can believe it, the weather in Vancouver was 99% rain free!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/kits-sunset.jpg"></p>

<h3>Schools Out for Summer</h3>

<p>During my downtime I&rsquo;ve enrolled in the <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/money">Economics of Banking and Money</a> on <a href="https://www.coursera.org">Coursera</a>. I never
thought I would find learning this stuff so much fun! To supplement the course material, I&rsquo;ve been listening to the
following podcasts too:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/">Planet Money</a></li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/radio/">Freakanomics Radio</a></li>
</ul>


<p>This is the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course">MOOC</a> I&rsquo;ve taken and I really enjoy the format. It could be the fact that I&rsquo;m older and have
already been established in a career for a while that my approach to learning is different. School always seemed to be
about grades to me growing up. With this course, I&rsquo;m more focused on learning and developing an intuition for the
subject.</p>

<p>From this course I&rsquo;ve learned that the banking and money system is a lot more complicated than I thought. I also now
feel that the system itself isn&rsquo;t altogether evil, it&rsquo;s just trying to facilitate trade the best that it can. I&rsquo;m still
not confident in my ability to summarize what I&rsquo;ve learnt so far, but I think I&rsquo;m going to come out of this much more
empowered.</p>

<h3>Ship Happens</h3>

<p>Today I finally start my voyage on a container ship! You can track where I am on this <a href="http://www.marinetraffic.com/ais/details/ships/636091353/vessel:INDEPENDENT_ACCORD">Facebook for ships</a>
website. If you search for the name &ldquo;Independent Accord&rdquo; in your favourite online search website
you&rsquo;ll see there are dozens of websites that have databases of ships. The websites are pretty well done too. I had no
idea this shipping world can be so interesting. I&rsquo;m sure the captain and crew are going to be sick of my questions over
the next 11 days.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested, <a href="http://www.cruisepeople.co.uk/">here&rsquo;s</a> that I booked my travel through. If you&rsquo;re nostalgic for the 90&rsquo;s you&rsquo;ll
enjoy it a lot.</p>

<h3>Map Reduce</h3>

<p>Since I have all this time on my hands, I&rsquo;ve started journalling the places that I&rsquo;m staying (and coffee shops I leech
Internet off of) in this <a href="https://mapsengine.google.com/map/edit?mid=znoHAqfzfPKU.k2lUp8fKHDCg">online map</a>. It&rsquo;s work in progress and will be fleshed out more as I go.</p>

<h3>Back to Life, Back to Reality</h3>

<p>One question I&rsquo;ve been getting asked frequently is &ldquo;when are you coming back to reality?&rdquo;. I find it an odd question.
This is reality. There&rsquo;s nothing to get back to (unless I could travel in time). Sure, I&rsquo;ll be figuring out what to do
work wise. Not sure how that&rsquo;s coming &ldquo;back&rdquo; to reality though. I think we&rsquo;re living in an era where social norms are
shifting all over the place. Hopes and aspirations appear to be more varied than before. One persons normality is
another persons exceptionality. So when I hear this question my interpretation is &ldquo;when are you coming back to the
lifestyle of yours that I consider normal?&rdquo;.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m starting to feel the career break settling in. I&rsquo;ve slowed things down a lot. My favourite thing to do now is leave
my phone behind and go for a wander. Writing blog posts like this is much more fulfilling than a series of micro-blogs
(aka tweets) that lack context, albeit they are more timely.</p>

<p>See you on the other side!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing Powershell Code That Talks to CLR Objects]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/testing-powershell-code-that-talks-to-clr-objects/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-06T02:39:41+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/testing-powershell-code-that-talks-to-clr-objects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several months ago someone posted an excellent question on the <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/pester/Y8UzSiNlcSE">Pester Group</a> about a certain problem area
in testing PowerShell with <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester">Pester</a>.  He brings up a relevant example of the difficulties that can occur when writing tests
is done afterwards. It also reveals a missing feature of Pester.</p>

<p>First let me display the code that needed tests:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/e5abe37881628f13cd0a.js?file=Get-FromSFtp.ps1'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>Add-Type -Path (Join-Path -Path $psScriptRoot &quot;Renci.SshNet.dll&quot;)

function Get-FromSFtp {
    $fileList=$null
    try {
        $sftp=New-Object Renci.SshNet.SftpClient(&quot;127.0.0.1&quot;,&quot;test&quot;,&quot;test&quot;)
        $sftp.Connect()
        if($sftp.IsConnected) {
            $sftp.ChangeDirectory(&quot;/test&quot;)
            $fileList=$sftp.ListDirectory(&quot;.&quot;)
        }
        return $fileList
    } catch [Exception] {
        Write-Host $_.Exception.ToString()
    } finally {
        if(($sftp -ne $null) -and ($sftp.IsConnected)) {
            $sftp.Disconnect()
        }
    }
}
</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>Here are a couple reasons why this code is difficult to test:</p>

<ul>
<li>Line 4 returns a CLR object that actually does SFTP</li>
<li>Many parameters are hard coded</li>
</ul>


<h3>Start With Integration</h3>

<p>I started this exercise with the intention of not changing a single character of the code submitted. Here&rsquo;s the story of
how the changes took place (I had a git repo of this, but the files got corrupted). First thing to do was to make the
existing code pass a test as is. In order to do that, I needed an integration environment for it to talk to. So I used
<a href="http://www.vagrantup.com/">Vagrant</a> to spin up a local linux box. I manually configured the box such that the credentials in the code
work. Here&rsquo;s the Vagrantfile</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/e5abe37881628f13cd0a.js?file=Vagrantfile'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># -*- mode: ruby -*-
# vi: set ft=ruby :

# Vagrantfile API/syntax version. Don&#39;t touch unless you know what you&#39;re doing!
VAGRANTFILE_API_VERSION = &quot;2&quot;

Vagrant.configure(VAGRANTFILE_API_VERSION) do |config|
  config.vm.box = &quot;precise64&quot;
  config.vm.box_url = &quot;http://files.vagrantup.com/precise64.box&quot;
  config.vm.network &quot;forwarded_port&quot;, guest: 22, host: 22
end
</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>and here&rsquo;s the passing test. I&rsquo;m happy with it because I could change the code or the environment and cause the test to
fail, thus giving me confidence that the test is good enough to tell if me I broke anything.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="n">Describe</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Get-FromSFtp Integration&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;returns the 2 default dir entries&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">Get-FromSFtp</span> <span class="p">|</span> <span class="k">ForEach</span><span class="n">-Object</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nv">$_</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Name</span> <span class="p">}</span> <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Be</span> <span class="s2">&quot;.&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;..&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Happy that I have a feedback loop going now, I begin to start testing the code in isolation. I start by writing the
contexts and specifications:</p>

<h3>Follow Up With Isolated Tests</h3>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="n">Describe</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Get-FromSFtp&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">Context</span> <span class="s2">&quot;when connected&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;attempts to connect to an sftp server&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;changes to the directory /test&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;gets the contents listing of the directory&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;disconnects from the sftp server&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">Context</span> <span class="s2">&quot;when not connected&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;returns 0 files&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">Context</span> <span class="s2">&quot;when an error happens&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;prints out the error to the user&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I was stumped for a bit because I realized Pester didn&rsquo;t have the power necessary to do this easily. It didn&rsquo;t mean it
couldn&rsquo;t be tested though. The Mocking functionality came to the rescue as I was able to mock <code>New-Object</code> and decouple
my tests from the <code>Renci.SshNet</code> library. The hard part was hand-rolling the mock object to be used in the tests.</p>

<p>One by one, I made each spec pass. The beginning of each <code>Context</code> was the setup, and each <code>It</code> asserted something from
after that setup and action had been taken. The nice thing that resulted was I could break a specific piece of the
production code, and the specific test would tell me that it&rsquo;s broken at that place (eg: change the directory the
production code goes to).</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the complete test file for the code:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/e5abe37881628f13cd0a.js?file=Get-FromSFtp.Tests.ps1'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>$here = Split-Path -Parent $MyInvocation.MyCommand.Path
$sut = (Split-Path -Leaf $MyInvocation.MyCommand.Path).Replace(&quot;.Tests.&quot;, &quot;.&quot;)
. &quot;$here\$sut&quot;

$mockSFtpCode = @&quot;
public class MockSFtp {
    public bool ConnectCalled { get; private set; }
    public bool DisconnectCalled { get; private set; }
    public bool IsConnected { get; set; }
    public string ChangeDirectoryParam { get; private set; }
    public string ListDirectoryParam { get; private set; }

    public void Connect() {
        this.ConnectCalled = true;
    }

    public void Disconnect() {
        this.DisconnectCalled = true;
    }

    public void ChangeDirectory(string directory) {
        this.ChangeDirectoryParam = directory;
    }

    public string[] ListDirectory(string path) {
        this.ListDirectoryParam = path;
        return new string[] { &quot;test1&quot; };
    }
}
&quot;@

$throwingMockSFtpCode = @&quot;
public class ThrowingMockSFtp {
    public void Connect() {
        throw new System.Exception();
    }
}
&quot;@

Add-Type -TypeDefinition $mockSFtpCode
Add-Type -TypeDefinition $throwingMockSFtpCode

Describe &quot;Get-FromSFtp&quot; {
    Context &quot;when connected&quot; {
        $mockSFtp = New-Object MockSFtp
        $mockSFtp.IsConnected = $true
        Mock New-Object -MockWith { $mockSFtp }
        $files = Get-FromSFtp

        It &quot;attempts to connect to an sftp server&quot; {
            $mockSFtp.ConnectCalled | Should Be $true
        }

        It &quot;changes to the directory /test&quot; {
            $mockSFtp.ChangeDirectoryParam | Should Be &#39;/test&#39;
        }

        It &quot;gets the content listing of the directory&quot; {
            $mockSFtp.ListDirectoryParam | Should Be &#39;.&#39;
            $files | Should Be @(&quot;test1&quot;)
        }

        It &quot;disconnects from the sftp server&quot; {
            $mockSFtp.DisconnectCalled | Should Be $true
        }
    }

    Context &quot;when not connected&quot; {
        $mockSFtp = New-Object MockSFtp
        $mockSFtp.IsConnected = $false
        Mock New-Object -MockWith { $mockSFtp }
        $files = Get-FromSFtp

        It &quot;returns 0 files&quot; {
            $files | Should BeNullOrEmpty
        }
    }

    Context &quot;when an exception happens&quot; {
        $mockSFtp = New-Object ThrowingMockSFtp
        Mock New-Object -MockWith { $mockSFtp }

        It &quot;prints out the error to the user&quot; {
            # I do not think this is a good test, but until
            # mocking of Write-Host can be done, this is all
            # that we can really do.
            { Get-FromSFtp } | Should Not Throw
        }
    }
}

Describe &quot;Get-FromSFtp Integration&quot; {
    It &quot;returns the 2 default dir entries&quot; {
        Get-FromSFtp | ForEach-Object { $_.Name } | Should Be &quot;.&quot;, &quot;..&quot;
    }
}
</code></pre></noscript></div>


<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I can&rsquo;t say this is the best test code out there. I think testing PowerShell is in a different place than testing C# or
other OO languages. It seems like the best you can do is test the function logic and test the composition of it all in
an integrated way. The first refactoring change I would likely do to this function is make the connection a parameter.
That way I wouldn&rsquo;t need to mock <code>New-Object</code>, but passing a mock object is still an issue. Perhaps Pester needs a mock
object builder of some kind, though writing mocks by hand wasn&rsquo;t too difficult either. It&rsquo;s something I would expect a
testing framework to be able to do for me though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Weeks Living Off the Clock]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/two-weeks-living-off-the-clock/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-23T01:14:14+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/two-weeks-living-off-the-clock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the last two weeks I&rsquo;ve been house sitting for a friend in the beautiful area of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kitsilano">Kitsalano</a> in Vancouver. The
goal for the two weeks was to figure out the rest of my travel plans and to meet up with a lot of my friends and
acquaintances that I haven&rsquo;t seen for a while.</p>

<h3>According to Plan?</h3>

<p>The two weeks went by quickly. I mainly organized myself around other people&rsquo;s clocks. This meant meeting people for
lunch or after work the majority of the time. Since I had gaps in time between meet ups, I spent a lot of time walking
everywhere (and sometimes biking). Experiencing many modes of transportation ends up being an influence on me later on.
It was refreshing to not be the dictator of my time, albeit my intentions did dictate who to meet. So by a transitive
relationship, I was still directing my time?</p>

<h3>Natural Time Management</h3>

<p>As an experiment I decided to not turn my morning alarm clock on. I&rsquo;ve always thought of myself as a morning person and
wanted to see if that held true. What ended up happening was that I rolled out of bed around 8:30pm every morning
regardless of when I went to bed (range: 11:00pm &ndash; 1:00am). I&rsquo;m curious about whether or not work pressure (or pressure
in general) has been the cause of my normal much earlier natural wake up time.</p>

<p>Another normal time structure that I thought my body adhered to strictly was when to eat. I started to eat when I was hungry
and found that some days I only ate 1 meal, or my lunch ended up happening at 4pm. There wasn&rsquo;t any natural rhythm to my
eating times.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s interesting to start following nature&rsquo;s conventions rather than socially, and I guess structurally imposed ones.</p>

<h3>Career Ideas</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s nice when part of my &ldquo;mission&rdquo; with this career break moves forward in some dimension. During my many walks along
the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seawall_(Vancouver)">seawall</a> I&rsquo;ve listened to many episodes of <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a>. One in particular got me a little bit
inspired. The episode was about <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/charles_marohn.html">Strong Towns</a>, and revealed that I have a lot of interest in urban
development. Shortly after that, I had dinner with a colleague, and conversation with his girlfriend got me inspired
too. It turns out she works for <a href="http://www.translink.ca/">TransLink</a> and she mentioned there&rsquo;s work available for someone with my
skills. What fascinated me was my initial feeling of joy to chat with someone regarding this topic.</p>

<p>Did I mention that I&rsquo;m slowing getting addicted to <a href="http://www.positech.co.uk/democracy3/">Democracy 3</a>?</p>

<h3>Speaking of Transport</h3>

<p>Being mobile via foot, bike, bus, train, and car share has reinforced my thoughts on urban planning. Another part of my
&ldquo;mission&rdquo; is to figure out where to live. Being mobile, while having a low impact, is an opinion that has been further
strengthened while being here. The bicycle is such a wonderful piece of engineering that has changed, relatively, little
over the years. It&rsquo;s an efficient form of transport and it&rsquo;s fun. I can&rsquo;t imagine living anywhere where I wouldn&rsquo;t feel
comfortable riding a bike much of the time.</p>

<h3>Discovering the Source of My Anxiety</h3>

<p>In my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month/">previous post</a> I alluded to a sense of anxiousness that I was feeling. It dawned on me that I was spending a lot of
time coordinating what was going to be a hurried and expensive road trip across the continent. Eventually I realized
that I didn&rsquo;t have to do that trip. I&rsquo;m already going to be doing plenty of travel in the coming months. It also
occurred to me that I spent a good amount of my &ldquo;relaxing&rdquo; time trying to make this trip work. So I&rsquo;ve canceled the
road trip and am going to spend an extra two weeks in Vancouver!</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the list of reasons that convinced that this was the right decision:</p>

<ul>
<li>Not providing ample time to truly enjoy the trip</li>
<li>Not being able to spend a proper amount of time visiting each and every person</li>
<li>Going to be more expensive than the cargo ship cruise!</li>
<li>Goes against the principles of this career break which is to take things slowly and this road trip would be a dash to Wilmington, NC</li>
<li>Lessons learned from the SF road trip (I should have slowed it down)</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m not doing any of the tech related practice I&rsquo;ve wanted to do</li>
</ul>


<p>Not sure if the software analogy fits, but it felt like removing scope from an unfinished project.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>Responding to feedback is important. On my road trip to San Francisco I learned that I&rsquo;m not going slow enough during my
time off. During the last two weeks in Vancouver I learned that it&rsquo;s nice to stand still and I wasn&rsquo;t doing too much of
that. The speed of the journey and the complexity in coordinating amongst many people and locations was resulting in an
energy level overhead that was creating anxiety (and how can someone who&rsquo;s not working possibly feel anxious about
anything). Responding to this feedback by canceling the road trip made me feel like a weight was lifted off of my
shoulders.</p>

<p>Along with the negative feedback, I&rsquo;m going to explore the positive feedback my mind felt when pondering ideas around
urban planning and public transport.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I won&rsquo;t get to see a lot of people that I wanted to, but I realized the quality of the interactions is more
important than the quantity of the interactions. This touches on my principle of doing things slowly during this break.
No better way to go slow than to stand still. Queue the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dMSFqXGZ5TQ">Rush</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections of Being Unemployed and Homeless for 1 Month]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-13T04:13:53+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For some context, you may want to read my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">previous post</a> about quitting my job.</p>

<p>I am homeless and unemployed in probably the most priveleged meaning of the terms. Both states of being are choices I&rsquo;ve
explicitly made. From what I&rsquo;ve read, I&rsquo;m not really on a sabbatical, but I&rsquo;m on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Career_break">Career Break</a>, except the homeless
aspect of it is not as conventional.</p>

<p>So here are the reflections:</p>

<h3>Where Am I Sleeping Tonight</h3>

<p>On September 1st 2012 I gave up my awesome apartment in Calgary as I prepared for an assignment in India (without
really knowing where I was going after that). I changed my mailing address to my brothers place and really didn&rsquo;t feel
much had changed. I had already been travelling weekly for my work assignments since April 2011, and I picked up my life
and departed <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/a-new-beginning-or-goodbye-20-s-hello-30-s/">Vancouver to Calgary</a> in January 2010.</p>

<p>In the last month I&rsquo;ve spent 13 nights in different beds. One of those nights was part of a 30 hour trip from
Johannesburg to Vancouver, and another night was one where I lost my dignity in Vegas (ask me to show you the scar one
day). I&rsquo;ve learned there&rsquo;s a lot of overhead in figuring out where you&rsquo;re going to sleep (and I have it easy compared to
those who aren&rsquo;t homeless by choice).</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s hit me those most is the disappearance of the sense of belonging. For 8 months I &ldquo;lived&rdquo; in a Residence Inn in
Bellevue, Washington and it was as much of a home as anywhere. I belonged there, had my routine haunts, and knew where I
was going to be for weeks on end. Nowadays I&rsquo;m either imposing on friends and family, or spending too much for a
hotel&hellip; ok, and using home sharing websites which is like a hybrid of the two.</p>

<p>So I guess this break has been successful in teaching me something already. I need to find a place to live. I do like
the traveling lifestyle, but only when I have a home base.</p>

<h3>Talk Talk Talk</h3>

<p>For some reason, this first month break started off strong with lots of conversations with people in the tech industry.
Maybe I was seeking the familiar so these conversations fit in my comfort zone. I&rsquo;ve probably spoken to over 10 or so
companies and am journaling my pursuits as I go. I&rsquo;ve added a constraint on my life that I won&rsquo;t work for 6 months so
it&rsquo;s hard to not jump on what seem to be great opportunities.</p>

<h3>No Startup For Me</h3>

<p>As a technologist, I&rsquo;m passionate about open standards and infrastructure that makes the Internet work. The last thing I
would want as a startup is for my company name to be a verb (eg: Uber, Tweet). Technology like: SMTP, HTTP, HTML, DNS
aren&rsquo;t corporate brand names. I like to live in abstractions, and as a business owner, I think that&rsquo;s probably the worst
characteristic I could probably have in order to be successful.</p>

<p>In fact, I&rsquo;ve challenged myself to minimize the brands names I speak unless it&rsquo;s trully an endorsement for the brand.
Here are some of the translations I&rsquo;m attempting to do:</p>

<ul>
<li>Tweet &ndash;> microblog</li>
<li>Uber &ndash;> rideshare</li>
<li>Nexus 4 &ndash;> phone</li>
<li>Coke &ndash;> cola</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://www.marriott.com/">Marriott</a>, on the other hand, is a brand I&rsquo;m happy to publicly endorse.</p>

<p>So yeah&hellip; given that one aspect of success for a startup is something I&rsquo;m not advocating, I think it&rsquo;ll be hard for me
to be part of a startup. Though, I think this really depends on the state of the startup.</p>

<h3>I&rsquo;m Super Lucky</h3>

<p>Part of what has made this break possible is the amazing network of friends and aquaintances I&rsquo;ve made over the years. There
are couches available to me all over the world and that&rsquo;s something I feel super blessed about. I really have to thank
<a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/join">ThoughtWorks</a> for enabling me to meet people from everywhere and make these connections.</p>

<h3>A Hint of Concern</h3>

<p>You would think after 1 month of not working I would feel stress free. For some reason there&rsquo;s still a hanging anxiety.
Part of it is probably my first point about finding a home. The other is that I feel there&rsquo;s something bigger that I
should be doing. Being in Vancouver for the last little while has sparked a stream of nostalgia and reflections on a
simpler and a more naive past.</p>

<h3>Familiar is Good</h3>

<p>This probably isn&rsquo;t a surprise to anyone that knows me, but I&rsquo;m a fan of the familiar. When I drove down to Seattle, I
visited <a href="http://www.oobatooba.com/">Ooba Tooba</a> and <a href="http://bathtubginseattle.com/">Bathtub Gin</a>. In San Francisco I went to the <a href="http://www.beresford.com/beresford/restaurant.htm">White Horse Tavern</a>. Anytime I go back to a place I
haven&rsquo;t been to in a while, I favour hitting the familiar places rather than trying something new. This is clearly part
of who I am and find it something I can&rsquo;t negotiate.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I have no idea how to summarize anything right now. The focus is on data ingress and going to delegate the analysis to a
later time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaving a Dream Job and Going on an Adventure]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-26T19:28:28+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On January 4th 2010 I joined <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/a-new-beginning-or-goodbye-20-s-hello-30-s/">ThoughtWorks</a> and it has been an amazing journey. I&rsquo;ve seen more systems,
worked with more people, and seen more countries than the entire 30 years that preceded that date. I still can&rsquo;t believe
how lucky I&rsquo;ve been to have such a wonderful opportunity. That&rsquo;s why it took me a long time to decide to leave it, and
go on a bit of an adventure.</p>

<h2>Why Leave Such a Good Thing?</h2>

<p>For some reason I&rsquo;ve had every job I&rsquo;ve had for 4 years since I was 12 years old, so I&rsquo;m just keeping to my routine! To
be honest though, there were a few things that instigated this change.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Consulting Fatigue</strong> &ndash; It&rsquo;s hard work always coming in as an outsider and trying to convince people to change their
ways. You never know if what you suggest is correct, and there&rsquo;s always so much context to process. One thing that I&rsquo;ve gotten
out of this though is becoming much more of a critical thinker. I&rsquo;ve learned to hold off on knee-jerk reactions and to
actively listen to the problem at hand. This has been something I apply on a day-to-day basis.</li>
<li><strong>Product Complacency</strong> &ndash; Though, I&rsquo;ve worked on some interesting projects (the latest being very cool), I can&rsquo;t shake
the satisfaction I got from working at <a href="http://music.cbc.ca/radio3/">CBC Radio 3</a> where I got to essentially build the product I wanted to
build on my own anyways. This may have been mitigated but the following reason adds to this one.</li>
<li><strong>Miss Small Teams</strong> &ndash; For some reason people thought I was great at working on large programs of work. While I thought
the challenges were interesting, I&rsquo;m more a small business person at heart. Some may be surprised by this because I&rsquo;ve
been on small teams, but they were in these large programs of work. I&rsquo;ve learned that I&rsquo;m more of a system thinker than I
thought and I find myself getting lost in the system thinking and see myself as this tiny insignificant cog just
wanting to make some impactful change.</li>
</ul>


<p>Though I&rsquo;m listing things related to ThoughtWorks, a lot of my weariness is more from IT in general. It could be an age
thing, but I&rsquo;ve been around long enough to see a lot of terrible things going on in this industry. No one seems to care
about security, and the innovation that is making billions in the stock market are consumer products that mean almost
nothing to me. It&rsquo;s hard to be optimistic after <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Snowden">Edward Snowden</a> revealed the NSA privacy issues.</p>

<p>In the last few years I&rsquo;ve managed to save some money, and given that I&rsquo;m still relatively young and healthy, I thought
now is the time to take a break before I get too cynical.</p>

<h2>What am I Going to do?</h2>

<p>The plan right now is pretty loose, but I have made a rough 6 month itinerary:</p>

<ul>
<li>Head back to North America. This will involve crashing at my brother&rsquo;s places and spend some time with family
and friends.</li>
<li>Do some roadtrips in Canada and the USA.</li>
<li>Taking a cargo ship across the Atlantic.</li>
<li>July is the month of Formula 1! I have tickets for the British GP and the German GP.</li>
<li>Visit Eastern Europe.</li>
<li>Hang out in India for a couple months.</li>
</ul>


<p>Along with the travels, I will be taking some mental journeys</p>

<ul>
<li>I want to study economics and capitalism. If we&rsquo;re in this prison of a system, I want to be an educated prisoner.</li>
<li>Get back to the basics of software development and attempt to unlearn all this &ldquo;Enterprise&rdquo; cruft I&rsquo;ve picked up.
Hoping to to this by learning a few new languages, doing code katas daily and releasing tiny side projects.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a stretch, but I would like to do some athletic training (mainly running).</li>
</ul>


<p>Like most things, I&rsquo;m probably thinking about it too much, but in this case it&rsquo;s the planning that&rsquo;s been valuable and
not the plan itself.</p>

<h2>Sounds Awesome, but That Cannot Last Forever</h2>

<p>During this time I&rsquo;m attempting to figure out future career ideas. At the end I&rsquo;ll
figure out a place to live and what on my list of interesting domains to pursue:</p>

<ul>
<li>Formula 1</li>
<li>Health care</li>
<li>Beer / Cocktails</li>
<li>Golf</li>
<li>Energy</li>
<li>Public Transportation</li>
<li>Music Distribution</li>
<li>Billiards</li>
<li>Space Exploration</li>
<li>City Planning</li>
<li>Software Delivery</li>
</ul>


<p>Heck, I haven&rsquo;t ruled out re-applying to ThoughtWorks.</p>

<h2>ThoughtWorks Made Me Do This</h2>

<p>The irony is that that ThoughtWorks has opened up my mind in such a way that it&rsquo;s empowered me to make this decision.
The ingress of information, concerns, cultures, opinions and experience is a storm brewing in my head trying it&rsquo;s best to
synthesize itself the best it can. If you&rsquo;re thinking about applying at ThoughtWorks, please ping me. It&rsquo;s an awesome
place to work, and full of great people. During this sabbitcal I plan on visiting as many ThoughtWorkers as I can!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking forward to reading this post a year from now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - Devops]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T03:17:52+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Valuable Links for Devops</h2>

<p>TL;DR &ndash; Watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3KpPBnEtRj4">this</a> video</p>

<p>Since I first learned the term devops 4 years ago I&rsquo;ve gone through many leaps in understanding. As a software
developer, I find delivering frequently highly motivating. Devops is a set of principles and practices that aim to
ensure delivery goes as smooth as possible. I found this post, <a href="http://blog.devopsguys.com/2014/02/25/a-scientific-basis-for-devops-success/">A Scientific Basis For Devops Success</a>,
to be a great introduction to why devops is important.</p>

<h2>People</h2>

<p>This list isn&rsquo;t comprehensive, but you can&rsquo;t go wrong by reading what these people have to say:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://jedi.be/">Patrick Debois</a> &ndash; coined the term devops</li>
<li><a href="http://www.noahsussman.com/">Noah Sussman</a> &ndash; provides excellent insights around QA</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kitchensoap.com/">John Allspaw</a> &ndash; has many excellent posts on the culture of devops</li>
<li><a href="http://itrevolution.com/">Gene Kim</a> &ndash; co-author of The Phoenix Project</li>
<li><a href="http://continuousdelivery.com/">Jez Humble</a> &ndash; co-author of Continuous Delivery</li>
</ul>


<h2>Devops is not a Role</h2>

<p>It took me a while to realize that devops is not a role played on a team and that it&rsquo;s got more in commong with Agile in
the fact that it&rsquo;s a collection of principles rather than straight up proceesses.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.getchef.com/blog/2010/07/16/what-devops-means-to-me/">CAMS</a> &ndash; <a href="https://twitter.com/botchagalupe/">John Willis</a>&lsquo; posts a list of principles</li>
<li><a href="http://blog.lusis.org/blog/2013/06/04/devops-the-title-match/">Lusis&#8217; rant</a> &ndash; an excellent rant about the absurditity of devops being a role</li>
</ul>


<h2>Must Watch Videos</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3KpPBnEtRj4">The Devops Transformation</a> &ndash; <a href="https://twitter.com/benr/">Ben Rockwood</a> does a most
enlightening talk on the subject.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h5E--QSBVBY">Devops Demystified</a> &ndash; Another <strong>Ben Rockwood</strong> talk that is awesome</li>
</ul>


<h2>Events</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/">DevOpsDays</a></li>
<li><a href="http://devopssummit.com/">DevOps Summit</a></li>
<li><a href="http://web.experiencedevops.org/">Experience DevOps</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Mailing Lists</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://code.google.com/p/devops-toolchain/">Devops Toolchain</a></li>
<li><a href="http://devopsweekly.com/">Devops Weekly</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Tools</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://devops-bookmarks.herokuapp.com/">Devops Bookmarks</a> &ndash; This is the ultimate one stop shop for all tools</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Developer Resolutions for 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T10:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was tempted to not write this post. My motivations are changing a bit and growing strong technically isn&rsquo;t one of
my top priorities nowadays.</p>

<h2>Reflections on <a href="http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2013/">2013</a></h2>

<p>Last year was very interesting for me. It&rsquo;s the first time I didn&rsquo;t really have a home. I&rsquo;ve split my time between
India, United States, and South Africa, (ok, I was in Toronto for a few weeks too). During that time I&rsquo;ve reflected a
lot (probably too much). My work was split between training new software developers and developing tools to deploy
the largest and most complex distributed system I&rsquo;ve ever worked on.</p>

<p>First, let&rsquo;s look back at 2013 and see how I did with my resolutions:</p>

<ul>
<li>Read 7 Languages in 7 Weeks &ndash; This was a massive fail. I never even got past chapter 1!</li>
<li>More Presentations &ndash; I would give myself a passing grade here. I&rsquo;ve started doing more internal presentations, but
I&rsquo;m sure that there&rsquo;s expectation for me to do more. The problem here is that I really don&rsquo;t enjoy delivering
presentations, but I do struggle when I believe I have interesting things to say and they&rsquo;re stuck in my head. I
definitely need an outlet and will have to figure this out going forward.</li>
<li>Expand my Ops Toolbelt &ndash; This one was definitely a success. I&rsquo;ve picked up Puppet, Ansible and MCollective. Also, I
feel that I&rsquo;ve grown quite adept at Continuous Delivery pipelines and Vagrantizing development environments.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Development Goals for 2014:</h2>

<p>2014 is going to be a different year for me. I don&rsquo;t really care about goals as much, but want to build better habits. I&rsquo;ve reached
many of my goals only to regress behaviour after the goals have been achieved. I&rsquo;ve realized that many of my technical
goals were due more to my ego and fear of looking dumb in front of colleagues and clients. I&rsquo;ve realized that I actually
have a pretty good personal brand, and that people respect my abilities. I&rsquo;ve proven myself over and over again, and
it&rsquo;s time for me to believe it myself.</p>

<h3>Increase Signal to Noise Ratio</h3>

<p>Social media tax is too high for me right now. It&rsquo;s time to start culling the amount of inputs I have. At least I&rsquo;ve
deleted my LinkedIn account. I&rsquo;m going to have a daily unfriend/unfollow 1 person, until I feel things are a bit more
manageable. One small victory in 2013 was deleting my LinkedIn account.</p>

<p>Improving my e-mail habits are up there as well. Things like not checking my e-mail before work is a habit that I plan
on picking up. I also need to write less e-mails. E-mails beget more e-mail.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Facebook Friends at end of 2013</strong> == 480</li>
<li><strong>Following on Twitter at of 2013</strong> == 627</li>
</ul>


<h3>Learn Docker</h3>

<p>OK, I&rsquo;ll sneak in a technical goal. I want to simply understand what the hype is around <a href="https://www.docker.io/">Docker</a>. I tend to be very slow
to catch onto trends. There&rsquo;s enough hype around Docker that I think I should at least understand what I&rsquo;m missing if I
do miss that boat.</p>

<h3>Do Meaningful Work</h3>

<p>4 years ago I left <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/">CBC</a> for <a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/">ThoughtWorks</a>. I don&rsquo;t regret the decision at all, but I now understand what it&rsquo;s like to do
meaningful work. Working on <a href="http://music.cbc.ca/#/blogs/2009/12/Today-on-Lanarama-Techie-Tuesday-A-Fond-Farewell-to-Scott-Muc">Radio 3</a> was fulfilling work, and I&rsquo;m still proud of what was created, and have strong
connections with the people I worked with there.</p>

<p>The tough part about the consulting business is that you can potentially work for money hungry
organisations. I personally don&rsquo;t want to help retail vendors sell more shirts, or banks earn more interest.
ThoughtWorks does do a lot of meaningful work, and I&rsquo;m going to do something I find more fulfilling. Another
stint in India doing ThoughtWorks University would be something that would satisfying this need.</p>

<p>Being a competent developer, I think I owe it to society to do what I can for a greater good. So I&rsquo;m looking at
contributing to <a href="http://www.mailpile.is/">MailPile</a> as a first step. The open government space is something I would like to explore as
well.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I think 2013 was a bit of a downer because of what&rsquo;s been revealed by <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/interactive/2013/nov/01/snowden-nsa-files-surveillance-revelations-decoded#section/1">Edward Snowden</a>. The numerous large scale
<a href="http://thinkprogress.org/security/2013/12/31/3108661/10-biggest-privacy-security-breaches-rocked-2013/">theft of e-mail addresses and passwords</a> have also lowered confidence in IT as a whole. Let&rsquo;s not talk about <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/10/20/4859316/healthcare-gov-woes">Obama Care</a>.
It&rsquo;s frustating to see the industry that I love so much do so much harm, and become so untrustworthy.
2014 is going to shape to be an interesting year as a result of these events.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - Vim]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-vim/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-03T19:31:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>First Off &ndash; Introducing Valuable Links</h2>

<p>Today I&rsquo;ve decided to start something new. I tend to send my friends and colleagues
links about all sorts of things. Usually when they are pertinent to a problem they are
having, or to supplement a conversation I&rsquo;ve had with them. My usual process to reproduce
these links ends up being a search in: <a href="https://twitter.com/scottmuc/" title="My Twitter Feed">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://getpocket.com/users/scottmuc" title="My Pocket Feed">Pocket</a>, History, and my Bookmarks.</p>

<p>Also, when I share my links I tend to write a few sentences about them. It adds a personal
touch and a bit of context, so that&rsquo;s why I&rsquo;m exploring this channel for displaying them.
As opposed to using a bookmarking website.</p>

<h2>Valuable Links for Vim</h2>

<p>I would say I&rsquo;m a moderate <a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a> user. I have a simple <code>.vimrc</code> with few plugins. Learning
to be competent at <code>vim</code> has made my computing experience so much better. Here are a few
websites that have helped me out:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.danielmiessler.com/study/vim/" title="Daniel Miessler's Vim Primer">Vim Primer</a> &ndash; I can&rsquo;t think of a more thorough primer. Even after knowing
vim for a while I learned a lot from this article. Not only that, it helped reinforce
the things I knew already to better explain them.</li>
<li><a href="http://statico.github.io/vim.html" title="Vim After 11 Years">Vim After 11 Years</a> &ndash; A good story on someone&rsquo;s journey learning
vim for the last 11 years.</li>
<li><a href="http://vimgolf.com/" title="Vim Golf">Vim Golf</a> &ndash; Try and do the editing exercises in the minimum number of keystrokes.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/" title="Destroy All Software">Destroy All Software</a> &ndash; Watching <a href="https://twitter.com/garybernhardt" title="Gary's Twitter Feed">Gary Bernhardt</a> is a great
way to learn vim. His excellent screencasts have 3 episodes focused on Vim:
<a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts/catalog/file-navigation-in-vim" title="File Navigation in Vim">File Navigation in Vim</a>, <a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts/catalog/some-vim-tips" title="Some Vim Tips">Some Vim Tips</a>, and
<a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts/catalog/the-vimrc" title="The vimrc">The vimrc</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h3>My Own Tips</h3>

<ul>
<li>Disable the arrow keys. They just encourage bad habits. For me, I had to use the
<code>h</code>, <code>j</code>, <code>l</code>, and <code>l</code> out of necessity. I travel a lot, and writing code on an
airplane is difficult if you have to move your hand to the arrow keys. The key is
not to do this too early otherwise you&rsquo;ll be frustrated like <a href="http://yehudakatz.com/2010/07/29/everyone-who-tried-to-convince-me-to-use-vim-was-wrong/">Yehuda Katz</a>.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t use a premade vim configuration. Things like <a href="https://github.com/carlhuda/janus" title="Janus">Janus</a> make it easy
for vim to behave more like <a href="http://macromates.com/" title="TextMate">TextMate</a> or <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/" title="Sublime Editor">Sublime</a> (both great
editors), but if that&rsquo;s what you want, why not just use them? Instead, strive to
keep your <code>.vimrc</code> your own and rely on plugins to get the benefits of the excellent
work that&rsquo;s been done by other people. <a href="http://blog.clifreeder.com/blog/2012/07/08/leaving-janus-for-vim/" title="Leaving Janus">Clif Reeder</a> articulates when
to leave Janus quite well.</li>
<li>Keep it simple! The more you stray from default, the more dependant you are on
your own configuration. Use plugins in order to extend functionality. If you can&rsquo;t
explain every line of your own <code>.vimrc</code> then either figure it out, or remove it.</li>
<li>As you grow more comfortable, start using vim everywhere. If you use <strong>gmail</strong>, turn
on the keyboard shortcuts (some of them are vim like). If you&rsquo;re using Chrome,
install <a href="http://vimium.github.io/">Vimium</a>. It allows you to navigate the browser
as if it&rsquo;s vim. There&rsquo;s even
<a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/59ca71b3-a4a3-46ca-8fe1-0e90e3f79329">VsVim</a>
for Visual Studio users!</li>
</ul>


<p>Admittedly, I still have a lot to learn. I&rsquo;m by no means an expert.</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong> &ndash; I&rsquo;m a &ldquo;learn it the hard way&rdquo; type of person. So that may explain
my thoughts on the subject.</p>

<p>Hope you enjoyed the first of what could be many &ldquo;valuable links&rdquo; posts.</p>

<h3>Addendum</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://dougblack.io/words/a-good-vimrc.html">A Good Vimrc</a></li>
<li><a href="http://nvie.com/posts/how-i-boosted-my-vim/">How I Boosted My Vim</a></li>
<li><a href="http://stevelosh.com/blog/2010/09/coming-home-to-vim/">Coming Home to Vim</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Most Over-Engineered Thing I Have Made]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/the-most-over-engineered-thing-I-have-made/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-25T08:13:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/the-most-over-engineered-thing-I-have-made</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other day I overheard some interns boasting about their complicated shell setup. They felt pretty good about
using tmux, zsh, and aliasing the heck out of everything. One of them had to re-map copy and paste because they messed
that up, but they felt awesome when they figured out a clever work around.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve all been there at some point. It&rsquo;s something that you grow out of over time. At least I hope so. Here&rsquo;s a story of
the most complicated thing I&rsquo;ve made and I&rsquo;ll start with a network diagram of my basement suite circa 2003:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/complicated-network.png" title="Network Diagram"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/complicated-network.png" width="600"></a></p>

<h2>My Contribution to Over-Engineering</h2>

<p>Hmm, after looking at that network diagram again, I&rsquo;m now thinking about how complicated I&rsquo;ve made a lot of things!
Anyways, the most complicated thing I&rsquo;ve made was a music playing setup for my home. Doesn&rsquo;t sound like it should
be complicated, right?</p>

<p>Here are some of the requirements:</p>

<ul>
<li>Rebooting my laptop doesn&rsquo;t stop the music. I was quad booting (that&rsquo;s another story) and would switch frequently</li>
<li>Control can be from any computer (I did some NAT translation so I could control it from outside the house too)</li>
<li>The machine playing the music had to be quiet (PCs those days were much louder)</li>
</ul>


<h3>Architecture</h3>

<blockquote><p>The result was an mp3 playing system that required 5 computers in order to work.</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/complicated-rack.jpg" title="Server Rack"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/complicated-rack.jpg" width="300"></a> First there was the <strong>file server</strong> that contained
all my music. It would expose files to the network via Nfs and Samba. I was pretty meticulous when it came to
organizing my files. Every artist had a directory, and every album was a sub-directory. In case you&rsquo;re wondering,
I organized artist names as <em>Last Name, First Name</em>. All the mp3s were created by ripping my personal CD collection.</p>

<p>Second was the <strong>music player</strong> box. This was an underclocked machine with no hard drive. This way I was able to run it
without any fans except for the power supply. It used PXE boot load the operating system and would Nfs mount it&rsquo;s filesystem.
The only thing running on it was <a href="http://www.musicpd.org/" title="Music Player Daemon Website">music player daemon</a> which played mp3s that were also Nfs mounted.</p>

<p>So since I required PXE boot, I setup a <strong>network config</strong> server. It was my local DNS, DHCP, and TFTP host. I
configured DHCP to respond to the MAC address of the music player box and provide it a TFTP location to fetch its kernel.
I had a DNS zone setup that handled internal .muc-central.com records (eg: jukebox.muc-central.com).</p>

<p>Those 3 servers were sufficient to have a working music playing system, but it didn&rsquo;t have a user interface. This
required the addition the <strong>web server</strong> which ran Apache and PHP to host <a href="http://mpd.wikia.com/wiki/Client:PhpMp" title="PHP Music Player">PhpMp</a> that connected to the music
player boxes <code>mpd</code> service.</p>

<p>Now with a UI, you can start playing songs, and update a playlist from any machine in the house. The 5th machine is the
<strong>client</strong>, which was my laptop at the time. This was before the era of smart phones, but I imagine with some tweaks, a
mobile web browser would have worked just fine too.</p>

<h2>The Result</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/complicated-livingroom.jpg" title="Living Room"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/complicated-livingroom.jpg" width="515"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/complicated-ui.jpg" title="Screenshot"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/complicated-ui.jpg" width="515"></a></p>

<p><span style="color: #eaeaea;">hack to break the floats</span></p>

<p>The machine that plays music is in a closet near the entrance into my apartment. Then I setup some shelves to
put my <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Altec-Lansing-ACS48-Computer-Speakers/product-reviews/B00000JBJF" title="ACS48 Reviews">Altec Langsing ACS48</a> speakers on top of. The volume on the speakers was set to max so the volume could be
controlled through the software.</p>

<p>The web interface wasn&rsquo;t fancy but I still prefer it to many of the applications I&rsquo;ve used recently. It&rsquo;s a basic PHP
app called <a href="http://mpd.wikia.com/wiki/Client:PhpMp" title="PHP Music Player">PhpMp</a>. What I liked about it the most was the playlist was easy to modify. My friends would browse
the music collection and click a link to add a song to the playlist. The only picture I can find is an old desktop
screenshot where you can see the playlist in the bottom left of the screen.</p>

<h2>Lesson Learned</h2>

<p>Although I would never set something up like that again, I&rsquo;m glad I did it. It was an excellent learning experience and
it actually was one of the best digital music setups I had. It also was the gateway to me starting to write technical
<a href="http://muc-central.com/articles/index.php?file=FreeBSD%20Jukebox" title="My First Online Article">articles</a> online 10 years ago! While listening to the interns, it came to me that this is simply a right
of passage. I don&rsquo;t think I would be where I am today if I did the simplest thing to solve all my problems. One thing it
did make me think about is that I probably should contrive complex solutions as a way to practice my understanding
of of complex systems.</p>

<p>Things I learned by doing this:</p>

<ul>
<li>PXE booting</li>
<li>Diskless computing</li>
<li>TFTP</li>
<li>Non trivial DHCP</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Replacing the Kanban Board With a Shark Tank]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/going-post-kanban-with-a-shark-tank/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-13T23:48:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/going-post-kanban-with-a-shark-tank</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/shark-tank-wall.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>No, this is not an April Fools joke. This was something that was actually implemented.</p>

<p>After ThoughtWorks University was over we had a backlog of work items that needed to be done before we all went back to
billable work. I wanted to put up a Kanban board with 3 columns (TODO, WIP, DONE) to track the work we needed to do. A
question popped into my head; is 3 columns the minimum number necessary?</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/mfait">Michael Fait</a>, a colleague of mine, challenged this notion saying:</p>

<blockquote><p>First, we can get rid of DONE. Just rip up the card.Second, we can remove WIP by putting stickies with names on them on the cards being worked on.</p></blockquote>


<p>Then we wanted to consider priority, so we had the most important things float to the top. Less important items could
not float up until the top ones were removed. &ldquo;Like a fish tank!&rdquo;, one of us exclaimed! The metaphor went crazy from that
point forward. Somehow we introduced sharks and they live near the surface eating all the meat (tasks) that float to
the top. Pairing is represented by sharks eating the same piece of meat. If a shark is out, then they hang out on the beach.</p>

<h3>Make Your Own Shark Tank</h3>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gfydvDUncbY">Draw sharks</a> representing each person on the team.</li>
<li>Put <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blu-Tack">blu tack</a> on the back of the sharks.</li>
<li>Draw the surface of the water, this is where work will get done.</li>
<li>Put stickies in the tank representing work that needs to get done.</li>
<li>As the sharks eat the stickies, let the next level of stickies float on up.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Going Against the Flow]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/going-against-the-flow/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-10T23:41:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/going-against-the-flow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Developers like to talk about being in a state of
<a href="http://psygrammer.com/2011/02/10/the-flow-programming-in-ecstasy/">flow</a>. This is when time just seems to fly
by and you&rsquo;re writing more code in a few hours than you do in several days when you&rsquo;re not &ldquo;flowing&rdquo;. While I think
flowing can be postive, it often can do more harm than good if going on for <strong>too long</strong>.</p>

<p>In the past I would complain that the environment around me kept me from the <strong>flow</strong>. I would look forward to the quiet
times in the office when I could zone out for hours and complete some wild and crazy code I was working on. Many times
I would return the next day and realize that I could have done it simpler, or there were many other aspects of the
problem that I didn&rsquo;t take into consideration. One of the biggest complaints about flow is that it takes a long time to
get into that state. How can we minimize this time, and keep these flows shorter?</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/flow.png">What I found myself needing were breaks. Brief moments to reflect on the past bit of effort and reflect on what work was
done and where it&rsquo;s heading. Many times this has resulted in an &ldquo;aha&rdquo; moment and see that my path is not going towards a
solution that is best for the project. It&rsquo;s also a good time to check your assumptions. You may be flowing towards a
dead-end because of something a little bit of planning could have prevented. Like the diagram to the right suggests,
flow can result in effort that&rsquo;s far from the solution, whereas the small bursts follow a &ldquo;truer&rdquo; path. After the flow
session is it easy to get back on track? Sometimes it&rsquo;s best to simply eliminate all you&rsquo;ve worked on and start from
scratch.</p>

<p>This leads me to <a href="http://www.jamesshore.com/Agile-Book/spike_solutions.html">spiking</a>. Getting into a flow can be useful
when performing a spike. It can reduce the spike time, but is it really possible to flow when working on something you
don&rsquo;t have any clue about?</p>

<p>When programming solo I try my best to always practice the <a href="http://www.pomodorotechnique.com/">pomodoro technique</a>.
There have been so many times that the break (and I try to be disciplined about stopping when the timer goes off, even
when I&rsquo;m in the middle of something) introduces new ways of tackling the problem.</p>

<p>When pairing I experience similar gains with breaks. I never considered this technique when pairing, because I always thought that the
practice already mitigated the risks I mentioned earlier. That may be true, but thanks to <a href="http://johnpdaigle.com/">Paul Daigle</a>, I
found that it was just as effective when pairing. It&rsquo;s even better because you have
someone to reflect upon the pairing session with. A quick time away from the code is a good time to recall what problem
you&rsquo;re actually trying to solve and whether or not the direction you&rsquo;re going is actually going to lead you there.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re leading a technical team and you see everyone glued to their monitors and typing franctically, you might think
that they are &ldquo;flowing&rdquo; and working at a heightened level of productivity. Think again, they could possibly be racing towards
the wrong direction. A team that&rsquo;s moving around, going for walks, taking 5 to do a
<a href="http://www.tabatatimer.com/">tabata</a> to me is a sign of a more switched on team.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PowerShell Pester 2 and 1.2 Released!]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/powershell-pester-2-and-1-dot-2-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-02T15:34:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/powershell-pester-2-and-1-dot-2-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a whirlwind of activity on the <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester">Pester</a> codebase I&rsquo;m happy to announce the latest release of Pester. Versions 1.2 and 2 are identical feature wise except for one subtle difference that I&rsquo;ll get into soon.</p>

<h2>New Expectation and Matcher Syntax</h2>

<p>In prior versions of Pester, we have the dot notation expectation and matcher syntax</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$some_string</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">should</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">be</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;some value&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This required some <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester/blob/bf3afbf330808cfee8a26665a77c9388ae432286/ObjectAdaptations/types.ps1xml">clever and downright nasty hacks</a> to the PowerShell runtime. This created a <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester/issues/19">few</a> <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester/issues/27">issues</a> for some users and I wanted to get that fixed. It turned out the extension on Object was the root issue so I investigated a pipeline based expectation syntax. Here is the result:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$deployDir</span>                <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Be</span> <span class="s2">&quot;C:\inetpub\wwwroot\myApp&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s2">&quot;iis:\Sites\myApp&quot;</span>        <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Exist</span> <span class="c"># this works with any PowerShell provider</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s2">&quot;C:\test\rush_albums.txt&quot;</span> <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Contain</span> <span class="n">2112</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s2">&quot;&quot;</span>                        <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Be</span> <span class="n">NullOrEmpty</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">{</span> <span class="n">throw</span> <span class="p">}</span>                 <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Throw</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Negative statements work too:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="n">2</span>                                   <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Not</span> <span class="n">Be</span> <span class="n">1</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s2">&quot;C:\temp\deployment_scratch_space&quot;</span>  <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Not</span> <span class="n">Exist</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s2">&quot;C:\test\rush_albums.txt&quot;</span>           <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Not</span> <span class="n">Contain</span> <span class="n">5150</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">3</span>                               <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Not</span> <span class="n">Be</span> <span class="n">NullOrEmpty</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">{</span> <span class="n">Deploy-Website</span> <span class="s2">&quot;superawesome&quot;</span> <span class="p">}</span>   <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Not</span> <span class="n">Throw</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Extending the syntax is simply a matter of adding domain specific expectations, that follow the Pester function naming
conventions, to your test suite:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="k">function</span> <span class="n">PesterBeCanadian</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$sentence</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$sentence</span> <span class="o">-match</span> <span class="s2">&quot;.*[,\ ]eh.$&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">function</span> <span class="n">PesterBeCanadianFailureMessage</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$sentence</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Expected: {$sentence} to end with &#39;eh&#39;&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">function</span> <span class="n">NotPesterBeCanadianFailureMessage</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$sentence</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Expected: {$sentence} ended with eh, you hoser!&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">Describe</span> <span class="s2">&quot;a few sentences&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">Context</span> <span class="s2">&quot;when scott says something&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;is Canadian&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="nv">$what_scott_says</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Good show, eh?&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="nv">$what_scott_says</span> <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">BeCanadian</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">Context</span> <span class="s2">&quot;when pete hodgson says something&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;is not Canadian&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="nv">$what_pete_says</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Have you tried testing it with Frank?&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="nv">$what_pete_says</span> <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Not</span> <span class="n">BeCanadian</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Pretty cool, eh? I feel that this can lessen the potential bloat of expectations in Pester and allow people to write
test suites that fit their infrastructure domain model. The expectations are also very <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester/blob/master/Functions/Assertions/Be.Tests.ps1">easy to test</a> in isolation. The core matchers are pretty light, but they should be easy to modify now that matchers have test coverage unlike the previous syntax.</p>

<p>Adding your own matcher requires you to add 3 convention following functions. One that is the matcher, and 2 that return
failure messages for postive and negative expectations. The biggest problem I see with this method is that if the
convention ever changes, I&rsquo;ll have to be very cautious and make it backwards compatible.</p>

<h2>Mocks!</h2>

<p>This was released earlier but I didn&rsquo;t really announce anything. Thanks to <a href="http://www.mattwrock.com/">Matt Wrock</a>(<a href="https://twitter.com/mwrockx">twitter</a>) Pester has the ability to mock cmdlets. I&rsquo;m looking forward to trying this out on my next project.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="n">Mock</span> <span class="nb">Get-Location</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s2">&quot;you are home, sir.&quot;</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">Get-Location</span> <span class="p">|</span> <span class="n">Should</span> <span class="n">Be</span> <span class="s2">&quot;you are home, sir.&quot;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>Description Tagging</h2>

<p>Thanks to <a href="https://github.com/rismoney">Rich Siegel</a>, Pester can now run blocks that fit a certain tag.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="n">Describe</span> <span class="n">-Tag</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Acceptance&quot;</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Website deployment flow&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">It</span> <span class="s2">&quot;...&quot;</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">...</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># and run it like this:</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">Invoke-Pester</span> <span class="n">-Tag</span> <span class="n">Acceptance</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>Xml Reporting</h2>

<p>Another contributor is <a href="https://github.com/mbergmann">Max Bergmann</a> who added NUnit style xml reporting to Pester runs.
We are even using it in Pester&rsquo;s own <a href="http://teamcity.codebetter.com/project.html?projectId=project261&amp;tab=projectOverview">CI build</a>.
There&rsquo;s some XML validation bugs that are still being sorted out.</p>

<h2>Why 1.2.x and 2.0.x?</h2>

<p>The motivation for this release is to fix the issues people have add where a <code>should</code> property is added to every Object.
I&rsquo;m not sure how exactly it was breaking things, but it was messy anyways, and I wanted to get rid of it.</p>

<p>In version <code>1.2.x</code>, you can disable the old assertions by running Pester with the <code>-DisableLegacyExpectations</code>. This will
mean that your test suite has to only use the new pipeline style expectations.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="c"># version 1.2.x has this switch</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">Invoke-Pester</span> <span class="n">-DisableLegacyExpectations</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>For version <code>2.0.x</code> we disable the old style assertions and you need to explicitly enable them using the
<code>-EnableLegacyExpectations</code> switch. In the next significant release we&rsquo;re going to remove the dot style assertions
completely from the codebase.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='powershell'><span class='line'><span class="c"># version 2.0.x has this switch</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">Invoke-Pester</span> <span class="n">-EnableLegacyExpectations</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>So if you&rsquo;re upgrading Pester, then you should probably move to <code>1.2.x</code> first. If you can run your tests with the
<code>-DisableLegacyAssertions</code> flag set, then you should be fine to move to <code>2.0.x</code>. If you&rsquo;re starting from scratch, then
definitely use <code>2.0.x</code>.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s Left To Do?</h2>

<p>Lots and lots of documenting. The <code>Get-Help</code> pages need to be updated and I want to get pesterbdd.com up as soon as
possible. I think version 2 should be a fairly stable version of Pester.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in contributing to Pester please join the <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/pester">google group</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up Overtone]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/setting-up-overtone/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-27T21:11:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/setting-up-overtone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every now and then I like to sit in a coffee shop on a Sunday and focus on writing some code. This weekend I had the pleasure of spending this geeky time with a colleague, <a href="http://literateprogrammer.blogspot.in/">Chris Ford</a>(<a href="https://twitter.com/ctford">twitter</a>).</p>

<p>Chris has gotten me interested into an open source toolkit for creating sounds and making music called <a href="https://github.com/overtone/overtone">Overtone</a>. Here&rsquo;s a talk about demonstrates functional composition using clojure through music and overtone.</p>

<iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Mfsnlbd-4xQ " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>That talk made me want to play with overtone. Here&rsquo;s the diary of my workstation setup.</p>

<h2>Leiningen</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://leiningen.org/img/leiningen.jpg"> Thinking I know what I&rsquo;m doing I say &ldquo;So, Overtone is in Clojure, right? So I&rsquo;ll first install that.&rdquo;. To which he replied &ldquo;No, you need to install <a href="http://leiningen.org/">Leiningen</a>.&rdquo;. What?! I want to install clojure, why do I need this oddly named tool? Already my world has been turned upside down.</p>

<p>Leiningen is a package manager for Clojure. I can&rsquo;t say I understand completely what it&rsquo;s doing, but when I did a <code>sudo port install leiningen</code> I saw Maven was being installed. Chris calmed me down and said that <code>lein</code> hides the pain so I don&rsquo;t have to worry about it.</p>

<p>Sure enough, the install works. I run <code>lein new mucmusic</code> and a simple project structure is setup for me. I updated the <code>project.clj</code> to refer to the 1.4.0 version of Clojure.</p>

<p>I then run <code>lein repl</code> and see the package manager at work. It downloads Clojure for me and I&rsquo;m in a repl. I try the most basic thing I know <code>(+ 1 1)</code> and it works! I can only imagine what&rsquo;s going on behind the scenes. I find it interesting that a package management tool is responsible for obtaining the language you&rsquo;re going to develop in. It makes a whole lot of sense actually. It&rsquo;s sort of like <a href="http://www.virtualenv.org/en/latest/">virtualenv</a>, but not quite.</p>

<h2>Clojure</h2>

<p><img class="left" src="http://clojure.org/space/showimage/clojure-icon.gif"> Since I&rsquo;m still coming to grips on writing code in Clojure I can&rsquo;t comment on the language, but what I really like so far is how accessible the documentation is. Simply evaluating <code>(doc +)</code> will print the documentation for &lsquo;+&rsquo; function  and <code>(source +)</code> prints out the source code. The REPL made it very easy to get started.</p>

<p>One thing that tripped me up was using a namespace I had defined. I learned the the &lsquo; character is used to indicate the following text is a symbol and not to be evaluated. Also, the first project I created had an underscore in it. In order to use that namespace I had to use a hyphen when using it.</p>

<h2>Overtone</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://overtone.github.com/media/logo.png"> Happy that I can write and evaluate Clojure code it was time to setup Overtone. This part was really nice. All I did was update the <code>project.clj</code> file and added the overtone dependency. The next time I ran <code>lein repl</code> it downloaded overtone and set everything up for me.</p>

<p>In the repl I loaded overtone via <code>(use 'overtone.live)</code> and here&rsquo;s the output:</p>

<pre><code>reply.eval-modes.nrepl=&gt; (use 'overtone.live)
--&gt; Loading Overtone...
--&gt; Booting internal SuperCollider server...
--&gt; Connecting to internal SuperCollider server...
--&gt; Connection established

    _____                 __
   / __  /_  _____  _____/ /_____  ____  ___
  / / / / | / / _ \/ ___/ __/ __ \/ __ \/ _ \
 / /_/ /| |/ /  __/ /  / /_/ /_/ / / / /  __/
 \____/ |___/\___/_/   \__/\____/_/ /_/\___/

    Collaborative Programmable Music. v0.8

Hello ThoughtWorks, just take a moment to pause and focus your creative powers...
</code></pre>

<p>Woah! Booting internal SuperCollider server? Is Clojure so powerful that I can run my own atom smasher?
Turns out the answer is unknown on that, but what <code>overtone.live</code> does is smartly start up
<a href="http://supercollider.sourceforge.net/">SuperCollider</a> which is &ldquo;an environment and programming language
for real time audio synthesis and algorithmic composition&rdquo;. Ahh! So overtone needs this to actually
create audio.</p>

<p>I continue to follow the <a href="https://github.com/overtone/overtone">README</a> and make my first sound.</p>

<pre><code>(demo (sin-osc))
</code></pre>

<p>This code rewards me with the beautiful sound that is a sine wave. Curious as to what <code>demo</code> and <code>sin-osc</code>
do I load up the docs in the repl.</p>

<pre><code>overtone.live/demo
([&amp; body])
Macro
  Listen to an anonymous synth definition for a fixed period of time.
  Useful for experimentation.  If the root node is not an out ugen, then
  it will add one automatically.  You can specify a timeout in seconds
  as the first argument otherwise it defaults to *demo-time* ms. See
  #'run for a version of demo that does not add an out ugen.

  (demo (sin-osc 440))      ;=&gt; plays a sine wave for *demo-time* ms
  (demo 0.5 (sin-osc 440))  ;=&gt; plays a sine wave for half a second
nil
user=&gt; (doc sin-osc)
-------------------------
overtone.live/sin-osc
([freq phase])

  Sine table lookup oscillator 

  [freq 440.0, phase 0.0]

  freq  - Frequency in Hertz 
  phase - Phase offset or modulator in radians 

  Outputs a sine wave with values oscillating between -1 and 1 similar to 
  osc except that the table has already been fixed as a sine table of 8192 
  entries.

  Sine waves are often used for creating sub-basses or are mixed with 
  other waveforms to add extra body or bottom end to a sound. They contain 
  no harmonics and consist entirely of the fundamental frequency. This 
  means that they're not suitable for subtractive synthesis i.e. 
  passing through filters such as a hpf or lpf. However, they are useful 
  for additive synthesis i.e. adding multiple sine waves together at 
  different frequencies, amplitudes and phase to create new timbres. 

  Categories: Generators -&gt; Deterministic
  Rates: [ :ar, :kr ]
  Default rate: :ar
</code></pre>

<p>No wonder people love programming in clojure! This idea of the documentation living in the
code is wonderful. I&rsquo;m generally used to googling for a function name, but this makes that step
unnecessary.</p>

<h2>VimClojure</h2>

<p>Chris, like myself, also uses <a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a>. So first thing I wanted to do is get some syntax highlighting. Chris points me to <a href="https://github.com/daveray/vimclojure-easy">vimclojure-easy</a>, but I didn&rsquo;t want to replace my vim configuration. I already maintain my vim in a tidy and versioned way. Looking at the this repo gave me the direction I needed to set this up. I cloned <a href="https://github.com/vim-scripts/VimClojure">VimClojure</a> into my <code>~/.vim/bundle</code> directory (and removed its .git directory). I launch vim on a clojure file and I have syntax highlighting!</p>

<h2>lein-tarsier and nailgun</h2>

<p>Thinking I was complete I tried some of the vim shortcuts to evaluate some clojure from within vim. Then I realized I&rsquo;m
not quite done (feels like my visit to the <a href="http://indianfrro.gov.in/frro/">FRRO</a>. This is now where the JVM comes in.
Clojure is a JIT compiled language. In order to compile, it needs a JVM. Starting up a JVM all the time is a very
slow and painful process.</p>

<p>Lein-tarsier (tarsier is the type of creature on the <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596529833.do">O&#8217;Reilly Vim book</a>
is a lein plugin that starts up a VimClojure server. To install this, I just added it to my lein profile. It didn&rsquo;t work
at first, but that was because MacPorts installs version 1.6 of lein. Nailgun was some C code that you have to download a compile and make reference to it in your vimrc. I&rsquo;m sort of lost on how all these components work together.</p>

<p>A quick <code>lein upgrade</code> got me to version 2.0. Then an execution of <code>lein vimclojure</code> and the server is up and running.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>After installing a bunch of oddly named things I was able to play the pieces from Chris&#8217; talk in vim.</p>

<p>There were some details that I left out (and forgot). I don&rsquo;t think I would have gotten this far without help from Chris
and the considerable documentation that&rsquo;s in the README files and wikis. Part of me also thinks that it shouldn&rsquo;t
require this much work. As a side project, I&rsquo;m going to look into pulling all of these steps into a Vagrant
configuration management setup. I think it would be nice to go <code>vagrant up overtone</code> and have a working overtone
development environment.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Developer Resolutions for 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2013/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-31T10:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2012 started off interesting because I was on on an iOS/ruby project. Nearly everything was new to me, but I liked how
my past experiences with other technology stacks were still relevant. Even though I didn&rsquo;t know the languages very well
the patterns I&rsquo;ve seen before still applied.</p>

<p>The last quarter of the year was spent teaching new software developers in India, which has been one of the most
rewarding experiences of my career! It has definitely influenced my goals for 2013.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Reflections on 2012 and carry over from 2011:</h2>

<ul>
<li>Learn a server provisioning automation tool (2011) &ndash; I may have failed this one big time in 2011 but 2012 was a great
year for this. I spent much of the year getting to know Chef. I feel I can check this one off now.</li>
<li>Stop reading comments (2012) &ndash; Can&rsquo;t say I&rsquo;ve stopped reading comments but I&rsquo;m more conscious of when I&rsquo;m wasting my
time and tend to stop immediately. I started following a <a href="https://twitter.com/AvoidComments">useful twitter account</a>
which provides constant reminders that reading comments can be a huge waste of time.</li>
<li>No client work when away from client (2012) &ndash; I twisted this one into a conditional success. I still like to hack in
my spare time but I hack on my personal projects and stay away from doing extra billable hours when I should be having
ME time. I&rsquo;ve been much better at saying NO to excess outings and have focused on being healthy.</li>
<li>Complete <a href="https://github.com/manojlds/YDeliver/">YDeliver</a> (2012) &ndash; This one is a big failure. I barely touched
YDeliver all year. Apparently it&rsquo;s been used in a few ThoughtWorks projects by <a href="https://github.com/manojlds">Manoj</a> and he now
has ownership of the repository. I&rsquo;ve come to the realization that OSS doesn&rsquo;t come out of a vacuum. YDeliver was
going strong when I still had fresh memories of that previous project, but as time went on, the relevance (to me) of
YDeliver was diminishing. The takeaway for is me to maintain the momentum if it&rsquo;s there.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Development Goals for 2013:</h2>

<p>While 2012 was a great mix of fun ops tooling learning and consulting, I want to get back to my roots (pun?) and do more low
level tech related things. At the same time, I want to improve on my teaching skills which will mean facilitating more learning
workshops and presenting more frequently.</p>

<h3>Read <a href="http://pragprog.com/book/btlang/seven-languages-in-seven-weeks">7 Languages in 7 Weeks</a></h3>

<p>Much of my effort is spent making many puzzle pieces fit together. Being isolated to a
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Read%E2%80%93eval%E2%80%93print_loop">REPL</a> and a text editor would be
pleasant change. Also, I haven&rsquo;t dived deep into a language lately. All my ruby learning has been simply by having to
write ruby code for work. I can&rsquo;t say I know the language, but I&rsquo;ve managed to figure things out. I miss having a little
bit deeper knowledge of a language like I used to have with C#.</p>

<p>My action plan is to purchase the book and do 1 language a month. So by July this goal will be accomplished.</p>

<h3>More Presentations</h3>

<p>Being a trainer at ThoughtWorks University taught me that I have a lot to learn about presenting. <a href="http://www.learninggeneralist.com/">Sumeet
Moghe</a>, who was the previous lead trainer, showed excellent examples of what makes a
good presentation. It was interesting, because I always felt those points internally, but he expresses them externally
in a digestable way that actually inspires me to make excellent presentations.</p>

<p>My colleague <a href="http://twitter.com/tpbrown">Tim Brown</a> will be happy about this goal because he&rsquo;s been nagging me for a
while about this. Some topics I&rsquo;ve been pondering so far are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Using <a href="http://vagrantup.com/">Vagrant</a> to provide local infrastructure (aka never install a DB server on your machine again)</li>
<li>Application configuration patterns with a non-trivial number of environments</li>
<li>PowerShell BDD with <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester/">Pester</a></li>
</ul>


<p>The action plan is to choose 1 of these topics and present it 3 times. As well as the presentations, I will design 3
different workshops and faciliate each one 3 times.</p>

<h3>Expand my Ops Toolbelt</h3>

<p>I really love ops and I think this is the career path I want to continue on. 2012 was great for learning
<a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">Chef</a>, so this year I want to learn <a href="http://puppetlabs.com/">Puppet</a>. Another area
that I would like to improve upon my knowledge is the domain of remoting.</p>

<p>My action plan is to duplicate any Vagrant server setups that use Chef to use Puppet as well. This will be great for
a side-by-side comparison. So currently that would mean the following repositories need a puppet provisioner:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/vagrant-postgresql">vagrant-postgresql</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/vagrant_rails">vagrant-rails</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/gordon">gordon</a></li>
</ul>


<p>For remoting I plan on writing 10 blog posts on tools like ssh, winRM. I want to dive into the mechanics of
authentication and networking to better understand technologies like kerberos, certificates, and gssapi which are
crucial for making remoting work on a larger scale.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>The last few years I&rsquo;ve learned a lot about managing my goals. I&rsquo;m doing my best to keep my goals
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SMART_criteria">SMART</a> so that I can actually achieve them. We&rsquo;ll see how things turn
out 365 days from now!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devops Days 2012 in Summary]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/devops-days-2012-in-summary/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-29T17:08:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/devops-days-2012-in-summary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://devopsdays.org/">DevopsDays</a> is a juxtaposition in the world of IT. Most
tech conferences focus on tools and processes, whereas Devops Days focuses on
culture and the delivery of value. This year&rsquo;s conference was no exception and
here is a summary of what I experienced:</p>

<h2>Day 1</h2>

<h4>The Audubon Society for Partial Failures</h4>

<p>The first <a href="http://cl.ly/2t1J0H1M3b2O092a1v1S">presentation</a> was done by <a href="https://twitter.com/moonpolysoft">Cliff Moon</a>. He argues
that there are many common patterns in the IT space and it would be valuable
to have a repository of knowledge that we can visit to read about the types of
errors that can happen. If we could build a taxonomy for the partial failures
that exist we may better understand our systems and explain when full-blown
outages occur.</p>

<p>He stresses sharing as the ultimate method for this. Not just sharing ideas and
hypotheses but also the data that lead to the hypothesis. This allows for peer
review and corrections to be made if analysis of the data could have been
misinterpreted.</p>

<p>What I really enjoyed was the spirit of Cliff&rsquo;s talk. The influence for the title
was a man who was obsessed with categorizing birds, John James Adubon. What
really hit home was the idea that there&rsquo;s always someone on your team that is
somewhat of a shaman when it comes to resolving production issues. It might
simply be because that person understands the conventions of the system at
work. Creating this taxonomy could help in revealing the shaman&rsquo;s &ldquo;secrets&rdquo; and
allow for everyone to weave a little magic.</p>

<h4>Continuous Improvement</h4>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/noahsussman">Noah Sussman</a> is a test architect at Etsy and he
<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/noahsussman/continuous-improvement-devops-day-mountain-view-2012">presented</a> on how Continuous Deployment and
Continuous Delivery change how quality assurance needs to be done.</p>

<p>I believe this to be a very important topic because this is going to be
a drastic change for most organisations. Large companies are enamoured with
startup culture and ideas, but aren&rsquo;t seeing what&rsquo;s required of them to change
to this model. A change in testing strategy is a significant barrier to entry
for most large companies. Even if the devs and ops teams are collaborating,
they can&rsquo;t deliver anything unless it gets passed the quality gates.</p>

<h4>Vagrant 2.0</h4>

<p>I got a chance to meet <a href="https://twitter.com/mitchellh">Mitchell Hashimoto</a>,
creator of a tool that I&rsquo;ve been enjoying quite a bit lately,
<a href="http://vagrantup.com/">Vagrant</a>. There was an excellent discussion on how people
are using vagrant in their organisation. What was also exciting was hearing
what&rsquo;s coming out next:</p>

<ul>
<li>run on any VM software</li>
<li>run any guest OS (that includes OS X)</li>
<li>distributed as a package, not as a gem</li>
<li>Builder (essentially merging veewee into vagrant)</li>
</ul>


<p>During the session I also learned about the concept of baking an image vs
frying one (and everyone knows I love analogies). To bake an image is to use
an image as is, no configuration management is needed. This doesn&rsquo;t mean
configuration management isn&rsquo;t used to bake that image though which I thought
was an important detail. Frying an image is to start with a common base and
always reach an end state via configuration management. Frying is the approach
I favour because I like to execute my chef recipes as often as possible. I
also learned about different ways of baking images and still having the same
level of confidence in configuration management scripting.</p>

<h2>Day 2</h2>

<h4>Gauntlt and bridging the gap between security and everyone</h4>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/wickett">James Wickett</a>, a security consultant, discussed how security is feeling left
out in this crazy world of Continuous Integration, Testing, and Delivery.
What is cool, is that he&rsquo;s doing something about it.</p>

<p>In typical security processes, an organisation has someone come in and
perform an assessment of the security of the applications being developed.
The artifact is usually a 100 page PDF describing everything that&rsquo;s wrong
with the system being developed. Instead of a document, he suggests delivering
a test suite that can be executed continuously. Hence <a href="https://github.com/thegauntlet/gauntlt">gauntlt</a> is born; a tool
to execute security tests against a running application.</p>

<p>I chatted with James briefly and somehow managed to volunteer to join their
team. I am no security expert, but I believe there&rsquo;s a gap in security knowledge
in the software industry. Hopefully by integrating gauntlt into future projects
I can provide some feedback to make the tool more useful.</p>

<h4>Continuous Delivery at Ancestry.com</h4>

<p>I posted my thoughts on a similar presentation at <a href="http://scottmuc.com/chefconf-2012-in-summary/">Chef Conf</a> and again John
delivered an excellent presentation on the values of culture and delivery focus
at their organisation.</p>

<p>Again I got a chance to chat with Dan Gilmer who implemented a lot of tech
around their pipeline and am looking forward to collaborating with him on
open sourcing his robust solution to dealing with Windows configuration
management using PowerShell and Chef. Hopefully we&rsquo;ll have some of that
knowledge in a project in github soon.</p>

<h4>Automating Application Configuration Deployment</h4>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/dcnem">Dan Nemec</a> delivered a presentation that is very near and dear to my heart.
Application configuration management can be messy if left to people who do not
have visibility into all the systems that are in play. He brought a system that
required 400+ configuration files to a 2 file system. The 400+ files still
existed but by using templates, and simple configuration hierarchy in chef
he was able to make application configuration management much simpler and
easier to scale.</p>

<p>This hit home for me because I&rsquo;ve implemented my own turnkey implementation
of this on my last few projects. Those that have worked with me know I refer
to these as environment yaml files. These files are a manifest of the topology
of an environment and all its configuration.</p>

<p>You can read more about Dan&rsquo;s thoughts on this on his <a href="http://blog.geeksgonemad.com/2012/05/automating-application-configuration.html">blog</a>.</p>

<h4>Where Does SmallOps Fit In</h4>

<p>This session was very relevant to me as someone who has been working on a small
team for the last few months. <a href="https://twitter.com/mkocher">Matthew Kocher</a>
highlights the simple solutions which is why I really enjoy hearing him discuss
his opinion.</p>

<p>During this session not much of a consensus was reached. I got the feeling that
most of the people in the room didn&rsquo;t quite know what to do with SmallOps. How
do you manage 20 servers and not complicate the infrastructure
management?</p>

<h4>Devops as a role on projects</h4>

<p>This topic, I love in principle, but do a horrible job in practice. There&rsquo;s
no such thing as a &ldquo;DevOps Engineer&rdquo;, it&rsquo;s just a mindset. This is where
the cultural message is most important. DevOps is about transforming
organisations to remove silos. Jamie who brought up the open space likened
a software delivery team to a sports team (again, I love the analogies). With
sports you still have specialists, but they work has a cohesive unit. In
football, there&rsquo;s no reason a defense person can&rsquo;t score a goal. If you have
a team where offensive players begin blaming defense for their lack of success
you then have a disfunctional team.</p>

<h4>What Am I Going To Do Now?</h4>

<p>It really hit home to me after this Devops Days how I am doing a lot of things
wrong in the mission to bridge these gaps.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Measure all things.</li>
<li>Use monitoring tools (I&rsquo;ve been a cowboy ops person for too long)</li>
<li>Keep my engagements short to force knowledge transfer early</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Examples of How Production Like Environments Can Catch Bugs Early]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/examples-of-how-production-like-environments-can-catch-bugs-early/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-08T17:03:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/examples-of-how-production-like-environments-can-catch-bugs-early</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On a previous project, I witnessed a few interesting build breakages that we caught in <a href="http://wikipedia.org/Continuous_Integration">CI</a>
that could have easily gotten passed our automated quality gates. These issues would have hurt us in downstream
environments.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s commonly referenced in the <a href="http://continuousdelivery.com/">Continuous Delivery</a> book that development
environments should be as close to production like as possible. This might not
be 100% possible but you can come close. What can come that close is your
system integration test environment. On this project we had a typical
web application architecture: web server, database server, and a load balancer
to support multiple web servers. Here are a couple integration failures that we experienced:</p>

<h2>Issue 1</h2>

<p>A route in our application returned the version of the application and the
hostname of the machine. It wasn&rsquo;t used by the application at all, but it was
used in environments that had load balancers because it is what they used to
detect the health of the application. Someone deleted this route and
deployments ceased to be successful because the application was considered
down by the load balancer so it returned <a href="http://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616-sec10.html">HTTP 503</a>.</p>

<p>Had our <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System_integration_testing">system integration</a> environment simply used the hostname of the
application server, this would not have been caught until it made it to
downstream environments. It was easy to fix and helped transfer knowledge to
the team. It was also much less stressful to catch here than when a product
owner is pushing something to UAT and things all of the sudden break.</p>

<h2>Issue 2</h2>

<p>A change to some application code used unconfigured database connection
code. Default behaviour of the code is to connect to localhost when issuing
queries against the database. This worked fine locally, but because the
system integration environment seperated the database server from the web
application server, this unconfigured code was caught before it made it to
any other downstream environment.</p>

<h2>Isn&rsquo;t That Overboard?</h2>

<p>If I was managing environments manually, I would say yes. Since the environments
are nearly 100% configured by <a href="http://opscode.com/chef">Chef</a> and our deployment code is automated, I don&rsquo;t think
having the environment set up this way is going too far. It caught what could be
extremely stressful defects to debug in production much earlier such that that our fixes
could be done quickly and with confidence.</p>

<p>I predict that in the future, tools like <a href="http://vagrantup.com/">vagrant</a> will help us setup these
architectures on our local machines so that we can catch these issues before
they even get checked into version control. Imagine developing software in
a way that the mismatch between dev and prod becomes such a non-issue that
it&rsquo;s no longer a worry? I look forward to helping make that world possible.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
