<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-26T09:56:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Irish Whiskey Appreciation]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/irish-whiskey-appreciation/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-20T19:05:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/irish-whiskey-appreciation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/dublin.jpg" width="1024"></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer &ndash; I was not paid or propositioned to write this post and/or link to the Mitchell &amp; Son web store. I just
enjoyed their course a lot. At the end of the course I was given a 10€ discount on any Green/Yellow spot whiskies. I
would also recommend the <a href="http://www.celticwhiskeyshop.com/">Celtic Whiskey Shop</a> too.</strong></p>

<p>Over the last month I had the wonderful opportunity of learning all about Irish whiskey. It was held in the
<a href="http://mitchellandson.com/">Mitchell and Son</a> store in <a href="http://chq.ie/">The CHQ Building</a> (where I work) so how could I not participate?
If you see them offering it again I highly recommend it! Not only did I learn a lot about Irish whiskey, I learned
a lot about whiskey in general.</p>

<p>First, a bit of history. It&rsquo;s quite possible that you are screaming at your screen shouting that I am spelling
whiskey incorrectly. Chill out. The word originates from the old Irish word <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uisce_beatha">uisce</a></em> (meaning water). When
Scotch whisky became popular the proud Irish introduced &lsquo;e&rsquo; into the anglicised version of <em>uisce</em>, hence whiskey.
The USA often uses this spelling too which may be because of the large amounts of Irish emigration during that time.
What&rsquo;s very clear is that people do spend way too much time arguing about what is the &ldquo;right&rdquo; way. The liquid doesn&rsquo;t
care what you call it.</p>

<p>Three of the evenings had brand ambassadors to do a bit of a sales pitch. At least that&rsquo;s what I thought they were going
to do. What I ended up hearing from them was passion about whiskey and its Irish origins. They enjoyed their competitors
products and they were happy to be a part of the booming Irish whiskey resurgence. There was a feeling of
disappointment  about the world view of Irish whiskey. Scotch is perceived as the ultimate whiskey and that Irish whiskey
is only used for shots (and usually only Jameson).</p>

<p>Thankfully, I know better now. The course made me appreciate Irish whiskey, but it made me appreciate the Irish people
as well. The course did not have any air of snobbery about it. The presenters gave tips and hints about how they like to
enjoy their whiskey but didn&rsquo;t seem to be too bothered too much if people had other ways of enjoying it. In the end they
just wanted people to know that Irish whiskey isn&rsquo;t just shots of Jameson and a brutal hangover.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s begin!</p>

<h2>Week 1 &ndash; Single Pot Still Whiskey</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week1-whiskies-full.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week1-whiskies.jpg" width="400"></a>
Irish single <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pot_still">pot still</a> whiskey is the traditional way of making the spirit. It&rsquo;s a bit more laborious
compared to using a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Column_still">continuous still (aka column still)</a>, which some whiskeys in later weeks are made by.</p>

<p>For traditional Irish single pot still whiskey the mash bill is half malted barley and half unmalted barley. The unmalted
barley is there because of tax laws the existed in 1795. This tickles the economist in me because I love seeing how
financial incentives create innovation (the history of British ales and Belgium beer have similar economic origins). With
the tax incentives gone this style of whiskey is still made because the flavour profile became rather popular.</p>

<p>The distilling begins with a fermenting mash heated to a temperature where the alcohol evaporates. The first
distillation isn&rsquo;t pure enough so this gets distilled again. When you read a label that says &ldquo;triple distilled&rdquo;, it&rsquo;s
because it was distilled in pot stills and you need that third distillation to really extract the cleanest
distilate. Some whiskeys are known and enjoyed for being double distilled, but this usually isn&rsquo;t by design. It&rsquo;s
most likely because of budget since the extra still does cost quite a bit (again with the financial incentives).</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week1-notes-full.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week1-notes.jpg" width="500"></a>
The evening started with a collection of whiskies in a circle. In the period of 2 hours we heard the wise words
of Mark McLaughlin. You can instantly tell the guy is mad about whiskey. He does an excellent job of getting you just
as excited to experience the whiskey as he is.</p>

<p>To the right you can see the whiskeys I tried.</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://mitchellandson.com/spirits/spirits-category/whiskey/green-spot-chateau-leoville-barton.html">Green Spot Château Léoville Barton</a> &ndash; A very unique nose (how it smells) on this one. My notes
say hopscotch but after further tastings I would add cookie dough or frosting. On the palate (how it tastes) is a bit
like buttered toast but transforms into a cinnamon toast. There&rsquo;s some nuts and spice to it as well. The finish
(aftertaste) is fruity, warm, and medium length.</li>
<li><a href="http://mitchellandson.com/redbreast-sherry-finish-lustau-edition.html">Red Breat Lustau</a> &ndash; Like the above it had a buttery nose to it. On the palate it was much meatier
and savory. There&rsquo;s dried fruit and a bit of spice. This is one of the remaining bottles I feel I need to add to the
collection.</li>
<li>I have to mention the <a href="http://mitchellandson.com/spirits/spirits-category/green-yellow-spot/green-spot-whiskey-10-year-old.html">Green Spot 10 Year Old</a> and the <a href="http://mitchellandson.com/spirits/spirits-category/midleton-dair-ghaelach-irish-oak-tree-3.html">Middleton Dair Ghaelach</a>
because they were amazing, but way out of my price range. I&rsquo;m quite content with the mid priced gems above.</li>
</ol>


<p>The representitive for this week was from <a href="http://www.irishdistillers.ie/">Irish Distillers</a> and boy could he talk&hellip; and talk&hellip; and talk.</p>

<br style="clear: both;" />


<h2>Week 2 &ndash; Single Malt Whiskey</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week2-whiskies-full.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week2-whiskies.jpg" width="400"></a>
The theme for this week is single malt whiskey. The term &ldquo;single malt&rdquo; has become synonymous with high quality. You may
even hear people say that they like a nice &ldquo;single malt&rdquo; and not mention the word whiskey. That&rsquo;s how popular and recognized
the term has become.</p>

<p>Some individuals think this is the only real style of whiskey and frown upon anything that&rsquo;s blended. They forget that
the word &ldquo;single&rdquo; implies that the liquid is just coming from the same distillery. The &ldquo;malt&rdquo; part means that only malted
barley is in the mash bill (you&rsquo;ll recall single pot still also had unmalted barley). Blending 100% malt whiskey of
different ages is very common. Again it&rsquo;s a matter of economics as well as taste. Because the business has fairly long
feedback loops their finance departments often face liquidity (zing) issues. So when you get a bottle and it says 8
years on the label, that&rsquo;s just the age of the youngest liquid in the bottle. Master blenders will use their stock to
combine different casks of several ages and come up with flavours that can be great and ready for the shelf.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week2-notes-full.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week2-notes.jpg" width="500"></a>
The brand ambassador of the evening was from <a href="http://www.bushmills.com/">Bushmills</a> which is the only old time distillery still in operation on the
island of Ireland (circa 1784). I really need to get myself up to Belfast for a visit and then a distillery tour up in
Bushmills at some point.</p>

<p>To the right you can see the whiskeys I tried.</p>

<ol>
<li><em>Bushmills Port Cask</em> &ndash; Something about this one tasted familiar. I believe I had a port cask Lagavulin that was like a
warm cozy blanket. This one was like that.</li>
<li><a href="http://mitchellandson.com/spirits/spirits-category/whiskey/teeling-revival-volume-ii-13-year-old.html">Teeling Revival Volume II</a> &ndash; My notes show a dominate apple characteristic. The nose was like
freshly cut green apple. The palate was like experiencing a 3 course meal! First was a light salad with fresh cut
apples, then something savoury like a vegetable stew, then finishes up with apple pie. I don&rsquo;t know if the first
whiskies had an affect on me, but I need to get a bottle of this to see if I can replicate that experience.</li>
<li><em>Tullamore Dew 18yr</em> &ndash; Again I got lots of apple, but that could have been the residue from the previous whiskey. The
palate was all over the place with juniper, mint, raisin, and honey. I even got a feeling of masala chai out of it.
This was very nice whiskey.</li>
</ol>


<p>You may have noticed an absence of links in a couple of the above whiskies. It turns out that airport duty free stores
are a huge market and many brands create airport only whiskies. The Bushmills representive said that 50% of their
product turnover is in airports! Such a shame because these two were really really good.</p>

<br style="clear: both;" />


<h2>Week 3 &ndash; All Grain and Independent Bottlers</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week3-whiskies-full.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week3-whiskies.jpg" width="400"></a>
The first couple whiskeys of the evening was a brief tour of Single Grain whiskey. The best I can understand it is that
the distillate is made of corn and distilled by column stills. This makes them a bit cheaper to produce and have their
own flavour profiles. They are much lighter on the palate and easy to drink. While I thought they were quite drinkable,
they didn&rsquo;t have the bigger flavour that I prefer.</p>

<p>Independent bottlers are a collection of brands that aren&rsquo;t backed by the big players in the market. What I found very
interesting is that the brand of the whiskey doesn&rsquo;t imply that they distilled the liquid. Since Ireland only has a handful
of running distilleries the liquid would only come from them (usually Bushmills but others are upping their production).
The independents can then choose their casks and blending strategies to make something unique and distinctly theirs. I&rsquo;m
glad they did because they produced a couple of my favourites!</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week3-notes-full.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week3-notes.jpg" width="500"></a>
To the right you can see the whiskeys I tried.</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://mitchellandson.com/writer-s-tears-red-head.html">Writer&rsquo;s Tears Red Head</a> &ndash; This is probably the best value out of all the whiskies that I rated
highly. The finish just keeps going. The middle provides this mouth feel that is a joy for the tongue.</li>
<li><a href="http://mitchellandson.com/spirits/dunville-s-10yo-px-finish.html">Dunvilles PX Cask Finish</a> &ndash; The nose is full of pineapple and tropical fruit. There&rsquo;s a bit of
chocolate there too. When you taste it you get something like a spicy valentines day heart candy, which settles down
into a nutty soft middle. The finish is smooth and long with hints of black berries and pine. Every sip of this is a
new story and trying to explain the flavours is so much fun. This is by far my favourite whiskey of the entire
course.</li>
<li><a href="http://mitchellandson.com/spirits/connemara-22-year-old.html">Connemara 22 yrs</a> &ndash; Another really complex whiskey with the flavour going all over the map. It was
very peaty, but behind the smokiness was many other flavours hiding in the woodwork (zing!). At the price
point it&rsquo;ll be something I pick up for a special occasion. Nah, I&rsquo;ll probably get a bottle soon enough.</li>
</ol>


<p>The first two were so good that I bought both of them the next day.</p>

<br style="clear: both;" />


<h2>Week 4 &ndash; Blended Whiskey</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week4-whiskies-full.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week4-whiskies.jpg" width="400"></a>
In the single malt section I described a bit of what blending entails. It&rsquo;s pretty simple to describe, but the execution
of the tasty blend is where the skills comes in. Blends are also quite fun to drink because it provides a puzzle for the
drinker to disect and figure out the blend composition is made up of. I felt that I was a bit snobby regarding blended
whiskies but I&rsquo;m ready to give blends much more time than before. It&rsquo;s funny how fickle our opinions can be when it
comes to taste. If it doesn&rsquo;t taste like what you&rsquo;re used to it seems natural to dislike it. Shake out those
preconceived biases and enjoy the drink on its own. Easier said than done.</p>

<p>The final week was extra special because the tastings were done blind. I loved this because it makes biased opinions
a lot harder. I would like to taste more whiskies this way. Something to keep in mind is that every single whiskey is very
good. None would be something I wouldn&rsquo;t be able to finish a bottle of. My scores just help me decide which of these
fine whiskies I should spend my money on.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week4-notes-full.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/week4-notes.jpg" width="500"></a>
To the right you can see the whiskeys I tried.</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://mitchellandson.com/tullamore-dew-12-year-old.html">Tullamore Dew 12yr</a> &ndash; This one was a lot of fun to drink. It&rsquo;s a triple style blend (single
pot-still, malt, and grain). I don&rsquo;t know if it&rsquo;s the blending but I enjoyed the juxtaposition of the nose
compared to the palate. It plays with the tongue in a prickly way too. At less than 50€ it&rsquo;s a pretty decent value
too.</li>
<li><a href="http://mitchellandson.com/the-irishman-cask-strength.html">Irishman Cask Strength</a> &ndash; A bit pricey but it provides so many ways to enjoy it. Every sip was
different. Adding a few drops of water took the edge off and created a brand new whiskey. Reading my notes seems to
reflect that because they didn&rsquo;t even make any sense! They were all over the place.</li>
</ol>


<p>The representitive for this week was from <a href="https://www.tullamoredew.com/">Tullamore Dew</a>. I enjoyed his easy going nature and his more
laissez faire attitude about how to drink whiskey. Seemed like someone that would be fun to go out for drinks with.</p>

<br style="clear: both;" />


<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>The course was well worth the 160€. Now I&rsquo;m happily building up a small collection of my favourites. Because of this
course I feel that I am getting much better value for the money spent because I am purchasing the whiskeys that best
fit what I enjoy. I wouldn&rsquo;t complain about any of the whiskies I tried, but when it comes to spending your hard earned
cash, it&rsquo;s nice to know a bit about what you&rsquo;re getting. Now I just need to add the <a href="http://mitchellandson.com/redbreast-sherry-finish-lustau-edition.html">Red Breast Lustau</a>,
<a href="http://mitchellandson.com/tullamore-dew-12-year-old.html">Tullamore Dew 12</a> and the <a href="http://mitchellandson.com/spirits/spirits-category/whiskey/teeling-revival-volume-ii-13-year-old.html">Teeling Revival Volume II</a> and I&rsquo;ll have a collection
fit for any occasion. Ok, I still need something peaty like a Connemara too.</p>

<p><strong>Sláinte!</strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/whiskey/personal-collection.jpg"></p>

<p><em>This post took 12 pomodoros (and drams) to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OSX Workstation Setup Automation]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/osx-workstation-setup-automation/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-11T14:45:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/osx-workstation-setup-automation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: red;"><strong>DISCLAIMER Try out at your own risk. This setup is not meant to be copy+paste reusable. It&rsquo;s about keeping MY
workstation under source control, and this strategy may destroy the machine you wish to attempt this on.</strong></span></p>

<h2>Objective</h2>

<p>IT infrastructure has gone down a long journey of automating all of the things. We have automated deployments, production
environments, and regression testing. We can make an API request to Amazon and get a server instances in minutes. The
developer workstation is another story. Often, the developer workstation is a finely crafted machine. Just like
production, your workstation should be treated like a <a href="https://twitter.com/pcalcado/status/759218156493795329">hotel room</a> rather than an owned residence.</p>

<h2>My Setup</h2>

<p>Why bother with this for my personal machine? It serves as a good disaster recovery method. Using this automation for
the last several years (several laptops + multiple laptop repaves) has given me a lot of confidence that I know what
is required to get my machine ready.</p>

<p>There are plenty of <a href="#existing-tools">tools</a> that help with this process. What I am going to describe is yet another
approach, but I hope the simplicity of it will be attractive to those who have struggled trying to get other frameworks
to work.</p>

<p>To see what&rsquo;s included in this tooling take a look at the <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/osx-homedir#so-whats-included">Inventory</a>. Essentially you get shell configuration, some OSX tweaks, and a bunch of software installed.</p>

<h2>There&rsquo;s No Place Like Home</h2>

<p><a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/osx-homedir/">My workstation automation</a> is cloned straight into <code>$HOME</code> on a fresh machine. This is a bit different than a lot of the other <a href="https://github.com/search?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;q=dotfiles">dotfile repositories</a> you&rsquo;ll see on GitHub.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/gh-dotfiles.png"></p>

<p><code>$HOME</code> as a repository was heavily influenced by <a href="https://github.com/garybernhardt/dotfiles">Gary Bernhardt&rsquo;s dot files</a>. I really liked the simplicity of not having extra scripting to create a bunch of symlinks. Once you have your home directory cloned, you&rsquo;re already quite far down the path of having your machine the way you want it. Because it&rsquo;s a repository, when you delete a file, it goes away and rerunning your setup will not restore that file. It&rsquo;s inherently an idempotent system!</p>

<p>Another feature I like about Gary&rsquo;s setup is that uses <code>~/bin</code> scripts rather than liberal use of aliases in his shell profile. This way you really minimize the configuration of your shell. I personally dislike shell plugin frameworks like <a href="https://github.com/Bash-it/bash-it">bash-it</a> and <a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh">oh-my-zsh</a> as I believe they add complexity where it really isn&rsquo;t warranted. Keep things simple and you don&rsquo;t need frameworks to manage stuff.</p>

<p>That being said, not using a framework is accepting the trade-off of not getting the benefit of community updates. I personally like watching the community for inspiration, not for automatically ingesting their updates.</p>

<h2>Awkward OSX Settings</h2>

<p>My previous iteration of this automation was 100% <a href="https://github.com/pivotal-sprout/sprout-wrap">pivotal-sprout</a> based. If you look <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/osx-homedir/blob/9e9c6bee3e24b481c06ba0cfaffdb0e3b6ac93ff/bin/coalesce_this_machine#L14-L21">closely</a> you will see that this
automation still invokes sprout. I&rsquo;ve gone the route of using it as a collection of OSX configurations. I could maintain some of these as shell scripts, but I feel ok having this additional complexity and added dependency.</p>

<p>The configuration provided by sprout is listed in the <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/osx-homedir#so-whats-included">Inventory</a>.</p>

<h2>What Could Possibly Go Wrong</h2>

<p>Workstation automation can be extremely flaky and that&rsquo;s due to the nature of it fetching dependencies from all sorts of locations. This drives home the reason for needing to run it frequently. I can pretty much guarantee that the code that worked a month ago will not work today. Packages change name, or download locations change. This can result in a lot of mistrust of the automation.</p>

<p>Having a good routine of wiping your machine and setting up from scratch is a good way to ensure it all still works. I used to be the type that was proud of how long they could keep their workstation running and would do OS upgrades (Windows, OSX, and FreeBSD). Now I feel much more satisfied by destroying and recreating.</p>

<h2>Duplication is OK</h2>

<p>Choosing when to vendor something is an important decision to make around construction your setup. The more you vendor,
the more reproducible your automation will be. The more you vendor, the harder it is to keep up to date with changes.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/bkuhlmann/osx#os-x-el-capitan">OSX installer</a> steps is something I&rsquo;d be willing to copy and paste into my own repository. Vendoring <code>vim</code> plugins is something I&rsquo;m in favour of doing as well. The principle is that the fewer moving parts there are, the better. Even with what I believe to be a simple workstation setup, there&rsquo;s still many external facing pieces that will cause failure or tricky bugs to appear.</p>

<p>There does not exist one true workstation to rule them all. Neither is there one workstation automation method to rule them all. Your automation is going to be a somewhat handcrafted piece of art, but it&rsquo;s going to be a simple piece
of art (hopefully).</p>

<h2>Replicating This Strategy</h2>

<p>Attempting this kind of automation seems to be best grown and not copied. If you&rsquo;re starting from scratch, the first step is running <code>git init</code> in your <code>$HOME</code> dir, adding 1 precious dot file, and pushing that somewhere off your machine.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>In the end, I have a setup I&rsquo;m relatively happy with. It turns out that my implementation looks oddly similar to <a href="https://github.com/gerhard/setup">Gerhard&rsquo;s</a>, a colleague of mine.</p>

<p>This post still took way too long to write making me think that I haven&rsquo;t made it simple enough though. There&rsquo;s still a lot of moving parts and many concepts I didn&rsquo;t dive into at all (e.g.: what about my data).</p>

<hr />


<h2>Appendix</h2>

<ol>
<li><p><span id="existing-tools"><strong>Other Tools and Strategies</strong></span></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/pivotal-sprout/sprout-wrap">Sprout</a> &ndash; Intially this was called <code>pivotal_workstation</code> but transformed into a slightly more
configurable and modular system. It uses <code>chef</code> under the covers and is quite comprehensive.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/boxen/boxen">Boxen</a> &ndash; Created by GitHub, this tool uses <code>puppet</code> under the covers.</li>
<li><a href="https://osxc.github.io/">osxc</a> &ndash; Not sure where it was born from, but it uses <code>ansible</code> underneath.</li>
</ul>


<p> All three of these strive for the same thing, but use different engines. It probably makes sense to use whichever one
 uses the Configuration Management tool you&rsquo;re most comfortable with. The problem though, is that these tools may add a
 bit more complexity than is really necessary.</p>

<p> <a href="http://www.ifdown.net/">Sam Gibson</a> wrote a <a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/p2magazine/issue08/babushka/">great article</a> about this using <a href="https://babushka.me/">Babushka</a>. He believed the
 above styles are too complex and strived to find a simpler solution. I like it, but I felt that it could be
 simplified further.</p>

<p> <a href="https://github.com/gerhard/setup">Gerhard Lazu&rsquo;s</a> workstation setup. He replaced <strong>sprout</strong> with a collection to
 shell scripts that I may be tempted to migrate towards. But one thing at a time; that&rsquo;s an important principle around
 working on this kind of stuff. There are a lot of moving parts and it&rsquo;ll only prove itself out over time.</p>

<p> <a href="http://joeyh.name/svnhome/">Joey Hess</a> has been doing this since 2000 using CVS (then SVN, then git).</p></li>
<li><p><strong>SSH keys</strong></p>

<p> You are probably going to want to update your code. In order to be able to push your changes to GitHub you&rsquo;ll need to
have your keys. For this, I follow Tammer Saleh&rsquo;s excellent post on <a href="http://tammersaleh.com/posts/building-an-encrypted-usb-drive-for-your-ssh-keys-in-os-x/">building an encrypted usb drive for your keys</a>.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Baseline OS</strong></p>

<p> Technically you cannot start from scratch because you need at least an existing OSX machine to create the installer USB
stick. To do this, I followed the instructions on Brooke Kuhlmann&rsquo;s <a href="https://github.com/bkuhlmann/osx#os-x-el-capitan">workstation automation</a>*
repository.</p>

<p>When following this process, I reformat the machines disk with an encrypted volume and always create my new machine with
a different username (to ensure my automation doesn&rsquo;t make too many assumptions on pathes).</p>

<p>* <em>Similar steps worked just recently for macOS Sierra</em></p></li>
</ol>


<p><strong>For fun, here&rsquo;s the complete output of the latest run:</strong></p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
<span class='line-number'>35</span>
<span class='line-number'>36</span>
<span class='line-number'>37</span>
<span class='line-number'>38</span>
<span class='line-number'>39</span>
<span class='line-number'>40</span>
<span class='line-number'>41</span>
<span class='line-number'>42</span>
<span class='line-number'>43</span>
<span class='line-number'>44</span>
<span class='line-number'>45</span>
<span class='line-number'>46</span>
<span class='line-number'>47</span>
<span class='line-number'>48</span>
<span class='line-number'>49</span>
<span class='line-number'>50</span>
<span class='line-number'>51</span>
<span class='line-number'>52</span>
<span class='line-number'>53</span>
<span class='line-number'>54</span>
<span class='line-number'>55</span>
<span class='line-number'>56</span>
<span class='line-number'>57</span>
<span class='line-number'>58</span>
<span class='line-number'>59</span>
<span class='line-number'>60</span>
<span class='line-number'>61</span>
<span class='line-number'>62</span>
<span class='line-number'>63</span>
<span class='line-number'>64</span>
<span class='line-number'>65</span>
<span class='line-number'>66</span>
<span class='line-number'>67</span>
<span class='line-number'>68</span>
<span class='line-number'>69</span>
<span class='line-number'>70</span>
<span class='line-number'>71</span>
<span class='line-number'>72</span>
<span class='line-number'>73</span>
<span class='line-number'>74</span>
<span class='line-number'>75</span>
<span class='line-number'>76</span>
<span class='line-number'>77</span>
<span class='line-number'>78</span>
<span class='line-number'>79</span>
<span class='line-number'>80</span>
<span class='line-number'>81</span>
<span class='line-number'>82</span>
<span class='line-number'>83</span>
<span class='line-number'>84</span>
<span class='line-number'>85</span>
<span class='line-number'>86</span>
<span class='line-number'>87</span>
<span class='line-number'>88</span>
<span class='line-number'>89</span>
<span class='line-number'>90</span>
<span class='line-number'>91</span>
<span class='line-number'>92</span>
<span class='line-number'>93</span>
<span class='line-number'>94</span>
<span class='line-number'>95</span>
<span class='line-number'>96</span>
<span class='line-number'>97</span>
<span class='line-number'>98</span>
<span class='line-number'>99</span>
<span class='line-number'>100</span>
<span class='line-number'>101</span>
<span class='line-number'>102</span>
<span class='line-number'>103</span>
<span class='line-number'>104</span>
<span class='line-number'>105</span>
<span class='line-number'>106</span>
<span class='line-number'>107</span>
<span class='line-number'>108</span>
<span class='line-number'>109</span>
<span class='line-number'>110</span>
<span class='line-number'>111</span>
<span class='line-number'>112</span>
<span class='line-number'>113</span>
<span class='line-number'>114</span>
<span class='line-number'>115</span>
<span class='line-number'>116</span>
<span class='line-number'>117</span>
<span class='line-number'>118</span>
<span class='line-number'>119</span>
<span class='line-number'>120</span>
<span class='line-number'>121</span>
<span class='line-number'>122</span>
<span class='line-number'>123</span>
<span class='line-number'>124</span>
<span class='line-number'>125</span>
<span class='line-number'>126</span>
<span class='line-number'>127</span>
<span class='line-number'>128</span>
<span class='line-number'>129</span>
<span class='line-number'>130</span>
<span class='line-number'>131</span>
<span class='line-number'>132</span>
<span class='line-number'>133</span>
<span class='line-number'>134</span>
<span class='line-number'>135</span>
<span class='line-number'>136</span>
<span class='line-number'>137</span>
<span class='line-number'>138</span>
<span class='line-number'>139</span>
<span class='line-number'>140</span>
<span class='line-number'>141</span>
<span class='line-number'>142</span>
<span class='line-number'>143</span>
<span class='line-number'>144</span>
<span class='line-number'>145</span>
<span class='line-number'>146</span>
<span class='line-number'>147</span>
<span class='line-number'>148</span>
<span class='line-number'>149</span>
<span class='line-number'>150</span>
<span class='line-number'>151</span>
<span class='line-number'>152</span>
<span class='line-number'>153</span>
<span class='line-number'>154</span>
<span class='line-number'>155</span>
<span class='line-number'>156</span>
<span class='line-number'>157</span>
<span class='line-number'>158</span>
<span class='line-number'>159</span>
<span class='line-number'>160</span>
<span class='line-number'>161</span>
<span class='line-number'>162</span>
<span class='line-number'>163</span>
<span class='line-number'>164</span>
<span class='line-number'>165</span>
<span class='line-number'>166</span>
<span class='line-number'>167</span>
<span class='line-number'>168</span>
<span class='line-number'>169</span>
<span class='line-number'>170</span>
<span class='line-number'>171</span>
<span class='line-number'>172</span>
<span class='line-number'>173</span>
<span class='line-number'>174</span>
<span class='line-number'>175</span>
<span class='line-number'>176</span>
<span class='line-number'>177</span>
<span class='line-number'>178</span>
<span class='line-number'>179</span>
<span class='line-number'>180</span>
<span class='line-number'>181</span>
<span class='line-number'>182</span>
<span class='line-number'>183</span>
<span class='line-number'>184</span>
<span class='line-number'>185</span>
<span class='line-number'>186</span>
<span class='line-number'>187</span>
<span class='line-number'>188</span>
<span class='line-number'>189</span>
<span class='line-number'>190</span>
<span class='line-number'>191</span>
<span class='line-number'>192</span>
<span class='line-number'>193</span>
<span class='line-number'>194</span>
<span class='line-number'>195</span>
<span class='line-number'>196</span>
<span class='line-number'>197</span>
<span class='line-number'>198</span>
<span class='line-number'>199</span>
<span class='line-number'>200</span>
<span class='line-number'>201</span>
<span class='line-number'>202</span>
<span class='line-number'>203</span>
<span class='line-number'>204</span>
<span class='line-number'>205</span>
<span class='line-number'>206</span>
<span class='line-number'>207</span>
<span class='line-number'>208</span>
<span class='line-number'>209</span>
<span class='line-number'>210</span>
<span class='line-number'>211</span>
<span class='line-number'>212</span>
<span class='line-number'>213</span>
<span class='line-number'>214</span>
<span class='line-number'>215</span>
<span class='line-number'>216</span>
<span class='line-number'>217</span>
<span class='line-number'>218</span>
<span class='line-number'>219</span>
<span class='line-number'>220</span>
<span class='line-number'>221</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>~ ? coalesce_this_machine
</span><span class='line'>~/workspace/sprout-wrap ~
</span><span class='line'>Rubygems 2.0.14.1 is not threadsafe, so your gems will be installed one at a time. Upgrade to Rubygems 2.1.0 or higher to enable parallel gem installation.
</span><span class='line'>Using rake 10.5.0
</span><span class='line'>Using awesome_print 1.6.1
</span><span class='line'>Using builder 3.2.2
</span><span class='line'>Using mixlib-config 2.2.1
</span><span class='line'>Using mixlib-shellout 2.2.5
</span><span class='line'>Using libyajl2 1.2.0
</span><span class='line'>Using hashie 2.1.2
</span><span class='line'>Using mixlib-log 1.6.0
</span><span class='line'>Using rack 1.6.4
</span><span class='line'>Using uuidtools 2.1.5
</span><span class='line'>Using diff-lcs 1.2.5
</span><span class='line'>Using erubis 2.7.0
</span><span class='line'>Using highline 1.7.8
</span><span class='line'>Using rspec-support 3.4.1
</span><span class='line'>Using mixlib-cli 1.5.0
</span><span class='line'>Using net-ssh 2.9.2
</span><span class='line'>Using ffi 1.9.10
</span><span class='line'>Using ipaddress 0.8.2
</span><span class='line'>Using systemu 2.6.5
</span><span class='line'>Using wmi-lite 1.0.0
</span><span class='line'>Using plist 3.1.0
</span><span class='line'>Using proxifier 1.0.3
</span><span class='line'>Using coderay 1.1.0
</span><span class='line'>Using method_source 0.8.2
</span><span class='line'>Using slop 3.6.0
</span><span class='line'>Using multi_json 1.11.2
</span><span class='line'>Using net-telnet 0.1.1
</span><span class='line'>Using sfl 2.2
</span><span class='line'>Using syslog-logger 1.6.8
</span><span class='line'>Using mini_portile2 2.0.0
</span><span class='line'>Using rufus-lru 1.0.5
</span><span class='line'>Using polyglot 0.3.5
</span><span class='line'>Using yajl-ruby 1.2.1
</span><span class='line'>Using thor 0.19.1
</span><span class='line'>Using minitar 0.5.4
</span><span class='line'>Using bundler 1.13.2
</span><span class='line'>Using chef-config 12.6.0
</span><span class='line'>Using ffi-yajl 2.2.3
</span><span class='line'>Using rspec-core 3.4.1
</span><span class='line'>Using rspec-expectations 3.4.0
</span><span class='line'>Using rspec-mocks 3.4.1
</span><span class='line'>Using net-ssh-gateway 1.2.0
</span><span class='line'>Using net-scp 1.2.1
</span><span class='line'>Using pry 0.10.3
</span><span class='line'>Using gherkin 2.12.2
</span><span class='line'>Using nokogiri 1.6.7.2
</span><span class='line'>Using treetop 1.6.3
</span><span class='line'>Using librarian 0.1.2
</span><span class='line'>Using chef-zero 4.4.2
</span><span class='line'>Using ohai 8.8.1
</span><span class='line'>Using rspec_junit_formatter 0.2.3
</span><span class='line'>Using rspec-its 1.2.0
</span><span class='line'>Using mixlib-authentication 1.4.0
</span><span class='line'>Using rspec 3.4.0
</span><span class='line'>Using net-ssh-multi 1.2.1
</span><span class='line'>Using specinfra 2.50.3
</span><span class='line'>Using foodcritic 6.0.0
</span><span class='line'>Using serverspec 2.29.1
</span><span class='line'>Using chef 12.6.0
</span><span class='line'>Using librarian-chef 0.0.4
</span><span class='line'>Using soloist 1.0.3
</span><span class='line'>Bundle complete! 3 Gemfile dependencies, 61 gems now installed.
</span><span class='line'>Use `bundle show [gemname]` to see where a bundled gem is installed.
</span><span class='line'>Installing build-essential (2.2.4)
</span><span class='line'>Installing dmg (2.3.0)
</span><span class='line'>Installing homebrew (2.0.5)
</span><span class='line'>Installing osx (0.1.0)
</span><span class='line'>Installing sprout-base (0.3.0)
</span><span class='line'>Installing sprout-osx-settings (0.1.0)
</span><span class='line'>Installing sprout-osx-apps (0.1.0)
</span><span class='line'>Password:
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:06+01:00] INFO: Forking chef instance to converge...
</span><span class='line'>Starting Chef Client, version 12.6.0
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:06+01:00] INFO: *** Chef 12.6.0 ***
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:06+01:00] INFO: Chef-client pid: 14253
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Setting the run_list to ["sprout-base", "sprout-osx-settings::defaults_fast_key_repeat_rate", "sprout-osx-settings::function_keys", "sprout-osx-settings::screensaver", "sprout-osx-settings::set_menubar_clock_format", "sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences"] from CLI options
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Run List is [recipe[sprout-base], recipe[sprout-osx-settings::defaults_fast_key_repeat_rate], recipe[sprout-osx-settings::function_keys], recipe[sprout-osx-settings::screensaver], recipe[sprout-osx-settings::set_menubar_clock_format], recipe[sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences]]
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Run List expands to [sprout-base, sprout-osx-settings::defaults_fast_key_repeat_rate, sprout-osx-settings::function_keys, sprout-osx-settings::screensaver, sprout-osx-settings::set_menubar_clock_format, sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences]
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Starting Chef Run for Meriadocs-MacBook-Air.local
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Running start handlers
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Start handlers complete.
</span><span class='line'>Compiling Cookbooks...
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: /Users/merry
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] WARN: Cloning resource attributes for osx_defaults[adjusts dock size to ] from prior resource (CHEF-3694)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] WARN: Previous osx_defaults[adjusts dock size to ]: /Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/sprout-osx-settings/recipes/dock_preferences.rb:24:in `from_file'
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] WARN: Current  osx_defaults[adjusts dock size to ]: /Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/sprout-osx-settings/recipes/dock_preferences.rb:31:in `from_file'
</span><span class='line'>Converging 17 resources
</span><span class='line'>Recipe: sprout-base::var_chef_cache
</span><span class='line'>  * directory[/var/chef/cache] action create[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing directory[/var/chef/cache] action create (sprout-base::var_chef_cache line 3)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>Recipe: sprout-osx-settings::defaults_fast_key_repeat_rate
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[set key repeat rate] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[set key repeat rate] action write (sprout-osx-settings::defaults_fast_key_repeat_rate line 1)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[set key repeat rate - /Users/merry/Library/Preferences/.GlobalPreferences - KeyRepeat] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[set key repeat rate - /Users/merry/Library/Preferences/.GlobalPreferences - KeyRepeat] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>1
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: execute[Guard resource] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'> (skipped due to not_if)
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[set initial key repeat delay] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[set initial key repeat delay] action write (sprout-osx-settings::defaults_fast_key_repeat_rate line 8)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[set initial key repeat delay - /Users/merry/Library/Preferences/.GlobalPreferences - InitialKeyRepeat] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[set initial key repeat delay - /Users/merry/Library/Preferences/.GlobalPreferences - InitialKeyRepeat] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>15
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: execute[Guard resource] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'> (skipped due to not_if)
</span><span class='line'>Recipe: sprout-osx-settings::function_keys
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[Turn on function-keys-work-as-function keys] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[Turn on function-keys-work-as-function keys] action write (sprout-osx-settings::function_keys line 5)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[Turn on function-keys-work-as-function keys - /Users/merry/Library/Preferences/.GlobalPreferences - com.apple.keyboard.fnState] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Turn on function-keys-work-as-function keys - /Users/merry/Library/Preferences/.GlobalPreferences - com.apple.keyboard.fnState] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: execute[Turn on function-keys-work-as-function keys - /Users/merry/Library/Preferences/.GlobalPreferences - com.apple.keyboard.fnState] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    - execute defaults write /Users/merry/Library/Preferences/.GlobalPreferences com.apple.keyboard.fnState -boolean true
</span><span class='line'>  * ruby_block[Fix Function Keys] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:20+01:00] INFO: Processing ruby_block[Fix Function Keys] action run (sprout-osx-settings::function_keys line 13)
</span><span class='line'>merry             275   0.0  0.5  2611920  40944   ??  S    Sat06pm   7:11.60 /System/Library/CoreServices/SystemUIServer.app/Contents/MacOS/SystemUIServer
</span><span class='line'>157:242: execution error: access for assistive devices is NOT enabled! (This is not an error, just a warning) (-2700)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: ruby_block[Fix Function Keys] called
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    - execute the ruby block Fix Function Keys
</span><span class='line'>Recipe: sprout-osx-settings::screensaver
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[ask for password when screen is locked] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[ask for password when screen is locked] action write (sprout-osx-settings::screensaver line 1)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[ask for password when screen is locked - com.apple.screensaver - askForPassword] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[ask for password when screen is locked - com.apple.screensaver - askForPassword] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>1
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: execute[Guard resource] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'> (skipped due to not_if)
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[wait 60 seconds between screensaver & lock] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[wait 60 seconds between screensaver & lock] action write (sprout-osx-settings::screensaver line 7)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[wait 60 seconds between screensaver & lock - com.apple.screensaver - askForPasswordDelay] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[wait 60 seconds between screensaver & lock - com.apple.screensaver - askForPasswordDelay] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: execute[wait 60 seconds between screensaver & lock - com.apple.screensaver - askForPasswordDelay] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    - execute defaults write com.apple.screensaver askForPasswordDelay -float 60.0
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[set screensaver timeout] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[set screensaver timeout] action write (sprout-osx-settings::screensaver line 19)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[set screensaver timeout - ByHost/com.apple.screensaver.E30179FA-16E3-5588-9F5E-127D843E0F27 - idleTime] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[set screensaver timeout - ByHost/com.apple.screensaver.E30179FA-16E3-5588-9F5E-127D843E0F27 - idleTime] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>600
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: execute[Guard resource] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'> (skipped due to not_if)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[set display, disk and computer sleep times] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[set display, disk and computer sleep times] action run (sprout-osx-settings::screensaver line 26)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: execute[set display, disk and computer sleep times] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    - execute pmset -a displaysleep 20 disksleep 15 sleep 0
</span><span class='line'>Recipe: sprout-osx-settings::set_menubar_clock_format
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[turn on date & seconds for menubar clock] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[turn on date & seconds for menubar clock] action write (sprout-osx-settings::set_menubar_clock_format line 2)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[turn on date & seconds for menubar clock - com.apple.menuextra.clock - DateFormat] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[turn on date & seconds for menubar clock - com.apple.menuextra.clock - DateFormat] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>MMM d  HH:mm:ss
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: execute[Guard resource] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'> (skipped due to not_if)
</span><span class='line'>Recipe: sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[set dock to be on left] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[set dock to be on left] action write (sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences line 3)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[set dock to be on left - com.apple.dock - orientation] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[set dock to be on left - com.apple.dock - orientation] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>left
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: execute[Guard resource] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'> (skipped due to not_if)
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[set dock autohide to ] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[set dock autohide to ] action write (sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences line 10)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[set dock autohide to  - com.apple.dock - autohide] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[set dock autohide to  - com.apple.dock - autohide] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: execute[set dock autohide to  - com.apple.dock - autohide] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    - execute defaults write com.apple.dock autohide -boolean true
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[remove persistent apps from the dock] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[remove persistent apps from the dock] action write (sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences line 17)
</span><span class='line'> (up to date)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[remove persistent apps from the dock - com.apple.dock - persistent-apps] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[remove persistent apps from the dock - com.apple.dock - persistent-apps] action run (/Users/merry/workspace/sprout-wrap/cookbooks/osx/providers/defaults.rb line 4)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[Guard resource] action run (dynamically defined)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: execute[remove persistent apps from the dock - com.apple.dock - persistent-apps] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    - execute defaults write com.apple.dock persistent-apps -array
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[adjusts dock size to ] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[adjusts dock size to ] action write (sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences line 24)
</span><span class='line'> (skipped due to only_if)
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[adjusts dock size to ] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[adjusts dock size to ] action write (sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences line 31)
</span><span class='line'> (skipped due to only_if)
</span><span class='line'>  * osx_defaults[toggle dock magnification on/off] action write[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing osx_defaults[toggle dock magnification on/off] action write (sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences line 38)
</span><span class='line'> (skipped due to not_if)
</span><span class='line'>  * execute[relaunch dock] action run[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Processing execute[relaunch dock] action run (sprout-osx-settings::dock_preferences line 45)
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: execute[relaunch dock] ran successfully
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    - execute killall Dock
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Chef Run complete in 1.275448 seconds
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Skipping removal of unused files from the cache
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Running handlers:
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Running report handlers
</span><span class='line'>Running handlers complete
</span><span class='line'>[2016-10-11T22:06:21+01:00] INFO: Report handlers complete
</span><span class='line'>Chef Client finished, 7/27 resources updated in 15 seconds
</span><span class='line'>~
</span><span class='line'>Already up-to-date.
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing golang
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing jq
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing mp3blaster
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing pstree
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing tree
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing 1password
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing dropbox
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing evernote
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing flycut
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing google-chrome
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing iterm2
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing selfcontrol
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing shiftit
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing skype
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing tunnelbear
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing vagrant
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing vlc
</span><span class='line'>Succeeded in installing virtualbox
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Success: 18 Fail: 0
</span><span class='line'>Last software update was 3 days ago
</span><span class='line'>Since softwareupdate ran recently, not going to do anything
</span><span class='line'>remove /Users/merry/.softwareupdate_indicator to force an update</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><em>This post took 12 pomodoros to complete (more time than it takes to setup a laptop from scratch)</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Resolutions for 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2017/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-02T13:07:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2016 was the first time I accomplished my goal!</p>

<h2>Reflections on <a href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2016/">2016</a></h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Write in a Journal</strong> &ndash; This one I am marking as a success.  Here are the (manually) calculated stats:</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>Jan 9
</span><span class='line'>Feb 3
</span><span class='line'>Mar 12
</span><span class='line'>Apr 9
</span><span class='line'>May 15
</span><span class='line'>Jun 9
</span><span class='line'>Jul 13
</span><span class='line'>Aug 14
</span><span class='line'>Sep 12
</span><span class='line'>Oct 14
</span><span class='line'>Nov 9
</span><span class='line'>Dec 12</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I wrote <strong>143</strong> journal entries over the course of 2016.  After counting them all up there are far fewer than I thought,
but the frequency is actually more consistent than I thought. I had imagined I had more months that only had a couple
entries. I see this as my first step in writing more and hopefully bringing it to this website. Seeing that my
journalling actually increased by the end of the year makes me really happy. I&rsquo;m going to continue this in 2017 for
sure.</p>

<h2>Goal for 2017:</h2>

<p>In the spirit of keeping my goal(s) simple and achievable I&rsquo;m going to stick to a similar strategy as 2016.</p>

<h3>Perform 1 Perfect Pullup</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s been many years since I&rsquo;ve been able to do a pullup. My body finally feels recovered from my previous injuries, but
it&rsquo;s certainly weaker than it&rsquo;s ever been. My <a href="http://scottmuc.com/health/">health dashboard</a> has already helped me reach a gym
going habit, but now I need to direct this routine to a different end. I cannot do the physical things I used to because
I&rsquo;ve gotten so out of shape and my previous focus on running put too much pressure on my weak body.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>As I grow older, the length of a year seems much shorter. I wonder if my previous <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/yearly-goals/">goals</a> were a result of not
acknowledging how much I can possibly do in that time frame.</p>

<p><em>This post took 1 pomodoro to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dealing With Contempt Culture in the Software World]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/dealing-with-contempt-culture-in-the-software-world/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-14T01:10:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/dealing-with-contempt-culture-in-the-software-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago I <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">left ThoughtWorks</a> and was considering leaving IT altogether.</p>

<blockquote><p>Though I’m listing things related to ThoughtWorks, a lot of my weariness is more<br/>from IT in general. It could be an age thing, but I’ve been around long enough to<br/>see a lot of terrible things going on in this industry. No one seems to care about<br/>security, and the innovation that is making billions in the stock market are consumer<br/>products that mean almost nothing to me. It’s hard to be optimistic after Edward<br/>Snowden revealed the NSA privacy issues.</p><footer><strong>Me</strong> <cite><a href='http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/'>Leaving a Dream Job and Going on an Adventure</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>After a long break and working at a couple more companies I am able to pinpoint some specific behaviours
of individuals that have an affect on my work ethic and general work happiness.</p>

<h2>Contempt Culture (in software)</h2>

<p>Recently I read an excellent post about <a href="http://blog.aurynn.com/contempt-culture">Contempt Culture</a>. What resonated so much with me was that I
remember being that way when I first started my career. I was impressionable and looked up to the veterans that I met at
conferences that appeared to me as people that knew everything. They&rsquo;ve seen it all. They would speak with such
authority on all the things and I bought it all. I didn&rsquo;t question, nor probe for reasons.</p>

<p>Nowadays I feel like my attitude is much better (friends, please correct me if I&rsquo;m wrong), but I still have a lot of room
for improvement. But&hellip; I&rsquo;m now one of those so called veterans I looked up to. I can see how much BS they were spouting
and how overconfident they were. I don&rsquo;t believe I&rsquo;m a bad developer, in fact I think I have a fairly strong skillset, but
I definitely don&rsquo;t know as much as I perceived those veterans to know.</p>

<p>Reading the quote from my previous blog post reveals the contempt that I was feeling. Do I still feel the same?
Sort of, but my energy is more focused on delivering value. It feels like a weight off my shoulders.</p>

<p>Part of me feels that <a href="http://bikeshed.com/">bike shedding</a> and the <a href="http://weblog.raganwald.com/2008/05/narcissism-of-small-code-differences.html">narcissism of small (code) differences</a>
are linked in some way. I don&rsquo;t have any evidence whatsoever, just something to ponder. It&rsquo;s easier to mock something
that differs in a trivial way. Anecdotally, I&rsquo;ve heard more criticism fired at Python because of the significance of
whitespace more than any other parts of the language.</p>

<p>Please watch this discussion titled <a href="https://vimeo.com/3536799">Why So Mean</a> from the Alt.NET Seattle 2009 open space
conversation. It does show many of the different personalities and perspectives.</p>

<h2>How it Affects Me (and how I deal with it)</h2>

<p>What I&rsquo;ve learnt is that this attitude can suck the energy out of me. When I meet an individual that exhibits these
behaviours I then have contempt for them! This is just as toxic and I&rsquo;m struggling to deal with it. I rarely engage
with these people because of the energy it takes out of me. Here are some thoughts that come to my head when I
hear dismissive comments:</p>

<ul>
<li>My friend made that! I saw what was there before and they have improved it so much!</li>
<li>If it&rsquo;s so easy why don&rsquo;t you do it?</li>
<li>You&rsquo;re wasting energy, can we focus on the problem in front of us?</li>
<li>You&rsquo;re too stupid to understand the complexity of the problem they are trying to solve.</li>
<li>If everyone did things the way you think they ought to be done, you think the world would be better?</li>
</ul>


<p>Not so healthy huh? I don&rsquo;t like having these thoughts. They drain me and dampen my motivation. What&rsquo;s worse is that I
find myself absorbing a bit of their attitude and will potentially mimic it. I don&rsquo;t know why but I get the feeling my
reaction to this is stronger than others. I wish I could ignore it, but if I could, I clearly wouldn&rsquo;t be writing this
post.</p>

<h2>Strategies for Handling Contemptuous Individuals</h2>

<p>Aurynn&rsquo;s post has a lot of good strategies to handle your own personal contempt, but what I need are ways to handle
other individuals. If I don&rsquo;t, I could see myself getting overly frustrated with the industry again.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.drmaciver.com/2015/12/on-criticizing-programming-languages/">This response</a> not only summarizes with a good list on how to deal with your own contempt but
also brought up an interesting observation about identity. The language, tool, framework
becomes an identity of sorts. However, that does bring up the point
categorizing the individual is not healthy. Placing someone in a bucket doesn&rsquo;t move things forward at all.</p>

<ul>
<li>Assume the person is experiencing imposter syndrome and is mimicing others in the field.</li>
<li>Ask why they have such a strong reaction. Try and find the root cause of the reaction.</li>
<li>Redirect the focus to the outcomes. Yes, language X has problems, but look how it is helping Y.</li>
</ul>


<p>A recent EconTalk episode titled <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2016/08/chuck_klosterma.html">&ldquo;What if We&rsquo;re Wrong&rdquo;</a> discusses in the first 10 minutes around
the utility around strong statements. Understanding the individual may better lead to why they feel the need to voice
their disdain so loudly.</p>

<p>Also that contempt culture can take many forms. This year has been full of unhealthy thoughts, but this post is
intended to speak specifically about the programming industry.</p>

<p>Clearly I need some assistance with this. Please leave a comment with your strategies. Or, if this doesn&rsquo;t bother you
much, I would love to hear why.</p>

<p><em>This post took 10 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joining Pivotal Cloud Foundry and Moving to Dublin]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/joining-pivotal-cloud-foundry-and-moving-to-dublin/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-21T21:45:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/joining-pivotal-cloud-foundry-and-moving-to-dublin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/pivotal-office.jpg" width="1024"></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I&rsquo;ve posted a &ldquo;life update&rdquo;. The <strong>TL;DR</strong> is that I have joined <a href="http://pivotal.io/platform">Pivotal Cloud Foundry</a> in
January and will be moving to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dublin">Dublin</a> in June.</p>

<h2>Reflections on Berlin and SoundCloud</h2>

<p>My guess is the most frequent question about this is: what happened? When I <a href="http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">posted</a> about my decision to
move to Berlin and join SoundCloud it appeared that I had found something I really wanted to do. Looking back at the
post you can see subtle hints of doubt, but went with the option that seemed a little more risky. In the end, the risk
was worth it as I learned a heck of a lot!</p>

<p><strong>The Awesome Stuff</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Berlin has been my favourite city I&rsquo;ve ever lived in. It&rsquo;s modified future projections of where I would like to live
long term. It&rsquo;s a city for humans with its comprehensive public transportation system, low cost of living, and its
openness to new cultures moving to the city.</li>
<li>I felt I managed to fulfill many of the goals I had set in mind in my earlier <a href="http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">post</a>. My most important
take-away is having developed empathy for those who speak English as a second language.</li>
<li>More traveling (Ukraine for Easter, Prague, London, Paris, Germany, and Switzerland). There are still so many places
to check out.</li>
<li>New friends (you know who you are)</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Not So Awesome Stuff</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Working in the media domain is very different than the public media domain. As monetization became a focus and utilizing
advertising became a core piece of it, I felt that it wasn&rsquo;t a strategy I wanted to participate in. Watching <a href="http://thoughtmaybe.com/the-century-of-the-self/">Century of Self</a>
too many times has probably made me a bit too cynical about advertising.</li>
<li>Really missed the ThoughtWorks culture around software development. I missed pair-programming and the role was more
consulting than it was software-dev (which is one of the reasons why I left ThoughtWorks). At the same time, I learned
how important it is to be aligned with the &ldquo;how we do work&rdquo; at an organisation. I can&rsquo;t say SoundCloud is doing it
wrong&hellip; there&rsquo;s just too little data to make that call. All I know is that it left me drained and unmotivated (but
has the opposite effect for many of the great engineers there).</li>
<li>I injured my hamstrings (and later my back), that definitely affected my life, but unrelated to my decision to move to
Berlin and join SoundCloud.</li>
<li>My personal possessions didn&rsquo;t reach Berlin until July which may have made the whole move feel quite transitory since
I never quite got the chance to settle down properly. I had grown the thought of leaving SoundCloud only just a few
months after my things from Canada had arrived.</li>
</ul>


<h2>What Triggered the Change?</h2>

<p>The funny thing is when I explain the work I was a part of in SoundCloud many folks wonder why I would ever leave. The
technology was interesting and we had a lot of autonomy. This was true, but when it comes to work, I&rsquo;m a process over
product kind of person. After a few events occurred I felt the urge to explore my options. I reached out to <a href="https://twitter.com/mkocher">Mathew Kocher</a>
and he said that the offer from a year ago still stands! After living in Berlin, I didn&rsquo;t have much
desire to leave the city let alone move to North America. He encouraged me to go to London and go through another round
of interviews.</p>

<p>In London I had a fantastic day of pairing interviews then a good evening out with <a href="https://twitter.com/tammersaleh">Tammer Saleh</a>. We discussed
many things about the industry (he later was a receipient of my link bombs that I often send out after an evening discussion). I was
definitely engergized about the experience but still wasn&rsquo;t decided. A few weeks later, many people came to Berlin for
the <a href="http://berlin2015.cfsummit.com/">Cloud Foundry Summit</a> and there  was a chance to meet some more people. I expressed that I love Berlin a lot,
and that I wasn&rsquo;t ready to leave Europe. Then the option of Dublin came up. It would allow me to go to SF for 3 months
and move to Ireland in the summertime. If I do want to do consulting again, there&rsquo;s a <a href="http://pivotal.io/locations/berlin">Pivotal Labs office in Berlin</a>.</p>

<p>The energy I had after the pairing sessions still was on my mind. I learned that the 3rd pillar of the company is to &ldquo;Be
Nice&rdquo; and the people I interacted with definitely seemed to espouse this value. After a few more days of discussing the
contract and some e-mail back and forth, I gave my notice to SoundCloud and accepted the offer from Pivotal.</p>

<h2>So What is Happening Now?</h2>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Ireland_Dublin_Night.JPG"><img class="right" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/93/Ireland%5FDublin%5FNight.JPG/640px-Ireland%5FDublin%5FNight.JPG" width="640"></a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s quite common for companies to have a 2-3 month notice period. So I had 2 months to finish up my work at SoundCloud
and then figure out the process for a Canadian living in Germany soon to be employed in Ireland but going to begin work
in the USA. I&rsquo;ll spare the details, but I managed to get my passport the day before going to SF.</p>

<p>After 3 weeks I&rsquo;m feeling quite good about my decision. I&rsquo;ve been pairing every single day and really enjoy the people
that I&rsquo;m working with. There&rsquo;s a strong diversity initiative as well, so hopefully the demographics of the organisation
will be just as good as ThoughtWorks. The applications for Cloud Foundry are more large scale and focused on the
Enterprise which I&rsquo;ve learned is an area that I&rsquo;m much more interested in (as opposed to start up products).</p>

<p>Since I&rsquo;ve &ldquo;lived&rdquo; in SF before I&rsquo;m not feeling very rushed. I&rsquo;m spending my days as I normally would with meeting up
with friends periodically dotting my calendar. I&rsquo;m excited about living in Dublin even though I&rsquo;ve never set foot in
Ireland before!</p>

<p>Even my back is feeling a bit better. I managed to do 2 3k runs this weekend. :&ndash;)</p>

<p><em>This post took 6 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Resolutions for 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-02T01:08:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post almost didn&rsquo;t happen. 2015 holds a lot of dead-air from me in the blogging world, but I&rsquo;m so compelled by my
routines that I felt that I had to do it! Honouring a self-made routine/tradition is my achilles heel and my biggest
strength at the same time.</p>

<h2>Reflections on <a href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2015/">2015</a></h2>

<p>2015 wasn&rsquo;t a good year for sticking to my goals, but I still learned a lot on the way:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Brew Beer</strong> &ndash; Didn&rsquo;t do well here since I didn&rsquo;t brew a single batch, but there was a lot of taste testing!</li>
<li><strong>Nurture a Healthy Habit</strong> &ndash; The year was off to a great start until I injured my leg. I attempted to get back into
running a bit too strong and injured myself again. If there&rsquo;s something positive I can take from this though is
that I still wish to run. It&rsquo;s been a very frustrating year as a result because I missed running in Berlin during
the best time of the year! I ended up gaining weight, which made me not feel so good about myself and other healthy
habits collapsed as well. The good news is that the desire is still there and I just need get back slowly.</li>
<li><strong>Think More Critically</strong> &ndash; This one is a strange one because I don&rsquo;t have anything countable to associate with it. In the
end I feel more clueless about everything. As I put a critical focus on anything it opens up complexity that I had
never imagined. Now I&rsquo;m not sure how people are so sure about anything! I need to stop listening to so many economics
podcasts ;&ndash;).</li>
</ul>


<p>That being said, I kicked arse on a <a href="http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014/">2014 resolution</a> which was to learn <a href="https://www.docker.com/">Docker</a>! Docker is a core
piece of technology in what I was working on at <a href="http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">SoundCloud</a>.</p>

<p>Looking back, 2015 was a difficult year to make such goals. I&rsquo;ve found a lot of interesting tactics on
<a href="http://jamesclear.com/good-habits">James Clear&rsquo;s article about good habits</a>. How would things been different had I set the goal to 1 run
per month? Even with my injury I&rsquo;m sure I would have been more proactive in testing the waters with a single 3k run each month.
Also, why not make the beer brewing goal a single brew for the entire year? I held back on brewing because I was
intimidated by the equipment I would have had to purchase and store. If it was one brew, I would have simply
brewed with the few people that I&rsquo;ve met in Berlin that do home brewing. Then again, it&rsquo;s easy to say that
in retrospect.</p>

<h2>Goal for 2016:</h2>

<p>This year I&rsquo;m going on a bit of a tangent from previous years. I feel I pushed 2015 too hard. It was more work than I
had anticipated. A good challenge but I set my expectations too high. 2016 is likely to be similar with moving to a new
city and starting a new job (post on that coming later this month). So I&rsquo;m only going to make 1 goal. I see it as a
realigning goal, a course correction from the journey that started when I left <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">ThoughtWorks back in 2014</a>.</p>

<h3>Write in a Journal</h3>

<p>I have the urge to write, but the public forum doesn&rsquo;t feel right. A real physical book where my text doesn&rsquo;t flow
through prying eyes wanting to find patterns, so that they can serve me better ads. I&rsquo;ve been
fairly public with my life and I&rsquo;m curious about taking that down a notch. My head feels like a swirling mass of
ideas that hasn&rsquo;t quite found its outlet (though those who have been out drinking with me when the topic of
economics comes up, would beg to differ).</p>

<p>Think of it as close-sourcing my thoughts. Once public, it&rsquo;s hard to make things private, but the other way is
certainly possible.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>A bit of a change from the usual. Let&rsquo;s see how things are in a year, shall we?</p>

<p><em>This post took 2 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make Masala Chai]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/how-to-make-masala-chai/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-26T11:22:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/how-to-make-masala-chai</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/chai/08-chai.jpg" width="300">
This is the simplest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Masala_chai">masala chai</a> recipe I know how to make. Compared to the street side chai you would get in India my
recipe differs in the fact that mine is less sweet and has a strong black tea and masala flavour (especially the ginger).
The wonderful thing about masala chai is that it&rsquo;s easy to adjust to your own taste and it&rsquo;s fun to experiment with.</p>

<p>So let&rsquo;s get started!</p>

<h3>Ingredients (for 1 mug)</h3>

<ul>
<li>&frac12; mug of water</li>
<li>&frac12; mug of high fat fresh milk (I use 3.5%)</li>
<li>&frac12; thumb (a unit I made up, but is the approximate size of a thumb) of ginger</li>
<li>3-6 cardamom pods (depending on the freshness and size of the product you have)</li>
<li>1 hand of Brook Bond Taj Mahal tea</li>
<li>1 hand of course-unrefined sugar</li>
</ul>


<h3>Other stuff</h3>

<ul>
<li>heat source (eg: stove)</li>
<li>small pot</li>
<li>strainer</li>
<li>mug</li>
<li>chopping board</li>
<li>knife</li>
</ul>


<h3>Instructions</h3>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/chai/01-ginger-cardamom-before.jpg" width="510">
<img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/chai/02-ginger-cardamom-after.jpg" width="510"></p>

<p>Cut the ginger into a few pieces and then crush/pound it so that the juices are flowing out. Using the flat of the knife
blade crush the cardamom pods so the seeds inside come out. Place these and the water into a pot and bring it to a boil.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/chai/03-hand-of-tea.jpg" width="330">
<img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/chai/04-steeping-begins.jpg" width="330">
<img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/chai/05-full-steep.jpg" width="330"></p>

<p>Just before a boil is reached throw in the tea. If the boil is too intense, turn the heat down. Too much heat applied to
the tea will cause it to taste overly bitter. The tea should naturally spread like in the pictures above.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/chai/06-add-sugar.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>After about 2 minutes, add the milk and set the heat to around medium. Add a hand of sugar now (I&rsquo;ve forgotten to add
sugar a few times so I just try to make it part of the routine at this point). Also remember that you can always add
sugar later. Since I tend to have a sweet snack with my chai, I like to have a less sweet chai to let the dessert
compliment the chai.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/chai/07-hot-break.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>After several minutes the mixture will start to foam and rise up (I like to call this the hot break which comes from
beer brewing). This means that the proteins in the milk have become denatured (ie: cooked) and this will give you the
lovely brown skin on your chai. Turn down the heat and let the chai continue to brew for a few minutes longer in a soft
rolling boil.</p>

<p>Let the tea cool for a minute and transfer it directly to a mug through a strainer.</p>

<p>Enjoy your masala chai and the fact that your garbage can will smell awesome for days!</p>

<h3>Adjustments</h3>

<p>In order to make more chai, it&rsquo;s just a matter of multiplying all of the ingredients. The limit is usually the size of
the pot. It can be hard to make a large batch when the pot is more than &frac34; full.</p>

<p>Other ingredients you can use to <strong>spice</strong> things up are:</p>

<ul>
<li>cinnamon</li>
<li>fennel</li>
<li>pepper corns</li>
<li>star anise</li>
<li>different chai (though I find Brook Bond Taj Mahal makes for the most consistent results)</li>
<li>chilis</li>
</ul>


<p>What I love of masala chai is that you have an easy method for trying out many different flavours!</p>

<p><em>This post took 1 pomodoro to complete (or the time to perform this recipe)</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Resolutions for 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-02T01:08:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This has become a bit of a tradition for me so I can&rsquo;t quite writing these now. This one will be a bit different than
the previous ones though. Normally these posts are my <em>technical</em> resolutions. I&rsquo;m not that ambitious anymore when it
comes to technical learning so I&rsquo;ve dropped that from the title. Even though I tend to despise meaningless dates, I look
at resolutions as one large <a href="http://pomodorotechnique.com/">pomodoro</a>. So the tradition lives on!</p>

<h2>Reflections on <a href="http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014/">2014</a></h2>

<p>Going on a <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a> sort of twisted everything around in 2014. Still, it was interesting to see how
I did:</p>

<ul>
<li>Increase Signal to Noise Ration &ndash; I&rsquo;m only following 118 people on Twitter now as opposed to 627, but my &ldquo;friend&rdquo;
count on FaceBook went up to 507 from 480. Considering that Twitter is where most of the noise comes from, I think I
succeeded in this goal.</li>
<li>Learn Docker &ndash; I&rsquo;ve yet to run the docker CLI, so didn&rsquo;t go far with this. I&rsquo;m not terribly interested in it now as my
frustration with tech is still there. 2015 may be a success if I still don&rsquo;t touch docker.</li>
<li>Do Meaningful Work &ndash; Does quitting my job and traveling the world for 9 months count as success? It does to me so I
think I slayed this resolution! I&rsquo;m also getting back into the <a href="http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">workforce</a> with a company that is in a domain I care
about and I&rsquo;ve gotten the opportunity to be on the board of advisors for an interesting <a href="http://zolair-energy.com/">clean energy start up</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Goals for 2015:</h2>

<p>I think the time off has given me a new perspective. These goals are more about looking at myself externally and
figuring out what kind of design changes to I want to make on myself.</p>

<h3>Brew Beer</h3>

<p>Given that I want to look into the business of beer, it would help if I&rsquo;ve actually brewed some. I believe brewing 10
batches is a reasonable goal. If I can&rsquo;t do this, then I can safely drop the idea of building a beer related business in
the future. I enjoy publishing my <a href="https://twitter.com/todayschai">chai</a> experiments and I&rsquo;ll do the same thing with my beer brewing. Will
probably publish them on this blog for now.</p>

<p><strong>Progress</strong>: 0 batches brewed</p>

<h3>Nurture a Healthy Habit</h3>

<p>Over the last 15 years of my life I&rsquo;ve ridden a health rollercoaster. I can&rsquo;t recall any year where I didn&rsquo;t go
off the routine and regress to my old unhealthy habits. This year I&rsquo;m aiming to be more proactive around my habits and
plan a bit better when I can see potential for a habit to break (eg: when traveling, or a busy period). My goal is run
at least 10 times every month. Be sure to verify my results on <a href="http://www.strava.com/athletes/6575733">Strava</a>. I am training for a half marathon but
this is very typical of my health ambitions. Do something big, and then stop.</p>

<p><strong>January</strong>: 19 runs<br/>
<strong>February</strong>: 13 runs<br/>
<strong>March</strong>: 6 runs (strained hamstring injury)<br/>
<strong>April</strong>:<br/>
<strong>May</strong>:<br/>
<strong>June</strong>:<br/>
<strong>July</strong>:<br/>
<strong>August</strong>:<br/>
<strong>September</strong>:<br/>
<strong>October</strong>:<br/>
<strong>November</strong>:<br/>
<strong>December</strong>:<br/></p>

<h3>Think More Critically</h3>

<p>This could be due to having a lot of time to consume too much media over the last year, but I feel that I should be more
thoughtful in my communication and critical of my messages. It&rsquo;s easy to type out a pithy tweet skipping a load of
context. When being critical I will do due dilligence in citing research when trying to impose my ideas, or at least be
more transparent in pointing out how much is anecdotal. This one is a tougher one to measure. The only thing I can think
of is comparing the number of tweets over the course of the years, and having source lists in all my blog posts (or
stating the source are my own observations and are completely theoretical).</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>When reading my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014/">2014 post</a> I can tell that I was getting jaded about the IT industry. It looks like I&rsquo;m still a bit
jaded, but this time I&rsquo;m steering the ship away from IT a bit. Let&rsquo;s see what these new waters are like.</p>

<p><em>This post took 2 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Months in India]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/three-months-in-india/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-16T05:21:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/three-months-in-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>September 20th &ndash; December 16th</em></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/blr-lake.large.jpg" width="800"></p>

<p>Ugh, I left this post until way too late. Unfortunately I&rsquo;ll have to drop a lot of detail as 3 months is pretty hard to
sum up in a single blog post. Hopefully I can do it justice as India is a place I&rsquo;m very fond of. I feel bad for all the
wonderful little experiences that happened and didn&rsquo;t get written about. I&rsquo;ll just have to visit India again and
properly journal the whole experience.</p>

<h3>Arrival</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/blr-flood.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/blr-flood.medium.jpg" width="200"></a>
The minute I got off the plane I was greeted with the familiar scent of Bangalore. The city gives me a bizarre sense of
being home. My arrival to India this time around is much different than the paniced call to Calgary at 4am where my
arrange pickup wasn&rsquo;t there. This time I breezed through the crowd to the taxi line and made my way to Indiranagar where
I was to stay in a wonderful <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.in/rooms/1009953">guest house</a> for the next long while.</p>

<p>It was the end of monsoon season and there was a bit more rain than last time. It was quite refreshing because it kept
the air clean for a little while. There was one evening where the road leading up to my apartment was flooded and had to
wade through knee deep &ldquo;water&rdquo;.</p>

<h3>Work Life Balance</h3>

<p>My goal in India was to finish my job search and just chill out for a little while. But first, I had to find a place
where I could hang out for most of the day to use the Internet. I first tried <a href="http://www.cobaltblr.com/">Cobalt</a> which was on Church St,
just a few minutes away from MG Road metro station. It had good Internet and there were other people around that made it
feel nice. The next day I tried <a href="http://www.beaglesloft.com/">Beaglesloft</a> as it was started by an ex-ThoughtWorker. It was a short walk from Trinity metro station, and it was decent too. A bit too quiet though.</p>

<h3>Finding Nilenso</h3>

<p>There was one more place to check out. An ex-ThoughtWorker, <a href="https://twitter.com/deobald">Steve</a> from Calgary, has lived in Bangalore for a
while and has is part of a software collective called <a href="http://nilenso.com/">Nilenso</a>. I also recommend reading his
<a href="http://blog.deobald.ca/">blog</a> as he is an excellent writer and has written some very insightful posts about life.</p>

<p>After one day of hanging out with the folks at Nilenso I had realized I had found my home. The whole group was extremely
welcoming to me. I had met Steve once before (for like around 5 minutes) and didn&rsquo;t know the others yet I now consider
them friends and will visit them every time I go back to Bangalore. They set me up with good Internet, a workstation
setup and meals! It was really hard not to apply and work with them. They also were excellent test subjects for my
<a href="https://twitter.com/todayschai">chai experiments</a></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/blr-chai.large.jpg" width="800"></p>

<h3>Pune</h3>

<p>After a few weeks I scheduled a trip to Pune to see some old friends and meet a company for a job interview. I had
Internet issues at the place I was staying at so I had to go to Starbucks nearly everyday for interviews and other
correspondance.</p>

<p>The job interview went really well, but declined to pursue the job any further as it felt like it would be ThoughtWorks
part 2. I used the down time to write a couple blog posts and do a little cooking.</p>

<h3>Chennai</h3>

<p>I wanted to meet some friends in Chennai as well so I did another short outing to see them. Besides eating awesome South
Indian food all day long I collaborated with <a href="https://twitter.com/rdsubhas">Subhas Dandapani</a> on <a href="http://www.devopsbookmarks.com/">devopsbookmarks.com</a>. All I
really did was &ldquo;project manage&rdquo; and Subhas essentially did all the work.</p>

<h3>Beer Tour</h3>

<p>Bangalore has a beer scene that&rsquo;s growing strong. In this trip alone I was able to visit 10 brewpubs and that&rsquo;s not
hitting them all!</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://toit.in/">Toit</a> &ndash; Definitely one of my favourites. I think I went there at least once a week. I highly recommend their
weiss beer.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.murphysbrewhouse.in/">Murphy&rsquo;s</a> &ndash; Only went their once for lunch. None of their beers really stood out to me. I regret not going
again because the view is quite nice.</li>
<li><a href="http://windmillscraftworks.com/">Windmills</a> &ndash; Overall, I think Windmills makes the best beer in Bangalore. It&rsquo;s a bit of a trek because
it&rsquo;s all the way in Whitefield.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.barleyz.com/">Barleyz</a> &ndash; The beer isn&rsquo;t that great, but the rooftop terrace is a good reason to go there. All the beers
tasted too watery.</li>
<li><a href="http://thebiereclub.com/">Biere Club</a> &ndash; A decent spot with decent beers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.arborbrewing.com/locations/india/">Arbor</a> &ndash; Arbor always shows up as the place to go for the best beer in Bangalore. I do think the beer is ok,
but it&rsquo;s not even close to Windmills in quality. I also found their beer gave me an allergic reaction. The beer is not
filtered and I know sometimes that can affect me, but it was more pronounced there.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/VapourBangalore">Vapour</a> &ndash; I ignored this spot for a while due to people around me saying it wasn&rsquo;t very good. While not all
beers were of consistent quality, the red ale was pretty good and their weiss beer was decent too. It&rsquo;s also a nice
roof top patio that serves decent food.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/Bigpitcher">Big Pitcher</a> &ndash; A giant establishment. Only checked it out once. There were a couple decent beers, but
the others tasted really off.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.brewsky.in/">Brewsky</a> &ndash; Best IPA I&rsquo;ve had in India. The dunkel was also really good, but the rest were quite bad.</li>
<li><a href="http://prost.in/">Prost</a> &ndash; I&rsquo;ve heard mixed reviews about the beers, but I found them to be pretty good. The Big Ben ale reminds
me a lot of the English Bay Pale Ale, which is an old favourite of mine. Their stout is quite good too, which is a
beer that doesn&rsquo;t seem to get much love in other Bangalore pubs.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Pun Town</h3>

<p>One of the reasons why Bangalore is close to my heart has to be their love of puns. Here are some of the stores that
were within 1km of where I was staying:</p>

<ul>
<li>Blind Love</li>
<li>Berry&#8217;ed Alive</li>
<li>Phobidden Fruit</li>
<li>Wearhouse</li>
<li>Infinitea</li>
<li>Chaipatty</li>
</ul>


<h3>Oh, and I Got a Job!</h3>

<p>Over the course of a few months I had interviewed with several companies. It was interesting trying to manage all of
this while moving around and being in terribly inconvenient time zones. I&rsquo;ve already <a href="http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">written</a> and huge post
about the job hunt process. Now I have a blog that if read in order really doesn&rsquo;t make any sense.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>All and all, this trip to India is a very stark contrast compared to my previous visit. I didn&rsquo;t do a whole lot of
traveling. It was really a low-key retreat so that I could do lots of reading, podcast listening, computering, and
reflecting. Sort of makes me wish I wrote about my previous trip because that one was definitely a lot more things going
on, but this trip was exactly what I needed/wanted.</p>

<p>*This post took an unknown number of pomodoros because I lack discipline :&ndash;( *</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Like Running]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/why-i-like-running/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-10T05:09:27+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/why-i-like-running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://instagram.com/p/LepNTRLlIB/"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/running/venice.jpg" width="700"></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been an off and on jogger for the last 2 years, but my goal is to be a jogger for the rest of my life. For some
reason I&rsquo;ve felt compelled to journal my reasons. If one person thinks to take up jogging, then that would be wonderful.</p>

<h3>Inspiration</h3>

<p><a href="http://theoatmeal.com/">The Oatmeal</a> made a fantastic comic of his reasons for running and found that there&rsquo;s a lot of overlap. Of
course I don&rsquo;t run ultra marathons, nor have I been running for a decade, but I find this comic inspirational and I look
at it every couple months. Please read his comic, it&rsquo;s that good!</p>

<p><a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/running"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/running/oatmeal.png" width="700"></a></p>

<ul>
<li>Growing up as a chubby person I can identify with the <strong>Blerch</strong>.</li>
<li>I definitely look at running as an asset to my eating balance sheet. Dieting makes life more complex so I choose the
simple approach of not being picky about what I eat. If it&rsquo;s unhealthy, then I try to control my portion size.</li>
<li>My expectations around how I&rsquo;ll look are realistic. It&rsquo;s that I love how I <strong>feel</strong> when I&rsquo;m running. My waistline may
not change but I have become comfortable with my body when I run. If that starts meaning more to me then I&rsquo;ll add
other forms of exercise to my routine.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Simplicity</h3>

<p>One of my favourite talks is by <a href="https://twitter.com/richhickey">Rich Hickey</a>, called <a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Simple-Made-Easy">Simple Made Easy</a>. It&rsquo;s funny that I
associate a software talk with life habits rather than software. I use running to explain the concepts to people that
confuse the term simple and easy. The simplicity of running is a major reason I like it so much. There&rsquo;s very little in
the way of dependencies that you need. A decent pair of shoes is pretty much it, and perhaps climate appropriate
clothing. The only thing stopping you from doing it is your own will power. Making it harder is simply a matter of adding
distance. It&rsquo;s liberating to not own expensive equipment or have a contract with some sleezy gym. I can just put on my
shoes and run.</p>

<h3>Mood Altering</h3>

<p>I used to wonder if I exercised more when I was in a good mood, or if I got into a good mood after exercise. My personal
anecdotal experience is that people used to notice my changed mood and would ask &ldquo;did you work out, you&rsquo;re behaving&hellip; a
bit too happy&rdquo;. This has added benefits to my work and my learning. This is backed up by science in the class I took
called: <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/learning">Learning how to Learn</a> (I did a <a href="http://scottmuc.com/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/">book review</a> for it too)</p>

<h3>Encourages Good Behaviour</h3>

<p>When I make a running goal I become very disciplined around good habits. I signed up the
<a href="http://www.vattenfall-berliner-halbmarathon.de/en/">Berlin Half Marathon</a> and I&rsquo;m much more inclined to not have a 2nd beer in the evening getting up at 6am
has becoming easier and easier. I&rsquo;ve signed up for the <a href="http://jamesclear.com/">James Clear</a> newsletter and one article really
struck home with me as I build up habits. I now know that I need to avoid the <a href="http://jamesclear.com/second-mistake">Second Mistake</a> otherwise
my habit will fall apart. This gives me the allowance to miss a run and not feel like a complete failure. Instead my
mind switchs to the thought that I <strong>MUST</strong> not miss my next run. It sounds so simple and I can&rsquo;t believe I never
noticed this before in my behaviour. My habits drop when I make my second mistake consistently. Again, I like how this
concent is backed up by science. Armed with this I intend to be an off-and-on runner no more!</p>

<h3>Health?</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s odd, but the health aspects of running are a secondary benefit to me. Though a potentially
<a href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com//2014/12/03/run-to-stay-young/">real good one</a>. Then again, most of the other benfits of running are also healthy. Let&rsquo;s just say
that my aim with running is not to be skinnier and athletic, though I won&rsquo;t complain if those things happen as a result
of running.</p>

<h3>The Only Social Media Spam I Always Like</h3>

<p>We all complain about the huge amount of information that comes our way. From baby pictures, wedding pictures, or
political kibitzing, our mood affects how we ingest these pieces. For me, I can safely say that I <strong>LOVE</strong> it when
people post their fitness accomplishments. It comes across as encouraging. So I have to shout out a big thank you to
<a href="https://twitter.com/hiyasmind">Hiyasmin</a> for catalyzing this new hobby of mine. Another thank you goes to the South Africa crew (pictured below)
who egged me on to join a trail run series. If you wish to give me encouragement, please add me on <a href="http://www.strava.com/athletes/6575733">Strava</a>.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/running/trail-run.jpg" width="500">
<img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/running/trail-run2.jpg" width="500"></p>

<p><strong>People I know that run off the top of my head:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Rose</li>
<li>Frankie</li>
<li>Cengiz</li>
<li>Srini</li>
<li>Derek H</li>
<li>KK</li>
<li>Rebecca</li>
<li>Jithu</li>
<li>Zabil</li>
<li>Kai</li>
</ul>


<p>All of you, please keep pushing me! :&ndash;)</p>

<p><em>This post took 4 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Makes Something a "Devops" Tool?]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/what-makes-something-a-devops-tool/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-05T04:13:52+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/what-makes-something-a-devops-tool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The term &ldquo;devops&rdquo; has only existed for 5 years and the trend is to label your tool as a devops tool in order for it to
gain traction. When I look at the landscape of tools, most look like Ops tools, just relabeled.</p>

<p>The reason this has been on my mind is that myself and <a href="twitter.com/rdsubhas">Subhas</a> released a website called
<a href="http://www.devopsbookmarks.com/">Devops Bookmarks</a> to aggregate all the tools in the landscape. Using a <a href="https://github.com/devopsbookmarks/devopsbookmarks.com/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md">Github Pull Request</a>
for contributions results in reviewing a lot of tools and after a short amount of time I found myself second-guessing
the need for such a website. It felt that we were diluting the devops term.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a couple that I think got it wrong:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://blog.xebialabs.com/2014/04/30/taxonomy/">http://blog.xebialabs.com/2014/04/30/taxonomy/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://newrelic.com/devops/toolset">http://newrelic.com/devops/toolset</a></li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;m greatly concerned the Devops Bookmarks is going to feel the same unless context is added to support the inclusion of
the tools. It&rsquo;s why I made a <a href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops/">devops links post</a> on my blog so that I could explain a little
bit why something is included.</p>

<h3>Going To the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gemba">Gemba</a></h3>

<p>Honestly, <a href="http://www.jedi.be/blog/">Patrick Debois&rsquo;s</a> blog is a must read to get adequate context around devops. He has an
excellent <a href="http://www.jedi.be/blog/2010/02/12/what-is-this-devops-thing-anyway/">introductory post</a> (written almost 5 years ago) and he&rsquo;s made an excellent slide deck pointing
out the same concepts I&rsquo;m struggling with right now.</p>

<div style="width: 450px; margin: 0 auto 0 auto;">
<iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/9631120" width="425" height="355" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0"
marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;"
allowfullscreen> </iframe> <div style="margin-bottom:5px"> <strong> <a
href="//www.slideshare.net/jedi4ever/devops-tools-fools-and-other-smart-things" title="Devops Tools Fools and Other
smart things" target="_blank">Devops Tools Fools and Other smart things</a> </strong> from <strong><a
href="//www.slideshare.net/jedi4ever" target="_blank">Patrick Debois</a></strong> </div>
</div>


<p>In that presentation the point of articulating desired <em>Behaviours</em> is very clear. To me a devops tool is something that
promotes good behaviour if it&rsquo;s executed well. The desired behaviours are cleary represented by
<a href="https://twitter.com/botchagalupe">John Willis&#8217;</a> excellent blog post titled: <a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/2010/07/16/what-devops-means-to-me/">What Devops Means to Me</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Examples</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Chef</strong> &ndash; promotes the behaviour of automating the configuration of machines. This reduces the tribal knowledge and
provides a collaborative environment to work on this automation (because it&rsquo;s now code instead of a Word doc).</li>
<li><strong>Vagrant</strong> &ndash; enables the ability to create production like environments anywhere. All roles in the software lifecycle
work with consistent infrastructure, thus can share their improvements and feedback.</li>
<li><strong>Gauntlt</strong> &ndash; security testing for humans. Using Cucumber, security tests can be easily read by everyone and the tests
can be executed in a continuous integration pipeline.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Not Sure About These</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gitorious</strong> &ndash; is it a devops tool because having source control is necessary?</li>
<li><strong>Static Analysis</strong> &ndash; is a python static analysis tool really a devops tool? What about something like Puppet Lint?</li>
</ul>


<p>Are some tools purely dev, and some purely ops? Everything lies on a spectrum and I guess what I&rsquo;m wondering is if
devops tools are simply the ones that are in the middle of that spectrum.</p>

<h3>Moving Forward</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m torn, but I think a feature in <a href="http://www.devopsbookmarks.com/">Devops Bookmarks</a> should be a requirement to explain why the tools
is a devops tool, and what behaviours does it try to support. If no explanation is provided, then it cannot be listed.</p>

<p>Currently the website is broken down by <em>Topics</em>, but that could change to <em>Behaviours</em> and the tools can be tagged with
the behaviours that it supports.</p>

<p>Consider this a request for comments.</p>

<p><em>This post took 3 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joining SoundCloud and Moving to Berlin]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-05T13:09:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/berlin-reichstag.medium.jpg" width="900"></p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t say exactly when the job search began. It began with the creation of a Note in Evernote (great tool
for this type of task). It was much different than any other job search I&rsquo;ve done, though I haven&rsquo;t done many as I tend
to stick to job for at least 4 years at a time. The key difference with this search was that I wasn&rsquo;t working, and
wasn&rsquo;t in a hurry to find a job. This allowed me to stick to some rules and a manifesto:</p>

<blockquote><p>- Being open to being located anywhere I&#8217;ve been before, and know at least someone there<br/>- Someone I know and respect must have worked there or works there now<br/>- The company must have cloud in the name ;-)</p><footer><strong>Scott Muc</strong> <cite>Job Application Criteria</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>manifesto:</p>

<blockquote><p>- People happiness over company success<br/>- Autonomy over being embedded in a machine<br/>- Physical and mental health over product growth<br/>- Access to beer over location</p><footer><strong>Scott Muc</strong> <cite>Preferred Employer Manifesto</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Those set me up much better to see if the company was a fit for me. It remains to be seen, but I think that being open
about my job search, my principals, and not being in a rush will result in a much better mutual partnership. It was a
zero stress endevour and I wish more people had the same privilege to be more precise about the work they apply for.</p>

<p>After several months I interviewed with a handful of companies, but eventually I narrowed it down.</p>

<h2>Then There Were Two</h2>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/cloudfoundry.jpg" width="300">
<strong><a href="http://cloudfoundry.org/">Cloud Foundry</a></strong> &ndash; Creators of an open source <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Platform_as_a_service">PaaS</a> software that allows for companies to create
their own <a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a>. I&rsquo;m not too familiar with the details of the product. It&rsquo;s not like you take a
piece of PaaS enabling software for a test drive every day. Despite not being knowledgable about their product, my
desire to work with them grew as a result of their fantastic interview process.</p>

<p>Every interview required pairing and coding. For me, this delivered a clear idea on how they work and that they prefered
a show me don&rsquo;t tell me approach to interviewing (which I think is awesome). The first pairing
exercise was pretty simple and I was the navigator. As remote pairing exercises go, this was great.
Because I wasn&rsquo;t driving, I wasn&rsquo;t self-conscious about my IDE skills or typing. <strong>David</strong>, who interviewed me, was
clearly prepared and made the interview smooth and fun.</p>

<p>The other two interviews were both roughly around 3 hours long. I was pairing with someone on some small code change
they were assigned to do. Both of them were with code and libraries I wasn&rsquo;t familiar with (go lang, anguluarJS), but
I was amazed at how much that didn&rsquo;t seem to matter. I asked questions, got the gist of what they were trying to do,
and did my best to keep iterating forward as much as possible given my knowledge constraints. The pairs were fun to work
with and I appreciated how they were able to slow down to my level to include me in the process of solving the issue.
I&rsquo;ve learned a lot on how to conduct an interview from this process.</p>

<p>I came away really feeling like these were people I would love to work with. More than that, I loved their discipline in
XP practices. Working with Cloud Foundry, I could become an expert in this field. They also respected employees work/life
balance and that&rsquo;s crucial for me.</p>

<p>The job would be located in San Francisco, and the pay would reflect that, though the cost of living would offset it.
It&rsquo;s a city I&rsquo;ve lived in before and enjoyed. I have a lot of friends there and would be immersed in beer culture.
My role would be a developer working on pieces of Cloud Foundry. So it&rsquo;s an opportunity to develop my dev chops again.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/soundcloud.png" width="300">
<strong><a href="https://soundcloud.com/">Soundcloud</a></strong> &ndash; The only way I can describe it is Twitter for audio. I&rsquo;ve only used the basic recording
functionality of their service (<a href="https://soundcloud.com/scottmuc">my profile</a>) and do listen to a few podcasts that are hosted by them.</p>

<p>Their interview process felt a bit more ad hoc compared to Cloud Foundry. After the initial screening interview with
<strong>Chris</strong>, who I would correspond with during the whole process, there was a developer assignment.</p>

<p>I had a blast working on the dev assignment! I had the luxury of not having a job so I got to spend a decent amount of
time on it. I&rsquo;m unsure about my code, but what I enjoyed was the process of how I grew the solution. Something that you
can&rsquo;t really demonstrate with a code submission. A pairing interview would have been nice so I could better get to know
how they work on a problem. I never did get any feedback on my submission. It would be nice to receive some just to get
a better feel for how they review code and deliver feedback.</p>

<p>After that I had a few more interviews more related to the role that they had envisioned I would fill and that would be
a member of the <a href="http://continuousdelivery.com/">Continuous Delivery</a> team. When I heard that my reaction was on how that&rsquo;s a bit
of an anti-pattern. After discussing it with them, I could see the team that they have formed aligns very much with I
would do if I were asked to create a &ldquo;Continuous Delivery&rdquo; team. It was great to see a bit of a shared mindset.</p>

<p>The location would be in Berlin, and the pay also reflects that. Though the cost of living is lower. I&rsquo;ve visited Berlin
twice and really enjoyed the city. I only know a handful of people there, but it is closer to people I know from all
around the area. The beer culture is definitely a huge plus, and can be great if I meet up with beer brewers in the
community. Being part of a CD team that&rsquo;s breaking down a monolith should provide some valuable experience and put me in
a position to practice a lot more than I preach.</p>

<h2>What Did I Choose?</h2>

<p>Both opportunities aligned well with my rules and manifesto. After a week of thinking (<strong>cough</strong> over-analyzing) about
it, I decided to accept the offer from <strong>Soundcloud</strong>! That means I&rsquo;ll be moving to Berlin in January 2015.</p>

<p>My mind kept flipping back and forth. Initially I thought for sure I was going to <strong>Cloud Foundry</strong>. I had already told
friends that I was going to San Francisco. The professionalism of the interview process had me convinced
that&rsquo;s where I would be most comfortable.</p>

<p>One of my best friends taught me a trick when it comes to making choices. Flip a coin and assign each choice to a
side. Treat the coin as if it&rsquo;s deciding your fate. If what results makes you feel joy and happiness, that&rsquo;s the right
choice. If you sort of deep down wish that the other side won, then you pick the other one. She suggested it with this
decision and I chickened out. Though what I ended up doing had the same result. I created a poll and posted it on Twitter.
It didn&rsquo;t really matter what the results were, but I noticed something. One, I voted for Berlin. Two, I was cheering on
Berlin while the votes were coming in.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/strawpoll.png" width="800"></p>

<h3>Choosing What Scares You</h3>

<p>SoundCloud felt like the riskier and scarier option to me which usually means a greater chance to grow and learn. Don&rsquo;t
get me wrong, Cloud Foundry would been a great chance to grow and learn, but I felt that it would be focused in the
technology spectrum. There looks to be more potential to grow as a person with SoundCloud.</p>

<h3>Learning a Language (That&rsquo;s Not a Programming Language)</h3>

<p>I have a hidden life goal of learning a second language. When I was a coach at ThoughtWorks University I had some
tough experiences with learners that did not speak English as their first language. I want to feel and understand better
what it&rsquo;s like to speak another language. There&rsquo;s a lot of potential for transfer of knowledge (ooh, applying my
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/">Learning how to Learn</a> lessons already) when translating. SoundCloud provides German lessons as a benefit and I plan on
taking advantage of that perk.</p>

<h3>More F1</h3>

<p>Nearly the entire F1 calendar is accessible from Berlin! I can continue fulfilling my other life goal which is to attend
all F1 races in my life time. These are the tracks that I can reach by train or a short flight that I haven&rsquo;t attended
yet: Monaco, Sochi, Abu Dhabi, Bahrain, Spain, and Austria.</p>

<h3>Access to Beer</h3>

<p>This leads to another life goal. To break off from technology and have a business in the beer domain.
In my Evernote journal I had a grade on each company/location on beer alignment. Of course both locations are
exceptional locations for a beer fan. San Francisco had a bit of a higher score because I know people there that do home
brewing. I&rsquo;m sure I can find a home brew community in Berlin.</p>

<h3>Music/Audio Domain</h3>

<p>Working in the music/audio domain! At CBC it was awesome being surrounded by music nerds. Sorry, but I&rsquo;ll choose
music nerds over tech nerds. Especially as my interest in the tech world is diminishing.</p>

<h3>More Travel</h3>

<p>So many travel opportunities being in central Europe. I hope to visit my relatives in Ukraine and friends in
Switzerland, England, Turkey, Czech Republic, Germany, and Hungary. With 5 weeks of holidays I&rsquo;ll be exploring and
visiting as much as possible.</p>

<p>Also, a part of me doesn&rsquo;t want to live in the USA. Cloud Foundry is also in London, but I would
want to be at the hub of the product development which is primarily in San Francisco. There would have been an option to
move to London after a year though, but my decision making was based more on the immediate change.</p>

<h2>Show Me the Money</h2>

<p>At first I was really concerned about how much less SoundCloud offered compared to Cloud Foundry. I took a look at a
<a href="http://www.numbeo.com/cost-of-living/compare_cities.jsp?country1=United+States&amp;country2=Germany&amp;city1=San+Francisco%2C+CA&amp;city2=Berlin">cost of living</a> website and calculated that to get the equivalent of an SF salary in Berlin, it would
have to be 56.3% percent (eg: making $56,300 in Berlin is equivalent to $100,000 in SF). Comparing the salary I was
offered it&rsquo;s at 55.7%. So it&rsquo;s a little bit lower, but not as crazy low as I thought.</p>

<p>It did take me on a tangent and wonder why we tend to care so much about salaries (I really wish salaries were public, I
don&rsquo;t keep mine much of a secret). My hypothesis is that your salary is a concrete tangible thing, whereas how much you
spend is harder to determine. If you&rsquo;re in Berlin making $56,300 and spend $50,000, then you&rsquo;ve save $6,300. If you make
$100,000 in SF and spend $95,000, you&rsquo;ve actually saved less. Unfortunately figuring out the amount you spend is left to
discipline around budgets.</p>

<h3>What I Don&rsquo;t Like</h3>

<p>This means I&rsquo;m joining a company that is becoming more tied to the big labels and entering the advertising space. I&rsquo;m
hoping to learn more about how this system works so that I can learn to be a more educated critic.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>I just reread <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">my post</a> from the beginning of this career break. This post and that one seem to align really
well and it gives me comfort in my decision. I really love the cadence my life has had for almost the last 20 years.
Keep an eye here for my next steps 5 years from now. Wish me luck!</p>

<h5>Looking for work? Both companies are still hiring:</h5>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://soundcloud.com/jobs">http://soundcloud.com/jobs</a></li>
<li><a href="http://cloudfoundry.com/jobs">http://cloudfoundry.com/jobs</a></li>
</ul>


<p><em>This post took 9 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Siófok/Tihany, Italian Grand Prix, and Istanbul]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/siofok-tihany-italian-grand-prix-and-istanbul/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-02T08:48:21+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/siofok-tihany-italian-grand-prix-and-istanbul</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>August 30th &ndash; September 19</em></p>

<h3>Hungary for More (Siófok/Tihany)</h3>

<p>Remember the woman that I met at the <a href="http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix/">Dream Theater concert</a>? We have kept in touch and she promised to show me around the
Hungarian country side! She recommended <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_Balaton">Balaton Lake</a> area so I found a <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2522686">place to stay</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Si%C3%B3fok">Siófok</a> and worked
on scheduling a day to meet up.</p>

<p>Unfortunately the weather did not cooperate as it rained most of the time I was there. On the plus side, I picked up a
cold on my way from Ukraine and wasn&rsquo;t feeling very adventurous anyways. I spent 3 days enjoying the sound of the rain,
and watching all of the Harry Potter movies. I picked up some groceries the day I arrived and was able to be pretty
self-sufficient.</p>

<p>On the last day my cold was disappearing and the weather outlook was brighter. Just in time for my meet up with <strong>Orsolya</strong> and a tour of
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Veszpr%C3%A9m">Veszprém</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tihany">Tihany</a>. Both places had the European charm that I&rsquo;ve enjoyed so much on this trip.
The sun came out while walking around Inner Lake (pic 3 below). <strong>Orsolya</strong> explained what life is like in rural Hungary
and I shared stories of my life. My favourite question was when she asked how I planned my travels. I never really
thought about it, but I replied saying that it was just a combination of many little trips. With each little trip I had
to plan the transition to the next trip and the opened up opportunities for other little trips.</p>

<p>After the day I was feeling recovered from my cold, and happy to have a new friend. Then I headed back to Budapest to
catch a flight to Milano for the last F1 in my travels.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle2.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle2.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-tihany.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/hungary-tihany.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h3>Italian Grand Prix (Milano)</h3>

<p>Figured that I could fit one more F1 race in this trip! I used some points to get a <a href="http://www.marriott.com/hotels/travel/milit-milan-marriott-hotel/">free hotel</a> in Milano. The
commute to the race track is pretty long so I didn&rsquo;t really have much time to explore the city. <a href="https://twitter.com/sragu">Srini</a>, who went
to the <a href="http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix/">British GP</a> with me, got his <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schengen_Area#Schengen_visa">Shengen visa</a> and was finally able to explore outside
of Istanbul and the UK. He couldn&rsquo;t come to the race but we got to hang out in the evenings when our respective daily
activities were done.</p>

<p>At the race track there&rsquo;s an abundance of people playing versions of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shell_game">shell game</a> . I watched it for
a bit and thought it looked pretty easy. I played once and was absolutely sure of my pick and lost 50 euros. I realized
I got scammed and was initially upset. Then I realized why I played the game. I wanted to win some easy money; how was I
any different than the perpetrators of the scam? It reminded me that no matter how &ldquo;good&rdquo; you try to be, temptation is
always there. I thought I could win a quick buck and I was being just as greedy as the scam artists. I laugh at the
experience now, and see it as a valuable lesson. I spent some time watching these games and saw all the tricks they play
and now understand why it&rsquo;s called a &ldquo;confidence game&rdquo;. I could see ways to &ldquo;win&rdquo;, but I would be playing against a
person who plays for hours everyday. I think their confidence will win in the long run.</p>

<p>As I alluded to earlier, the commute to my seat was quite long. My record time to my seat was 1 hour and 40 minutes, but
it was 2 hours most of the time. One of the nice things about F1 is that they aren&rsquo;t too strict about what you can bring
to the track. Each day I bought food from a local grocery store. Below is a picture of my breakfast on race day (yes
beer at 9:00am, don&rsquo;t judge). Buying from the on track vendors is a complete rip-off. For the price of a couple beers, I
was stocked up for the day.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/milano-breakfast.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/milano-breakfast.medium.jpg" width="700"></a></p>

<p>As for the race, the weekend was full of awesome moments. I watched both GP2 and GP3 races, and the F1 race was full of
awesome passes. I was sitting at the first turn which is at the end of a very fast straight (<a href="http://www.formula1.com/races/in_detail/italy_928/circuit_diagram.html">circuit diagram</a>).
Hopefully this historic track doesn&rsquo;t close, but I am so happy that I got to experience Monza before anything happens to
the event.</p>

<p>Of course my travels wouldn&rsquo;t be complete without meeting up with <a href="https://twitter.com/iliasbartolini">Ilias Bartolini</a>, a ThoughtWorker I met when I
was in India. He&rsquo;s on a project in Milano and we caught up over dinner at <a href="http://www.pizzeriamaruzzellamilano.it/">Maruzzella</a>. Again, a reminder of the
network that grew out of working at ThoughtWorks is global and full of such wonderful people.</p>

<h3>Turkish Delight</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-view.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-view.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
The last leg of my European travels is a stay in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Istanbul">Istanbul</a> (<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vsQrKZcYtqg">not Constantinople</a>). There&rsquo;s a big ThoughtWorks
project there and was able to stay in <a href="https://twitter.com/sragu">Srini</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/noppanit">Toy&rsquo;s</a> apartment (picture of the view to the right).
I wasn&rsquo;t sure how long I was going to be there so it was nice to have the flexibility of a ThoughtWorker&rsquo;s accommodation.</p>

<p>The reason for the uncertain length is that I would be applying for my <a href="http://indianvisaonline.gov.in/">Indian visa</a> from here. I won&rsquo;t go
into too much detail, but the process was relatively painless. The website is horrible and doesn&rsquo;t work in all browsers,
but once I got my application submitted, the rest of the process was straightforward. In a little over a week I got my
visa.</p>

<p>At this point in time I was beginning the interview process for several organizations. Much of my time was spent doing
coding exercises and submitting them, or doing calls. I really felt things were going forward and that in some time I&rsquo;ll
actually have figured out where I&rsquo;ll be living after all of this traveling.</p>

<p>It was a bit of a mini reunion with several people too. I met up with <a href="http://davidpetersimon.com/">David Simon</a>, who I climbed Kilimanjaro
with. There was also a bit of a Calgary reunion where I met up with <a href="http://isa.io/">Isa Goksu</a> who was my roommate for
over a year and I probably hadn&rsquo;t seem him in over 2 years! When I met up with Isa, <a href="http://www.cengizhan.com/">Cengiz Han</a>
was also there, smoking sheesha. He too was in Calgary, usually complaining about the cold, yet both of them talked
about how much they miss the Calgary days.</p>

<p>Oh right, I&rsquo;m in Istanbul! In the slack time, I spent many days wandering around this incredible city. My friend
<strong>Rose</strong> has a <a href="http://adidav9.blogspot.in/2014/07/illustrious-istanbul.html">picture filled post</a> that better captures the beauty of the city (and of other European
cities I&rsquo;ve visited).</p>

<p>Most of my day trips started out at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taksim_Square">Taksim Square</a>, which was the space that the <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-22732139">Gezi Park Riots</a> took
place at in 2013. Taking the metro from where I was staying was easy and efficient. From there I went down <a href="http://istiklalstreet.org/">Istiklal Street</a>
which is a big shopping area. My first stop was <a href="http://istanbuleats.com/2009/04/durumzade-wrap-artists/">Dürümzade</a> which was made famous by <strong>Anthony Bordain&rsquo;s</strong>
visit. Let&rsquo;s just say I went there 3 times during my stay! The adana dürüm was one of my favourite meals in Istanbul.
The area is a maze of winding hilly streets and I was content to wander this part of the city for a long time. Some days
I would hangout at <a href="http://kronotrop.com.tr/">Kronotrop</a> which is an excellent coffee bar. There&rsquo;s wifi and friendly people who are
very open to helping out a tourist with their Turkish. The pictures below are of: Istiklal Street, small street leading
to Dürümzade, and outside of Dürümzade.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-large-street.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-large-street.small.jpg" width="385"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-small-street.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-small-street.small.jpg" width="224"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-durumzade.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-durumzade.small.jpg" width="385"></a></p>

<p>On another day I walk down further and crossed the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galata_Bridge">Galata Bridge</a> and navigated through all the
fishermen to the other side (pic 1 below, you can see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galata_Tower">Galata Tower</a> in the background). Once on Old
Istanbul side I follow the meandering alleys in the direction of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hagia_Sophia">Hagia Sophia</a> (pic 2 below). How I arrive there I
don&rsquo;t know because the roads go in many different directions and they are very crowded. I kept on having to back track
as I took many wrong turns. It was a lot of fun to be lost in the shuffle. Unfortunately I arrived there after the
museum was closed so I didn&rsquo;t get to see inside. Last destination was the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sultan_Ahmed_Mosque">Blue Mosque</a> which is probably
one of the most famous landmarks (hard to say because there are so many). I was lucky to arrive in between prayer times
and was able to go inside. It was so majestic on the inside that I believe I sat there for at least 45 minutes just
soaking in the atmosphere. I couldn&rsquo;t get a decent picture inside with my phone (which has been my only camera on this
trip). I did manage to get a decent snap as the sun was getting low on the horizon (pic 3 below).</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-fishing.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-fishing.small.jpg" width="330"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-hagia-sophia.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-hagia-sophia.small.jpg" width="330"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-blue-mosque.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-blue-mosque.small.jpg" width="330"></a></p>

<p>One day walking around beautiful Old Istanbul wasn&rsquo;t enough so I made another walking tour from Taksim Square. This
time, instead of going east to all the great mosques and monuments I kept on going South to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_Bazaar,_Istanbul">Grand Bazaar</a>.
Walking through the bazaar is like being transported in time. I used to think India was a sensory explosion, but this
place comes pretty close. It was also a &lsquo;90s time warp as I couldn&rsquo;t get the following song out of my head:</p>

<div style="width:660px;margin-left:200px;">
<iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/JCye7v79Tz0 " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Never have I felt so immersed in history. I&rsquo;ve seen some historic places in my travels. The throngs of people that
still populate these places made the history feel more alive. At some point I&rsquo;ll have to go back to Turkey when I&rsquo;m not
quite so traveled out and explore more of the countries beauty and friendly people.</p>

<h3>Onward to India</h3>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for my travels in Europe for nearly 3 months. I now have the idea of writing a post about the metrics of this
career break. It&rsquo;ll be a good way to close out the series. But not yet! Now off to India for a few months to hang out
with friends, and get re-invigorated about software development.</p>

<p><em>This post took 10 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Review - a Mind for Numbers by Barbara Oakley]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-26T08:05:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.penguin.com/book/a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/9780399165245"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/book.jpg" width="200"></a>
Over the last 4 weeks I&rsquo;ve been taking the <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a> course <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/learning">Learning how to Learn</a> on the
recommendation of my friend <a href="https://twitter.com/sragu">Srini</a>. The 2nd assignment in the course is to create a presentation or some
form of media to present an understanding of the topics. An accompaniment to the course is the book,
<a href="http://www.penguin.com/book/a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/9780399165245">A Mind for Numbers</a> by <a href="http://www.barbaraoakley.com/">Barbara Oakley</a> (the primary course instructor), which is a short read but very
insightful and full of references. I&rsquo;m thoroughly enjoying the course and love the concept around the assignment. This
blog is my way of trying to synthesize ideas that are flying around in my head, which is exactly the purpose of the
assignment.</p>

<p>Over my education and career, I feel that I have developed some pretty good habits. The book has confirmed some of these
habits and given me an understanding around why they work. It&rsquo;s also able to point out some flaws that I tend to
down-play, but now realize that they are habits I need to deal with.</p>

<h2>Core Concepts</h2>

<p>The material in the book (and the course) were broken up into easy to consume chunks (see what I did there?).
I can&rsquo;t really cover all of it here but these are the 3 concepts that really stuck with me.</p>

<h3>Chunking</h3>

<p>Chunks can be thought of as an abstraction around a collection of specific thoughts. When I speak to another developer
and I say that this code <em>makes a web request</em>, that is a chunk of knowledge that I&rsquo;ve developed. I could break that
phrase down and say: establish a TCP connection with the remote server, using the HTTP protocol send a GET request
message, the server will receive this and route it to an appropriate controller, the application code will send an HTTP
response, the client will take the results and render the HTML to the browser. Woah, that was a lot of detail, and
that&rsquo;s one example of why it&rsquo;s important to chunk knowledge.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/chunking.png"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/chunking.png" title="&#34;chunking&#34;" alt="&#34;chunking&#34;"></a></p>

<p>It wasn&rsquo;t mentioned in the book, but a lot of what I read on chunking looked like reaching the <strong>competent</strong> level on the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dreyfus_model_of_skill_acquisition">Dreyfus Model of Skill Acquisition</a>. I&rsquo;m now curious if <strong>diffuse mode</strong> is an essential part of
becoming <strong>proficent</strong> or an <strong>expert</strong> in a particular topic.</p>

<p>This section of the book has made me realize some flaws in the way I learn and I feel I fall into the trap called
<strong>illusion of competence</strong>. This can be caused by <a href="http://blog.coursera.org/post/93424900982/learning-how-not-to-learn">poor learning practices</a> (below), and I know I am guilty of many of
these. Speaking of the Dreyfus model, <strong>Erik Dietrich</strong> wrote an article about the <a href="http://www.daedtech.com/how-developers-stop-learning-rise-of-the-expert-beginner">Advanced Beginner</a>,
which is another great way of explaining the <strong>illusion of competence</strong>.</p>

<blockquote><p>* Passive rereading<br/>* Letting highlights overwhelm you<br/>* Merely glancing at a problem&#8217;s solution and thinking you know how to do it<br/>* Waiting until the last minute to study<br/>* Repeatedly solving problems of the same type that you already know how to solve<br/>* Letting study sessions with friends turn into chat sessions<br/>* Neglecting to read the textbook before you start working problems<br/>* Not checking with your instructors or classmates to clear up points of confusion<br/>* Thinking you can learn deeply when you are being constantly distracted<br/>* Not getting enough sleep</p><footer><strong>Barbara Oakley</strong> <cite><a href='http://blog.coursera.org/post/93424900982/learning-how-not-to-learn'>Learning How (Not) to Learn</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I&rsquo;ve been lucky to accidentally avoid some of these habits. As a computer savvy person for the last 25 years, I still
prefer taking my notes on paper. I&rsquo;ve always stressed sleep too. I&rsquo;m definitely guilty of passive rereading, but I&rsquo;m
getting much better now. Solving similar problems is another one I need to catch myself doing.</p>

<h3>Diffuse and Focused Modes of Thinking</h3>

<p><strong>Focused Mode</strong> &ndash; When the brain is in this mode, it&rsquo;s busy building up foundations of material for access later. I
like to think of it as going to the gym. You&rsquo;re exercising ideas and building up their strength. If you don&rsquo;t practice
them deliberately, they can lose strength. If you don&rsquo;t focus on concepts with discipline, you don&rsquo;t effectively
chunk the concepts. When you get up from your task and realize that a lot more time has gone by than you had expected,
then you know you&rsquo;ve been in the focused mode.</p>

<p><strong>Diffuse Mode</strong> &ndash; This is where synthesis of multiple ideas (or chunks) happens. Our brain is good at continuing effort, solving
problems, while our bodies are performing activities like going for a walk, running, socializing, and cooking. This is
why when struggling with a problem late at night, sleeping on it, usually results in some new insights in the morning.
You know when you have yesterdays problem figured out in the morning during your shower? That&rsquo;s the diffuse mode kicking in.
Using the workout analogy, this is like using your in-shape body to enjoy life: traveling, playing with your children,
fixing up your garden.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/diffuse-focused.jpg" width="400" title="&#34;diffuse vs focused mode&#34;" alt="&#34;diffuse vs focused mode&#34;">
What&rsquo;s important to understand is that both of these modes can&rsquo;t operate at the same time. I <a href="http://scottmuc.com/going-against-the-flow/">even wrote</a>
about this a while ago and this book has given me the knowledge to better understand what I was observing when I wrote
that post. As a developer, the state of flow (deep focused mode) has its appeal, but breaking that up so that you can
piece together your new knowledge is equally important.</p>

<p>Sometimes you&rsquo;ll hear someone say that they are a great multi-tasker. This usually results in an inability to focus!
If someone is a multi-tasker, then they are taking time away from the <strong>focused mode</strong> of operating, and thus fall into
the many ways <a href="http://blog.coursera.org/post/93424900982/learning-how-not-to-learn">not to learn</a>.</p>

<h3>Procrastination and Habits</h3>

<p>The topic of procrastination was very informative. The explanation of how dopamine effects long term beneficial actions
(<a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/intrinsic-motivation-and-magical-unicorns/201206/procrastination-and-dopamine-receptor-density">reference</a>) is insightful and can be used to influence how we develop habits. The book is full of
ideas on how prevent procrastination and here&rsquo;s my list of tactics:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Zero Notifications</strong> &ndash; this is an easy one for me as I already try to live a notification free life. My phone is
almost always on silent unless I&rsquo;m <em>expecting</em> a call or message. All my applications on my phone and computer have
notifications turned off. It&rsquo;s very hard to think of any reason why any notification would need immediate action.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://pomodorotechnique.com/">Pomodoro Technique</a></strong> &ndash; I&rsquo;ve been a fan of this process for a long time. Procrastination doesn&rsquo;t stand
a chance when the timer is on. I like to use <a href="http://lifehacker.com/pomodoro-one-is-a-free-lightweight-pomodoro-timer-for-1626504270">pomodoro one</a> on my laptop. There are 4 components of
developing a habit, and the first one is the <strong>cue</strong>. Starting the timer triggers me to go into a focused mode.
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/self-control.png"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/l2l/self-control.png" width="300"></a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://selfcontrolapp.com/">Self Control</a></strong> (pictured) &ndash; This application does a machine level block of the hostnames that you specify for a
specific time period. It runs outside of the web-browser so it&rsquo;ll block applications that talk to these services and
even killing the process or rebooting your machine won&rsquo;t get the hostname working again. I will use this every time
I&rsquo;m doing a pomodoro.</li>
<li><strong>Process over Product</strong> &ndash; Unless the task is very very small, the time allocated to a single pomodoro should be
process based. As of right now, I have on my task list the following: &ldquo;2 pomodoros of coursera project&rdquo;. This keeps
the focus on the activity and now the anxiety around the outcome. I don&rsquo;t know how long it&rsquo;s going to take to complete
this post, but I know if I chip away at it with time-boxes of focus it&rsquo;ll be completed before I know it.</li>
</ul>


<p>I like reading about other people&rsquo;s techniques and thought <a href="http://jamesclear.com/">James Clear</a> has a good
<a href="http://jamesclear.com/multipliers">blog post</a> and a good list. On my reading list is <a href="http://masoncurrey.com/Daily-Rituals">Daily Rituals</a> which looks very
interesting. One thing that seems clear, is that many productive people have developed a system and it&rsquo;s important to
discover my own.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I began reading the book before taking the course and immediately benefited from a process that is described in the
book. The book on its own is a fantastic resource and is an excellent compliment to the course. I really think taking the
course at the same time instilled a lot of the information far better than if I had only just read the book. I was
surprised when I finished the book because my Kindle reported that I was only 65% complete when I was at the end. Well
that&rsquo;s because the remainder is a massive collection of references of all the research that&rsquo;s been done on all of the
topics! It shows that the content is truly backed by science which is refreshing given all the anecdotal type of
information that&rsquo;s published on the Internet.</p>

<p>Reading the book and taking the course was very meta; as I learned techniques from the
book, I applied them to the course and vice versa. I get the feeling this is going to be a book that I read on a yearly
basis (spaced repetition) to continuously improve these concepts. This post could have been a lot longer, but I&rsquo;d rather
encourage you to read the book yourself and practice the exercises at the end of each chapter.</p>

<h4>Other Resources and References</h4>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://pragprog.com/book/ahptl/pragmatic-thinking-and-learning">Pragmatic Thinking and Learning</a> which is geared more towards software developers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/">HealthyHacker Podcast</a> which talks a lot about memorization techniques and developing positive habits.</li>
<li><a href="http://betterexplained.com/">Better Explained</a> Kalid Azad does an exceptional job of explaining things. In an interview in the
course he describes his method of ADEPT (analogy, diagram, example, plain English, technical).</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EzpX0TLKS9Q">Slow Tech</a>, a talk about distraction and how to be focused. After the course, the points in this video
appear well connected with the material.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.brainpickings.org/2012/04/12/john-cleese-on-creativity-1991/">John Cleese on 5 Factors to Make Your Life More Creative</a>. A comedic genius explains how he uses time
boxing to focus on his craft.</li>
</ul>


<p>1 &ldquo;diffuse vs focused mode&rdquo; picture <a href="http://tdlc.ucsd.edu/educators/educators%5Fwebinar%5Foakley5%F031213.html">http://tdlc.ucsd.edu/educators/educators%5Fwebinar%5Foakley5%F031213.html</a><br />
2 &ldquo;chunking&rdquo; picture p.56 A Mind For Numbers, Barbara Oakley<br /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - Podcasts]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-podcasts/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-16T07:29:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-podcasts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/podcast.jpg" width="300">
It&rsquo;s quite surprising that I haven&rsquo;t really brought up the topic of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Podcast">podcasts</a> on my blog considering that
I&rsquo;ve been consuming them for almost 10 years! My methods and taste have changed a lot over the years. I want a place
to point people when asked about what podcasts I listen to, and with a little more context than just a pure list.</p>

<h2>Software / Tools</h2>

<p>A podcast is such a simple concept (from the technical side) that it allows for a lot of tools and applications to be
created around the idea. Nowadays I pretty much use a single application on my phone. I&rsquo;m generally only concerned with
the mobile experience since I try to listen to podcasts when I&rsquo;m on the move and when I&rsquo;m not focusing on work. Ask me
to listen to a podcast while programming and you&rsquo;ll discover that I won&rsquo;t be able to recall anything from the podcast
(or that I don&rsquo;t do any programming). The application I use is <a href="http://www.shiftyjelly.com/android/pocketcasts">PocketCasts</a>. The homepage is full of
hyperbole and non-truthes (eg: &hellip; deliver the updates instantly&hellip;), but it&rsquo;s an alright application and fits my needs for
now. Most importantly, it allows me to export my subscribed shows as an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opml">OPML file</a> which I&rsquo;ve made
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/podcasts_opml.xml">available to you</a>.</p>

<h2>The List</h2>

<p>Podcasts are a great way to tap into interests of all different types. You&rsquo;ll notice that only a few are related to my
professional life. Listening to podcasts is a wonderful activity and I do get a lot out of them, there becomes a point
where you&rsquo;ve found too much good content and there isn&rsquo;t enough time to listen to them all.</p>

<h2>Economics</h2>

<h3><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/rss.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/econtalk.jpg" width="200">
I begun listening to this show at the beginning of my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a>. The
host, <a href="http://russroberts.info/">Russ Roberts</a>, does a great job of letting the guests speak without pushing his views too often.
It&rsquo;s honestly changed how I think about problems in the world and how to best approach them. Economics is becoming a
tool that I use to help me understand how things are, and how to possibly alter them. The talks are well balanced and
help me see the other side of issues that I normally don&rsquo;t think of. When a new episode appears I look forward to
listening to it regardless of the topic!</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/charles_marohn.html">Charles Marohn on Strong Towns, Urban Development, and the Future of American Cities</a> &ndash; Conversations
around city design always fascinates me. There&rsquo;s a spectrum of that&rsquo;s a lot harder to accomplish than most people
realize. Living in an overly-designed city can be soul crushing, and a zero designed city can be too stressful.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/yuval_levin_on.html">Yuval Levin on Burke, Paine, and the Great Debate</a> &ndash; The difference between the right and left had been
something I hadn&rsquo;t thought deeply about. This conversation made me realize I&rsquo;m more right thinking than I thought. It
also made me understand that neither are &ldquo;bad&rdquo;.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/09/martha_nussbaum.html">Martha Nussbaum on Creating Capabilities and GDP</a> &ndash; There are other conversations around GDP, but this one
really stood out to me. I think Martha does an exceptional job of explaining how GDP is not a sufficient metric and
that we still have a long way to go to get people to the top of Maslow&rsquo;s Hierarchy.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/freakonomics-radio/">Freakonomics Radio</a><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/freakonomicsradio"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/freakonomics.jpg" width="200">
Sometimes hit or miss. Strives to be entertaining more than educational
sometimes, but overall the content is quite good. I identify a bit with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steven_Levitt">Steve Levitt</a> as he&rsquo;s more of an
intrespective quiet person.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/09/04/regulate-this-a-new-freakonomics-radio-podcast/">Regulate This!</a> &ndash; As a user of services like Uber and Airbnb, it&rsquo;s interesting to hear the issues that
these services raise. I find myself leaning towards the side of less regulation, but I still can&rsquo;t figure out where
the balance is. The term &ldquo;sharing economy&rdquo; also drives me nuts, because sharing implies no charge to me. These are
just peer-to-peer market places enabled by technology.</li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/09/25/fitness-apartheid-a-new-freakonomics-radio-podcast/">Fitness Apartheid</a> &ndash; An excellent example of how too little thought around a problem can lead to
bad consequences. It brings the concerns of both sides together and makes the listener understand that nothing is ever
as simple as you think it ought to be.</li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/05/29/the-upside-of-quitting-a-freakonomics-radio-rebroadcast/">The Upside of Quitting</a> &ndash; Very fitting for my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/06/05/failure-is-your-friend-a-new-freakonomics-radio-podcast/">Failure is your Friend</a> &ndash; A follow up to the previous episode.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/">Planet Money</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510289"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/planetmoney.png" width="200">
Short and to the point episodes that focus on very specific topics or issues. I
like this show because the pieces are bite-sized and frequently released. I find myself listening to this show when I
have to wait 15 minutes before something.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2014/09/26/351515481/episode-571-why-raising-money-for-ebola-is-hard">Why Raising Money for Ebola is Hard</a> &ndash; Excellent insights around why we give, and the pychology of charity.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2014/08/22/342232976/episode-562-a-mall-divided">A Mall Divided</a> &ndash; A peak into how economic policy can distrupt small businesses.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2014/07/11/330680385/episode-552-blockbusters-bombs-and-the-price-of-a-ticket">Blockbusters, Bombs, and the Price of a Ticket</a> &ndash; I had never put much thought into the cost of a movie
ticket, this episode explains all the details of why tickets cost the same regardless if it&rsquo;s sold-out or empty.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://mercatus.org/conversations-with-tyler">Conversations with Tyler</a><a href="http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:146429914/sounds.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/cwt.jpg" width="200">
A new one that I just got into. It&rsquo;s a bit more candid than EconTalk and more accessible. The guests are of the same
caliber and sometimes the Q&amp;A at the end can add interesting tidbits that may not neccessarily come up during an
interview.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/conversations-with-tyler/jeffrey-sachs-on-the-future-of-economic-development-2650c27b2776#.utox5d73q">Jeffrey Sachs</a> &ndash; I&rsquo;ve only listened to a few and they are all excellent but this one stands out because I
found Jeffrey Sachs inspires me a little bit. Instead of shrugging his shoulders and pointing out how all the terrible
things in the world can be explained by value functions and rational behaviour, he uses that knowledge to learn how to
tweak these systems. He&rsquo;s an interesting balance of idealist and a realist and I find that refreshing compared to
other economic speakers I&rsquo;ve listened to.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02nrss1">BBC More or Less</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02nrss1/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/bbc-mol.jpg" width="200">
This show takes a deeper look around statistics. It does the deeper critical view so you don&rsquo;t have to. Listening to
this makes me trust reports even less. Spin is such a problem and how information is presented requires a lot of effort
to reveal a non-biased presentation.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p03k2stg">When £10,000 Isn&rsquo;t a Good Incentive</a> &ndash; As a snooker fan I thought this was an interesting story of a
straightforward incentive behaviour.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p03lj18n">Fact Checking The Big Short</a> &ndash; I really enjoyed the movie <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1596363/">The Big Short</a> and the
timing of this episode was really good as I had just watched it.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006sz6t">BBC The Bottom Line</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006sz6t/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/bbc-bottom-line.jpg" width="200">
Provides a focus on what makes a business successful. It&rsquo;s a domain that I don&rsquo;t really have a clue. I find myself
wanting to be closer to the business in the work I do day to day so this has been good at introducing me to what
executives think about.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b070hns6">Data Privacy</a> &ndash; As someone on the sidelines watching the privacy debates from a technologist, it&rsquo;s
important to learn how these topics are perceived from a business owner level.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b0745q4l">Life After a Blockbuster</a> &ndash; The story about Angry Birds was fascinating. It reveals how often
the success we put on a pedestal comes from consistent tenanicity.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://podcast.ft.com/s/ft-alphachat/">FT Alphachat</a><a href="http://rss.acast.com/ft-alphachat"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/ft-alphachat.png" width="200">
Currently just trying this one out. Don&rsquo;t really have much to say about it at this point. It&rsquo;s more conversational than
some of the other business/economic podcasts.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/slate_money.html">Slate Money</a><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/SlateMoney"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/slate-money.png" width="200">
Yet another podcast that talks about world events and how they affect the economy. Each episode covers 2-4 topics. This
is starting become one of my required listening podcasts to stay informed about current events. The hosts discuss the
economics in a way that&rsquo;s targetted for people who don&rsquo;t know all the lingo.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/slate_money/2016/08/slate_money_takes_on_epipen_passive_investing_and_hedge_funds.html">The Worse than Marxism Edition</a> &ndash; As someone interested (and doing) passive investing, I wanted to
hear what they had to say about it.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/slate_money/2016/08/slate_money_on_three_of_today_s_top_online_products.html">The Product Edition</a> &ndash; Anything with Paul Ford is great to listen to. He has a nice down-to-earth
style of describing what Product Development is all about.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/slate_money/2016/06/slate_money_on_microsoft_s_acquisition_of_linkedin.html">The I&rsquo;d Like to Add You to my Professional Network Edition</a> &ndash; Another Paul Ford episode and it was
interesting to hear the conversation about the reasoning as to why such a massive purchase could happen.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hard-pass/id1090135741?mt=2">Hard Pass</a><a href="http://rss.acast.com/hardpass"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/hardpass.jpg" width="200">
I learned about Linette Lopez from the Slate Money podcast and really liked her style. She&rsquo;s punchy
and tells it like it is. Hard Pass is a good low-dose entertaining podcast about the business and
econmics news of the day. The episodes are so short that it&rsquo;s easy to digest any time.</p>

<hr />

<h3>Politics and World News</h3>

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006r4vz">BBC Analysis</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006r4vz/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/bbc-analysis.jpg" width="200">
For once it&rsquo;s nice to listen to something that isn&rsquo;t about US politics. I started listening to economic podcasts to
understand more of the world around me. Now it&rsquo;s pointing me in the direction of politics. This show is interesting to
hear about how ideas and policies gets introduced to society. They tackle some difficult issues as well which makes it a
bit heavier than some of the other lighter podcasts I have listed here.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b072j3g6">The End of Free</a> &ndash; I&rsquo;ve been incorporating ad blocking daily for over a decade. It was fascinating to
hear how it&rsquo;s hit a point where this practice is getting attention. Brands just want to engage with you! Why are we
being so mean to them!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p03qvxgb">Free Speech</a> &ndash; This is the first for a 4 part series. It asks the questions around the trade offs of
free speech. I find myself conflicted and tripping over my own thoughts on what should be allowed. Learning the types
of nullifiers to free speech I found interesting too.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://podcast.ft.com/s/world-weekly-with-gideon-rachman/">FT World Weekly</a><a href="http://rss.acast.com/ft-world-weekly"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/ft-worldweekly.png" width="200">
Another good source for global news how it influences the world markets. Can&rsquo;t really say I have any favourites, but I
do like how it&rsquo;s not just US news.</p>

<hr />

<h3>Culture and Curiosities</h3>

<h3><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/">99% Invisible</a><a href="http://feeds.99percentinvisible.org/99percentinvisible"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/99pi.png" width="200">
Now one of my favourites. You never know what to expect with this show because the
enigmatic host, <a href="https://twitter.com/romanmars">Roman Mars</a>, always finds something interesting that you likely have no idea about.
Roman started a group called <a href="http://www.radiotopia.fm/">Radiotopia</a> which is a collective of like minded artists to create
exceptional podcasts.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites (all of them):</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/thomassons/">Thomassons</a> &ndash; I dare you to listen to this episode and not look for Thomassons wherever you go!</li>
<li><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/the-straight-line-is-a-godless-line/">The Straight Line is a Godless Line</a> &ndash; Given that I was in Vienna and saw the Hundertwasserhaus, it
was very interesting to hear more about the architect. I love the fact that people like him exist, though I may not
want to completely follow his lead.</li>
<li><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/clean-trains/">Clean Trains</a> &ndash; There are so many applications to the lesson of this episode. Frequent and consistent
feedback is necessary to promote any change.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.radiolab.org/">RadioLab</a><a href="http://feeds.wnyc.org/radiolab"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/radiolab.png" width="200">
One of the pioneers in story-telling podcasts. I&rsquo;ve been away from it for a while and have re-subscribed as I&rsquo;ve been
missing the excellent stories.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.radiolab.org/story/91500-emergence/">Emergence</a> &ndash; This episode is from 2007 and it still comes up as one
of the more influencial podcast episodes I&rsquo;ve listened to. I&rsquo;m a control freak and find the concept of emergence hard
to understand. A top-down controller is easier for me to understand. This episode reminds me to rethink how things
ought to be and be more flexible.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://toe.prx.org/">Theory of Everything</a><a href="http://feeds.prx.org/toe"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/toe.jpg" width="200">
A member of the <a href="http://www.radiotopia.fm/">Radiotopia</a> collective. Just started getting into this podcast recently.
I&rsquo;m already becoming a huge fan!</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://toe.prx.org/2014/11/paying-for-it-the-dislike-club-part-ii/">Paying For It</a> &ndash; This is part of a series called
&ldquo;Dislike Club&rdquo; which is focusing on the Internet. This episode calls to attention the problems happening with todays
monetization of the web through advertising. It sums up so many of the thoughts I&rsquo;ve had about technology recently.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/">Stuff You Should Know</a><a href="http://www.howstuffworks.com/podcasts/stuff-you-should-know.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/sysk.jpg" width="200">
An exceptional podcast hosted by two charismatic people. Normally I find tangents in podcasts to be distracting, but for
some reason these two often make it worthwhile. They cover a myriad of topics and they make the most mundane seem
fascinating. There are many excellent episodes but the following ones really stood out for me.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The two part series (<a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/podcasts/the-dark-origins-of-fairy-tales.htm">episode 1</a> <a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/podcasts/how-grimms-fairy-tales-work.htm">episode 2</a>) is a wonderful explanation of the origins of fairy tales
and how dark the originally were. The Juniper Tree one is quite horrifying.</li>
<li>Another two part series one <a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/podcasts/josh-and-chuck-make-it-through-male-puberty.htm">male puberty</a> and <a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/podcasts/chuck-and-josh-make-it-through-female-puberty.htm">female puberty</a> discusses the awkward
phase of life that we all had with great clarity.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/podcasts/510308/hidden-brain">Hidden Brain</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510308"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/npr-hiddenbrain.jpg" width="200">
A topic that I&rsquo;ve been loving lately is learning how our brains work. Not at the micro level, but at the macro level.
What makes us make all the silly decisions that we make. How do we subtly use this knowledge to manipulate people for
good and bad. Whenever you find yourself asking the question &ldquo;why would anyone behave this way?&rdquo;, listen to this show
and it&rsquo;ll shed some light on us crazy humans.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/podcasts/510308/hidden-brain">Grit</a> &ndash; I found myself nodding at many of the points in this episode. It highlights how expertise requires
spending a large portion of your time performing deliberate practice. It also looks at why people love people that
show mastery in something but disregard the massive dedication these people spent on becoming a master.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/podcasts/510308/hidden-brain">AirBnB While Black</a> &ndash; As a western white male, the easiness of my life is often not very obvious,
that is until you hear the stories of others. I have a feeling that the Internet is exposing our unconscious biases
more frequently while at the same time providing people with techniques to overcome these hurdles.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b036tbly">The Human Zoo</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b036tbly/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/humanzoo.jpg" width="200">
Over time I have really started enjoying the topic of human behaviour and what makes us who we are.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b07j4ppt">Trust me&hellip; I&rsquo;m an expert</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b060zr3d">Perfect people</a></li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b00nrtd2">History of the World in 100 Objects</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b00nrtd2/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/history-of-world.jpg" width="200">
An excellent history of the world in small bite sized chunks. The format gives you a really good perspective of how
long civilization takes to change. I can only imagine how much time it took to determine which objects to use
from the last century. While listening to this I realized how much bias I have around change being technical.</p>

<hr />

<h2>Music</h2>

<h3><a href="http://music.cbc.ca/radio3/">CBC Radio 3</a><a href="http://www.cbcradio3.com/podcast/"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/cbcradio3.jpg" width="200">
It&rsquo;s likely that I&rsquo;m a bit biased, but this is where I discover new music. I worked
there from 2005-2009 during the rise of the podcast. I can attest to the quality of the curation of the content coming
from the folks at Radio 3. The superfeed subscribes you to all the different podcasts published by Radio 3, though I
don&rsquo;t think there are as many shows as there used to be.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://songexploder.net/">Song Exploder</a><a href="http://songexploder.libsyn.com/rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/songexploder.png" width="200">
This show satifies my curiosity about how a song gets made. It also makes me
appreciate songs that I wouldn&rsquo;t have given a second listen. By listening to this show, you can disover new artists, and
you&rsquo;ll learn how to listen to music and grow appreciation for the more subtle elements of song composition.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/podcasts/510019/all-songs-considered">All Songs Considered</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/rss/podcast.php?id=510019"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/npr-asc.jpg" width="200">
A podcast I tend to listen to when I going to sleep. I don&rsquo;t quite keep up with music as much as I should, but I find
listening to this keeps me somewhat informed of what&rsquo;s going on.</p>

<hr />

<h2>Tech / Programming</h2>

<h3><a href="https://trackchanges.postlight.com/tagged/podcast">Track Changes</a><a href="http://trackchanges.libsyn.com/rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/trackchanges.png" width="200">
Enjoying this podcast makes me feel quite odd. It&rsquo;s a branding exercise by Paul and Rich&rsquo;s company, but I&rsquo;m able to see
past that and enjoy the dialogue of this show. I feel connected with <a href="https://twitter.com/ftrain">Paul Ford</a> as he brings out the
computer nostalgia non-stop. It&rsquo;s a nice light-weight podcast that&rsquo;s nice for the gym or listening to before going to
sleep.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Craig Mod on Great Design and Long Journeys</strong> (<a href="https://trackchanges.postlight.com/craig-mod-on-great-design-and-long-journeys-part-1-49739ae17a0c#.84a4n1jhd">part 1</a>, <a href="https://trackchanges.postlight.com/craig-mod-on-great-design-and-long-journeys-part-2-ddaebcf0117a#.rnmqfuno1">part 2</a>) &ndash; I really enjoyed hearing
the chill zen thoughts from Craig compared to the NYC startup fast life of Rich and Paul. I got the sense that there&rsquo;s
a lot I can learn from Craig.</li>
<li><a href="https://trackchanges.postlight.com/track-changes-podcast-32-clover-newsletter-turning-over-a-new-leaf-or-four-with-founders-liza-291e89d1aa69#.q38zxsyhz">Clover Newsletter</a> &ndash; Want to get some some insight to how the younger generation rediscovers
old mediums and finds them useful for their cause? This episode is great for that.
I was really impressed at how wise beyond their years <a href="https://twitter.com/lizadarwin">Liza Darwin</a>
and <a href="https://twitter.com/caseymlewis">Casey Lewis</a> talk about their newsletter business. More interesting for me is to hear about a
demographic (teenage girls) that is so often not spoken about in tech circles.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h2>Language</h2>

<h3><a href="http://www.theallusionist.org/">The Allusionist</a><a href="http://feeds.theallusionist.org/Allusionist"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/allusionist.png" width="200">
I could list to Helen Zaltzman speak all day. Her style and sense of humour is wonderful and I find that I learn a lot
about the origins of the words in my native language.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.theallusionist.org/allusionist/please">Please</a> &ndash; Listen to this episode and think again if someone from another culture is being rude.
Also, think about how other cultures may have perceived you as being rude by trying to be overly polite!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theallusionist.org/allusionist/wltm-i">WLTM</a> &ndash; The language surrounding dating from three hundred years ago.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/lexicon_valley.html">Lexicon Valley</a><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/SlateLexiconValley"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/lexvalley.jpg" width="200">
Each episode starts with a clue as to what the topic is going to be, and the hosts try to figure it out. They often have
great dialogues about the words and are well researched in trying to pinpoint the origin of term. They have a good sense
of humour too.</p>

<p><strong>Favourties:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/lexicon_valley/2015/06/lexicon_valley_the_pollyanna_hypothesis_all_languages_have_a_positivity.html">Language Positivity Bias</a> &ndash; This episode made me laugh out loud while grocery shopping. They
dive into the lyrics of Slayer and it&rsquo;s really a priceless moment.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/lexicon_valley/2015/11/pussy_the_etymology_and_history_of_a_cat_a_coward_and_female_genitalia.html">A Cat, a Coward, and Female Genitalia</a> &ndash; Where did the word pussy come from?</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>There are a lot of podcasts here and I&rsquo;m constantly re-evaluating which ones should remain. Finding the balance of time
and value is hard to figure out. Currently I&rsquo;m unemployed making it a lot easier to consume this much content. I also
listen to tech specific podcasts when I&rsquo;m spending some time in that technology. A good example of that would be the
<a href="http://rubyrogues.com/">ruby rogues</a> podcast. Or, I may take a look at <a href="http://hanselminutes.com/">HanselMinutes</a> to see if something
interesting has come up.</p>

<p>To subscribe to all the same podcasts that I do, import this <a href="http://scottmuc.com/podcasts_opml.xml">OPML</a> file into your favourite podcast
listening software.</p>

<h2>Unsubcribed</h2>

<p>After a while I find myself changing my podcast listening tastes. Rather than delete them from this post, I&rsquo;ll list
them here and provide some context as to why I don&rsquo;t listen to them anymore.</p>

<h3><a href="http://a16z.com/tag/podcast/">a16z</a><a href="http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:62921190/sounds.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/a16z.jpg" width="200">
Getting into the startup world is not something I&rsquo;m terribly interested in, but I am critical
about the tech community, especially startups. This show helps me better understand the world of startups so I can
better understand the mechanics of startups. Over time this podcast has become to irritate me. The Valley speak gets to
you after a while (count how many questions are answered with an excited &ldquo;Absolutely!&rdquo;). I stopped listen to this
because I realized that I simply did not care about the startup world. Listening to this podcast started to depress me.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://a16z.com/2014/09/05/a16z-podcast-everything-you-need-to-know-about-amazon/">Everything You Need to Know About Amazon</a> &ndash; Explanation of how Amazon re-invests all of its profits to avoid
opportunity costs is a novel concept. Not sure why investors are ok with it. Makes me more curious about what Amazon
will be doing 20-30 years from now.</li>
<li><a href="http://a16z.com/2014/09/30/a16z-podcast-creating-new-silicon-valleys/">Creating New Silicon Valleys</a> &ndash; When something becomes trendy, people always want to figure out how
to replicate it. This episode explains how cultures are emergent, not created. Common sense it would seem, but that
doesn&rsquo;t seem to really stop people. I feel the same around the topic of <a href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops/">DevOps</a>.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://hearstartup.com/">StartUp</a><a href="http://feeds.hearstartup.com/hearstartup"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/startup.png" width="200">
A podcast about a podcast startup. It mixes so many of my favourite things into one show.
Fantastic storytelling about a medium I&rsquo;m passionate about and a domain that I want to learn more of. What connects
me to the show is that <a href="https://twitter.com/abexlumberg">Alex Blumberg</a> just wants to work on something he&rsquo;s passionate about, but has to wade through all
sorts of concerns completely separate from what he really wants to do, because that&rsquo;s business. Though this podcast
didn&rsquo;t depress me like the a16z podcast did, I found the material getting pretty old. It was starting to repeat many of
the lessons from the <a href="http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2008/04/podcast-1/">StackOverflow Podcast</a> (from 2008). Also, more North American podcast content isn&rsquo;t
something I really want more of.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://hearstartup.com/episodes/gbm3498ruf7abd4owt4xs20uck1cvn">Startups are Risky Business</a> &ndash; This gave me insight around the different VC models. I used to think
that they are all looking for the 100x payoff. I need to learn more about the more modest investments out there.
Sometimes you can invest in something simply because you want it to exist.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://podcasts.thoughtbot.com/giantrobots">Giant Robots Smashing into Other Giant Robots</a><a href="http://podcasts.thoughtbot.com/giantrobots.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/giantrobots.jpg" width="200">
Not quite a technical podcast, but it shares stories from the software development world. I became a fan of
<a href="https://twitter.com/r00k">Ben Orenstein</a> when I saw him do a play-by-play screencast. He strikes me as someone I would enjoy
working with. I&rsquo;m weaning myself off of tech podcasts so this had to be removed.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://theshipshow.com/">The Ship Show</a><a href="http://theshipshow.com/podcast.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/shipshow.jpg" width="200">
Co-started by an old on-line friend of mine, <a href="https://twitter.com/buildscientist">Youssuf Elkalay</a>.
I like the conversational style of this show as a way to keep me in the loop in the world of <a href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops/">DevOps</a>.
Removed because I&rsquo;m trying to stay away from technical podcasts.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/">HealthyHacker</a><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/feed.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/healthyhacker.png" width="200">
This one is fairly new and I&rsquo;ve already become a fan. <a href="https://twitter.com/chrishunt">Chris Hunt</a>
delivers his show in a charming style. He discusses being healthy, and what&rsquo;s interesting in the software world. All to
the tune of a catchy theme song. Now I just need to get into the habit of doing the workout of the week. Removed for now
because of its technical base.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/2014/08/04/pineapple-in-your-pocket/">Pineapple in Your Pocket</a> &ndash; I try and use this memorization technique as frequently as possible!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/2014/09/29/codecation/">Codecation</a> &ndash; The story of Chris and Ben meeting up for a codecation was inspiring. I would like to do
something similar at some point.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/programs/ted-radio-hour/">TED Radio Hour</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510298"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/ted-radio-hour.jpg" width="200">
Episodes are themed around TED talks of similar topics. It blends interviews with the speakers along with their talks.
I find this more rich than the talk on its own.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/2013/03/28/175609678/the-violence-within-us?showDate=2014-08-08">The Violence Within Us</a> &ndash; Sort of a scary episode, but it helps me understand that life is always in a
delicate balance. We&rsquo;ll never live in a world where everyone is good. I tend to be utopian in my thinking and this
provides a good dose of reality.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/programs/ted-radio-hour/321797073/what-is-original?showDate=2014-06-27">What is Original</a> &ndash; The thought of being unique and interesting is something everyone craves, but in the
end most of things are derivitive. This episode is good to pair with the 99% Invisible episode:
<a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/duplitecture/">Duplitecture</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/2013/10/06/229879937/identities?showDate=2014-02-21">Identities</a> &ndash; The next few generations of humans are going to have a much different concept about their
identity. We are more global and cross-cultural than ever before.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/tapestry/index.html">Tapestry</a><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/includes/tapestry.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/tapestry.jpg" width="200">
Getting into the spiritual side a bit. This show talks about culture and religion with an
open mind. The show reminds me to appreciate the differences between all of us on this rock. I used to listen to this
show all the time when I lived in Canada. I just recently subscribed to the podcast.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/tapestry/episode/2014/10/24/being-alone-views-from-a-mormon-feminist-poet-nikki-giovanni/">Being Alone</a> &ndash; The 2nd portion with <strong>Nikki Giovanni</strong> is so delightful. It&rsquo;s a candid conversation that
has so many quotable verses. I was walking the streets of Bangalore while listening to it and I had a huge smile on my
face the whole time.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/whitecoat/">White Coat Black Art</a><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/includes/whitecoat.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/whitecoat.jpg" width="200">
The health care system is usually a bit of a black box and this show provides some visibility into how things work. Like
tapestry, this was a show I used to listen to all the time when I lived in Canada. Recently subscribed to feel that
connection back to where I came from.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/radio/whitecoat/slow-code-1.2827708">Slow Code</a> &ndash; A conversation about health care professionals
minimaly applying &ldquo;Code Blue&rdquo; protocols when they know the patient won&rsquo;t survive or will survive at a considerable
cost. This episode made me remember that my job is pretty much pointless and to think about the people that do real
honest work out there.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/spark/index.html">Spark</a><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/includes/spark.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/spark.jpg" width="200">
A Canadian look into the technical world. Always nice to hear a Canadian perspective of what&rsquo;s going on. Hopefully
because it&rsquo;s created by the CBC, there isn&rsquo;t any product/partner agenda.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02nrwfk">BBC Peter Day&rsquo;s World of Business</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02nrwfk/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/bbc-pdwob.jpg" width="200">
A show that does a good job of covering both sides around global trends or analysing specific environments. I find this
show a bit deeper than something like Freakanomics or Planet Money.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p03qg5rq">Tax Transparency &ndash; Norway&rsquo;s Model</a> &ndash; Personally, I&rsquo;ve become fascinated with transparent systems. I like
the idea of everyone knowing what each other makes because it provides the knowledge required to make better
decisions. This episode provides a look into why this was imposed in Norway&rsquo;s past and some of the complexities that
have resulted in a more modern era.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.futilitycloset.com/category/podcast/">Futility Closet</a><a href="http://feedpress.me/futilitycloset"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/futilitycloset.png" width="200">
A show about curious events. They did a neat thing where they perform a lateral thinking puzzle with each episode. It
reminds me that sometimes truth is stranger than fiction and to always be curious about what is laid out in front of
you. I&rsquo;ve only listened to a few episodes so I don&rsquo;t have any favourites to list at the moment in time.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.hellointernet.fm/">Hello Internet</a><a href="http://www.hellointernet.fm/podcast?format=rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/podcasts/hellointernet.png" width="200">
Most of the time I dislike drawn out conversational style podcasts but this one I enjoy listening to while doing tasks
(and I don&rsquo;t mind not absorbing the contents of the episode). The hosts are: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CGP_Grey">CGP Grey</a>, who entertains me with
his affinity for comfort and observing the world from a far. Often I find myself aligned with his views and enjoy his
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC2C_jShtL725hvbm1arSV9w">Youtube Channel</a> immensely. The other host is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brady_Haran">Brady Haran</a> who is energetic and curious. I
enjoy is enthusiasm around travel. I would love to have beer with these two which I know Grey would despise the idea and
Brady would love it. Their contrasting personalities and mutual respect for each other is why I&rsquo;ll stick with this
podcast even though the episodes are too long by my listening standards.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Review - Learning Continuous Integration With TeamCity by Manoj Mahalingam]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/book-review-learning-continuous-integration-with-teamcity-by-manoj-mahalingam/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-13T13:04:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/book-review-learning-continuous-integration-with-teamcity-by-manoj-mahalingam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong> &ndash; I personally know Manoj and have worked with him in the past. I was asked to review his book,
<a href="http://goo.gl/5wUy3v">Learning Continuous Integration with TeamCity</a>, by <a href="https://www.packtpub.com/">Packt Publishing</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://goo.gl/5wUy3v"><img class="left" src="https://www.packtpub.com/sites/default/files/9518OT%5f0.jpg" width="200"></a>
As someone who had spent many years consulting around the benefits of CI and implementing build and release strategies,
I was interested in how the minutiae would be brought up in a book.</p>

<p>The book begins by going through the creation and configuration of a similar build process for 3 specific tech stacks:
Java, .Net, and Ruby. At first it feels rather repetitive but the repetition actually helps reinforce the importance of
consistency. With all tech stacks, the procedure is pretty much the same: <code>Checkout, Build, Test, Package, Deploy, Run
UI Tests</code>. This pattern really stands out after going through chapters 4, 5 and 6 and builds up a foundation for the
reader so that the rest of the material makes sense.</p>

<p>After setting the stage with these build configurations, he then dives into content that&rsquo;s a bit more TeamCity
specific. This area was much more interesting to me as I&rsquo;m already experienced with build and release concepts, but it
was nice to see TeamCity specific features explained in a little bit more depth.</p>

<p>One piece that felt a little out of place was the topic on Continuous Delivery. It&rsquo;s really hard to introduce a concept
that has a massive book dedicated to the subject. Not sure if its inclusion will help out the beginner that this book
appears to be targeting.</p>

<p>What I enjoyed the most was raising operational concerns around running a CI server system. It was likely
deliberately left out, but I would have liked to see a mention of automated configuration management. There&rsquo;s something
incredibly powerful around automation around your automation.</p>

<p>It became clear to me that this book is meant for the absolute beginner. Manoj hints at better ways of implementing
his example configurations (eg: using wrapper scripts over the built in runners) but doesn&rsquo;t distract the reader
with these possibly subjective tangents. I would recommend this book if you&rsquo;ve never worked with any CI tool and like
to have a guidebook as you try and set it up yourself. Despite being over 250 pages, the book is packed with
screenshots so that it&rsquo;s absolutely clear and won&rsquo;t take too long to go through the whole book. If you&rsquo;re already
experienced with some tools the principles around CI and good build hygiene, this book is useful to skim to see what&rsquo;s
new with TeamCity and some context of the usage of TeamCity specific features.</p>

<p>You can find more information about Manoj at his <a href="https://twitter.com/manojlds">twitter account</a>, on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/526535/manojlds">stackoverflow</a>, or his
<a href="http://stacktoheap.com/">website</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visiting the Motherland - Ukraine]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/visiting-the-motherland-ukraine/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-06T15:31:12+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/visiting-the-motherland-ukraine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>August 17th &ndash; August 29th</em></p>

<h3>Ukraine</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
The next leg of the journey was a long slog from Vienna to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lviv">L’viv</a>. I took a noon train to Budapest and had to pass
some time there for a little while. From Budapest it was an overnight journey with many frequent stops in the
middle of the night for immigration and customs. If you’ve ever played <a href="http://papersplea.se/">Papers, Please</a>, it felt like that. Ukraine
isn’t part of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schengen_Agreement">Schengen agreement</a> so you can’t just cross the border without a documents check. Around a few
hours from L’viv the attendant asks me about my purpose in Ukraine. She then points at my &ldquo;ringless&rdquo; ring finger and
smiles. I knew of the Russian/Ukrainian bride thing, but found it crazy that her first guess was for that purpose.
I thought it was a hyped up, but after watching a few <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8wW7c58nMI4">youtube documentaries</a> about it, I learned
it’s sadly alive and well.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train2.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train2.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
Even with such a long journey the train pretty much arrived on time within a couple minutes. When I exited the train I
immediately could recognize my cousin <a href="https://twitter.com/RusalkaUA">Lilia</a>. She ran up to me and gave me a proper family style hug. Looks like I’m
home! We took a bus to her home in the Northern part of the city. I was introduced to her roommate,
<a href="https://twitter.com/uPadavan">Vitalik</a>. He and I got along really well. He’s a web designer and looks to have a knack for it!
Lilia had to go back to work so I unpacked and made myself at home. Later that evening Lilia’s sister, Natalia, arrived
by train from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ternopil">Ternopil</a>. She had a huge package of food from her parents and we all enjoyed a feast as I
did my best to tell the story of myself and the Myц family Canadian history.</p>

<h2>L&#8217;viv</h2>

<p>I felt immediately comfortable in L’viv. As Lilia was at work, Vitalik and Natalia guided me around the city. Here
are some of the noteworthy places we checked out:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-high-castle.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-high-castle.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;High Castle&#34;" alt="&#34;High Castle&#34;"></a>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lviv_High_Castle">High Castle</a> &ndash; On my first day in L&#8217;viv I was antsy to go out and explore. I never feel comfortable
  in a location until I spend at least a whole day walking around exploring and knowing my surroundings. Natalia likes
  to sleep in (she&rsquo;s going to kill me), so instead of waiting for her to wake up, I decide to explore L&#8217;viv on my own.
  The high castle name is more of a memory as the castle isn&rsquo;t there anymore. Getting to the top of the hill was
  good exercise and rewarded me with a beautiful 360 degree view of the city.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-dim-legend.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-dim-legend.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Dim Legend&#34;" alt="&#34;Dim Legend&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://ukraineallaboutu.com/travel-in-ukraine/hotels-and-restaurants/lviv/house-of-legends/">Dim Legend (House of Legend)</a> &ndash; There are a collection of restaurants owned by a company that&rsquo;s doing some interesting
  setups. Dim Legend has a room for every story (or a story for every room). The restaurant takes
  the entire building and you can go up to the roof top where there&rsquo;s patio with a car, and a chimney with a ladder so
  that you can climb to the top. There&rsquo;s something refreshing about being in a country that doesn&rsquo;t have the same
  restrictive safety regulations of most western countries.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-rynok.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-rynok.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Rynok Square&#34;" alt="&#34;Rynok Square&#34;"></a>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Market_Square_(Lviv)">Rynok Square</a> &ndash; Like most Eastern European cities, L&#8217;viv has a beautiful (albeit touristy) city
  square. You&rsquo;ll find the &ldquo;floating&rdquo; statue people and dudes making giant bubbles. Overall though, the atmosphere is
  quaint and relaxing. Ukrainian culture is inviting so it&rsquo;s pretty hard to feel like you&rsquo;re too far out of place.
  This is probably where I spent the most time as all the coffee shops and restaurants are all near this location.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-chocolate-chili.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-chocolate-chili.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Melted Chocolate with Chili&#34;" alt="&#34;Melted Chocolate with Chili&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://ukraineallaboutu.com/travel-in-ukraine/hotels-and-restaurants/lviv/lviv-handmade-chocolate/">Lviv chocolate</a> &ndash; One of the most unique experiences I had in L&#8217;viv was drinking melted chocolate
  flavoured with a whole whack load of chili powder! This place was not good for any thought about losing weight. Not
  sure how everyone here stays so fit! At least I was getting a lot of walking in, but not sure if it&rsquo;s enough for
  all the sweets I&rsquo;ve been having.</p>

<p>&nbsp;
&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.lvivbeermuseum.com/uk/muzey">Lviv brewery</a> &ndash; On my own I stopped by the brewpub to sample a few of their beers. I was really
intrigued by the style of beer they make there. In general, I found Ukrainian beer sweeter than most beers I&rsquo;ve
had around the world. I visited the brewery a second time with Natalia and Vitalik. We took a brewery tour but
it was done in Ukrainian. I&rsquo;ve never heard Ukrainian spoken so fast, but it was pretty comprehensive. She started
the tour talking about the origins of beer in Egypt.</li>
<li><a href="http://trumitlu.virtual.ua/?lang=en">Try Mitly (3 Brooms)</a> &ndash; My cousins are huge Harry Potter fans and they said that there&rsquo;s a place to have
butter beer in L&#8217;viv! A lot of places were kitschy but that didn&rsquo;t bother me in this environment. I found them a lot
of fun. It could be that I felt like I was in an environment where people aren&rsquo;t as judgemental about such kinds
of establishments.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.justlviv.it/en/1714/gas-lamp.html">Gas lamp</a> &ndash; Owned by the same person as Dim Legend, this restaurant had a unique feel for every floor
and was a fun environment to take some time and relax in.</li>
<li><a href="http://visittoukraine.com/en/unique-ukraine/lviv-coffee-mine">Lviv coffee manufacture</a> &ndash; L&#8217;viv is the coffee capital of Ukraine. Normally tea is the hot beverage
choice, but here coffee rules. A proper L&#8217;viv coffee is hot water mixed with the coffee grounds without a filter.
You wait a few minutes and the grounds settle to the bottom and you&rsquo;re left with a rich, flavourful cup of coffee.
The best part is that you don&rsquo;t need any fancy expensive equipment to make it! It&rsquo;s really the quality of the beans
that matter.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lychakiv_Cemetery">Lychakiv Cemetery</a> &ndash; I wanted to go somewhere outside the center and old gothic cemeteries seem to appeal
to me for some reason. The day that I visited Lychakiv Cemetery was sunny and warm. The whole area is like a maze and
it was nice to wander around witnessing the beautiful scenery.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-beer.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-beer.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Beer Museum&#34;" alt="&#34;Beer Museum&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-butterbeer.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-butterbeer.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Butterbeer!&#34;" alt="&#34;Butterbeer!&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-books.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-books.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Book Market&#34;" alt="&#34;Book Market&#34;"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-alley.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-alley.small.jpg" width="190"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-cemetary.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-cemetary.small.jpg" width="190" title="&#34;Cemetary&#34;" alt="&#34;Cemetary&#34;"></a></p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/lviv-tram.jpg" width="70">
L&#8217;viv is a city rich in culture, architecture, and friendly people. It&rsquo;s accessible with its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trams_in_Lviv">120 year old tram</a>
system, but remember to punch your ticket yourself (pictures to the left) and has all the things you need as a traveler.
The city is sort of a dream land for me. It has excellent beer, chocolate, coffee, books, and food. The people are
friendly and accomodating, I can&rsquo;t wait to be back!</p>

<h2>Ternopil</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-home.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-home.small.jpg" width="200"></a>
For the weekend, Lillia had planned a trip to Ternopil to visit her parents and other relatives. Apparently they don’t
get many foreigners on the train and the attendant on the train made an effort to ask if I wanted tea or coffee in
English. He sort of chuckled and so did my cousins, not sure why. We took a bus from the train station to the outer area of Ternopil
where Lilias’s parents live. It was a classic pre 90’s looking apartment block. The door opens to their apartment and
I’m welcomed with a feast on the table! Lilia’s parents didn’t speak much English so poor Lilia had to spend a lot of
time translating (she eventually could tell me whole life story without me having to say a word). The meal started with
a shot of vodka. When Ivan offered me another, I replied “tak, bud laska!” (translation: yes, please!). That moment
signified me as an authentic family member.</p>

<p>First, I need to digress and talk about Lilia and Natalia’s parents, Ivan and Mariia. They are the sweetest couple and
so generous. I loved how they didn’t let the language barrier prevent us from getting to know each other. One of my
favourite moments was sitting with Ivan as he showed me pictures and we had a conversation. Lilia was busy packing
for the trip back and after she was done she asked what the heck we could possibly talk about. I’m not quite sure
myself, but we laughed a lot and didn’t let language stop us from at least trying to communicate. We even enjoyed
watching the Belgian GP (and what an awesome race!) with some Ukrainian craft beers. One day I hope to learn more
Ukrainian so we can communicate even more the next time we meet.</p>

<p>Mariia could easily be mistaken as a sister of her daughters. She’s actually my
cousin (Lilia and Natalia are my 2nd cousins 1st removed) and the family bond was definitely felt. She’s also an
amazing cook! The meals included home made: cabbage rolls, varenyky (perogies), shkvarky (pork rind), sour cream, borscht, milk, and juice.
I’m pretty sure I gained 5 kilos over those few days.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-beer1.jpg" width="180">
<img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-beer2.jpg" width="180">
The next day was spent driving to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Velyki_Birky">Velyki Birky</a>, a village outside of Ternopil. Our first stop was at Mariia’s parents (Hanna and
Fedoz). First we stopped by a house which was a family run brewery (business card pictured). One of the sons of the owner was there and he
happily (in excellent English) explained the whole operation. The beer was fresh, un-pasterized, un-filtered, and
very tasty. We then arrived and had a big family lunch (with more shots of vodka). Hanna is my dad’s cousin as she
is the daughter of Eve Myц who is the sister of Petro Myц, my dad’s father. The meal was of course fantastic and I
did my best to update them on my family back in Canada. During the afternoon, Lilia, Natalia, and I walked over to
where Hanna&rsquo;s other children live. Lilia gave her best rendition of my life story and we had fun playing more Q&amp;A
with more of my family. One of the big questions was on how Canada was receiving the news about the events going
on in Ukraine. Unfortunately I couldn&rsquo;t quite adequatley answer the question but from a generalized perspective I
could say that the West has been pretty weak in it&rsquo;s response.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family.medium.jpg" width="510"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.medium.jpg" width="510"></a></p>

<p>In the evening I went out with the girls to meet up with some of their friends. It was fun introducing them to some
of the games I played at TWU (eg: numbers game, and one-up one-down). The next day was a holiday for independence day
so we went walking around the city for a bit. The city had some very pretty areas and some interesting looking playgrounds.
After our walk we went to the train station (pic: don&rsquo;t we look like an intimidating group?).</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-playground.medium.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-playground2.medium.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-departing.medium.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<h2>Back to L&#8217;viv</h2>

<p>After an amazing weekend we headed back to L&#8217;viv. Lilia&rsquo;s roommate was returning so I had find a <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.in/rooms/451524">place of my own</a>
to for a few days. I wasn&rsquo;t prepared for how much I would miss being in the same place as my cousins and Vitalik (I&rsquo;m
considering him family). I did feel some sense of relief to give Lilia some time without having to worry
about entertaining me and it gave me a chance to practice my Ukrainian all on my own. The few days I spent on my
own was focused on hanging out in coffee shops and working on a browser plugin. I realized there&rsquo;s a reason why
people smiled when I asked for the wifi password when I hung out at a venue. Trying to be Ukrainian I would say
&ldquo;Internet bud laska&rdquo;. This is the equivalent of ordering the Internet off of a menu. My cousins got a good laugh
from this, and apparently so did all the wait staff I said this to.</p>

<p>Anyways, over a couple days I got the the basic functionality of a plugin working called <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/blockworthy">BlockWorthy</a>.
It scrubs links to viral websites and issues you a warning if you happen to go to one of those websites. It felt good
to be writing some code and exploring some ideas.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>Leaving Ukraine I thought about the bond of family. I had been watching Game of Thrones and seeing how important
bloodlines are in that show probably had some affect on me. I was really touched that my cousins would openly accept
me into their home and all because we share common ancestry (my great grandfater, their great great grandfather).
I didn’t even know who were my cousins were until my aunt
in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biggar,_Saskatchewan">Biggar</a> informed me there are relatives in Ukraine who would love to meet me. The thought about the subconscious
bond with family made me think about why we have countries and lines on maps. It’s like a higher level view of the
bond. Patriotism is like a larger version of nepotism. I can’t help connect more easily with someone from Canada than
I would USA. My bond with my cousins exists because of who my parents are. My ability to nearly walk into any country
is simply because of the country I was born in.</p>

<p>What I’m really trying to say is that I’m so freaking lucky to be born into an awesome family and country. Because
of these uncontrollable events (on my part), I’ve been afforded so many luxuries.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rome, Switzerland, and Vienna]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/rome-switzerland-and-vienna/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T13:09:31+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/rome-switzerland-and-vienna</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 30th &ndash; August 17th</em></p>

<h2>When in Rome</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-fountain.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-fountain.medium.jpg" width="900"></a></p>

<p>When I learned that my uncle and his family would be in Rome I looked at my schedule to see if I could make seeing them
work. It turned out it fit perfectly! The last time I saw them was in London while they were doing their 2013 summer
trip and I was on my Belgian Grand Prix vacation. My aunt and uncle are well versed in the world of business so we had
many evenings discussing what I&rsquo;ve learned from the economics courses and floating ideas of what&rsquo;s next for my life. Of
course I got to catch up with my cousins too. Can&rsquo;t believe how quickly they are growing up (I won&rsquo;t mention that I
remember seeing them in diapers to avoid their embarassment).  They had rented a flat near the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Steps">Spanish Steps</a>
which made it easy for me to cram in a bunch of sight-seeing in a short amount of time.</p>

<p>Touring Rome is pretty easy because all you have to do is step outside. Even on my first walk I stumbled across many
interersting sites. I did a couple free walking tours, but they weren&rsquo;t organized by Sandeman and weren&rsquo;t nearly the
same quality. Still, it was good to have a guided walk to the Colloseum and to the Vatican. My favourite place was the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Gallery_of_Maps">Hallway of Maps</a> in the Vatican Museum. Ever since I was a kid, I&rsquo;ve always loved looking at maps. On
roadtrips I would be the navigator, and my favourite thing about Ultima VII is the cloth map that was packaged with the
game</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-colosseum.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-colosseum.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-square.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-square.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-st-peters.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/rome-st-peters.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>As beautiful as Rome was, I knew my time as a tourist was ending. I was at the point where I didn&rsquo;t want to elbow my
way through tourists anymore. Nor was I as interested as I was before in exploring musuems and historical places. The
brain can only hold so much. One thing I enjoyed immensely were the flavour of the tomatoes! Every meal I had I was sure
to have tomatoes as a part of it.</p>

<h2>Watching Time Go By in Switzerland</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-home.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-home.medium.jpg" width="900"></a></p>

<p>The other part that made Rome convenient was that I could travel to Switzerland to meet up with fellow ex-ThoughtWork
<a href="https://twitter.com/mhoefi">Marc Hofer</a>, who I worked with in India in ThoughtWorks University (TWU), and who&rsquo;s balcony view is displayed above.
He had a 1L bottle of scotch ready (we numbed our heads with scotch nearly every evening during TWU). Thankfully he was
generous enough to give me a couch for as long as I needed one. I ended up spending 10 days in beautiful <a href="http://www.myswitzerland.com/en/thun.html">Thun</a>!</p>

<p>Over the those days I did the following:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Dinners and chats with Marc</strong> &ndash; Catching up with Marc was a lot of fun. During the day I would accrue a lot of ideas and
he became my wall to bounce them off of. One such idea was my new currency that I called &ldquo;Sunset&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s a time based
currency where you determine the exchange rate of the base amount which is a Day. If your daily expenses are $100USD,
then that&rsquo;s the exchange rate into Days. If you have $1400 in the bank than you have 2 Weeks saved. It&rsquo;s a completely
personal currency because everyone&rsquo;s exchange into Days will be different. We of course
talked about our time in India and software development in Switzerland. We never really lacked of things to talk about
the whole time I was there.</li>
<li><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bern.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bern.small.jpg" width="300"></a> <strong>Bern
Excursion</strong> &ndash; Marc had a meetup with some of his colleagues and invited me out. I took a train out to Bern a few
hours before the meetup started so I could wander around a bit. It didn&rsquo;t take long for me to find the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kindlifresserbrunnen">Kindlifresserbrunnen (Child Eater Fountain)</a> which is probably the most bizarre statue I&rsquo;ve ever seen. The old
town was beautiful (like Antwerp, Bruges, Heidelberg, Prague, etc&hellip;) and of course I found a nearby
<a href="http://www.altestramdepot.ch/htm/home.htm">brewery</a> to quench my thirst for a bit before heading to meet up with Marc and his colleagues.</li>
<li><strong>Coffee shops</strong> &ndash; During the day I looked to find cafes to hang out in and work on my blog (these posts seem to take me a
heck of a lot of time). There was <a href="https://plus.google.com/106555922181396502598/about?hl=en">one cafe</a> that I really liked. The staff were friendly, played good music, and the
coffee and beers available were very tasty. During this period I was getting working on my <a href="http://careers.stackoverflow.com/scottmuc">CV</a> and getting
excited about working again!</li>
<li><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bike.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bike.small.jpg" width="300"></a> <strong>Bike
around Lake Thun</strong> &ndash; The weather was hit-and-miss, but for one day there was excellent weather. I rented a bike and
rode it to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interlaken">Interlaken</a> and back to Thun for a total of 60km. It was a beautiful ride, but I could feel that I&rsquo;m a bit
out of shape.</li>
<li><strong>Train tour</strong> &ndash; There were spare days on my Eurail pass so I decided to check out all the main city centers in the
country. I started by going to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geneva">Geneva</a>, then <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zurich">Zurich</a>, and finished in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lucerne">Luzern</a>.
Mike Wong, a ThoughtWorker from SF, was on vacation and we met up for dinner. Seriously, ThoughtWorkers are everywhere!</li>
<li><strong>Oberhofen Castle and Clock Museum</strong> &ndash; Over the weekend Marc played tourist with me and we headed over to Oberhofen. The
purpose of the trip was to go the <a href="http://www.myswitzerland.com/en/museum-of-clocks-and-mechanical-musical-instruments.html">clock museum</a> but it didn&rsquo;t open for a few hours. We walked around and decided to
tour the <a href="http://www.schlossoberhofen.ch/en/home">castle</a>. After a bit of walking and a quick snack we went back to the clock museum. They
didn&rsquo;t do tours in English so Marc played translator. Even in Swiss-German it was a fun tour. The guide was clearly
passionate about the watches and the music devices.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-spiez.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-spiez.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-thun-canal.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-thun-canal.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bridge.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bridge.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>Since I was in the land of clocks I was hoping to purchase a watch there. Something to be a symbol of taking time to
enjoy life (a principle of my career break) and something to keep me from looking at my phone for the time. I was
inspired by the intricate work that goes into making a watch and thought having one on my wrist would remind me to take
pride in my work and take the necessary time to do it well. Unfortunately all the watch stores were posh and displayed
ideas around prestige and fashion more than engineering. It switched off my idea of purchasing a watch for now.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-currency.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/swiss-currency.small.jpg" width="180"></a>
It was hard to leave Switzerland because I was growing comfortable there. The people were friendly and forgiving of my
inability to speak any of the 4 official languages. Then again, paying over $30 (0.3 Days) was quickly draining my money
reserves. At least the best part of Switzerland is free; the scenery. Oh, and I also like how the currency folded nicely
in my money clip. The notes are sized in such a way that the denomination of the note aligns in such a way that you can
see all of your notes when folded! I can&rsquo;t say how many times I&rsquo;ve had a roll of US notes and found that they were all
$1 bills and I only had a total of $30 on me.</p>

<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h2>Composing my Thoughts in Vienna</h2>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-cats.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-cats.medium.jpg" width="900"></a></p>

<p>The next leg of my journey is a long train trip to L&#8217;viv, Ukraine. I decided to break up the trip with a stop in Vienna
for a couple days. With only a couple days I had to pack in the sight-seeing. This was made easier with me being
museumed-out so I was mostly checking things out from the outside. To make things easy, I found a
<a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/1531563">great location</a> with a host with a couple cats (pictured above).</p>

<p>My first day was spent checking out the two largest palaces in Vienna. The highlight was a stop at a <a href="http://www.salmbraeu.com/index.php?id=2&amp;L=1">brewery</a> just
outside the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belvedere_(palace)">Belvedere</a> palace. The service was great, the food yummy, and every beer tasty. After 1.5L of beer I was set
for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sch%C3%B6nbrunn_Palace">Schönbrunn</a> palace. I took the metro there and climb up the hill to Gloriette and had a little nap on the grass there.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-belvedere.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-belvedere.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-schunbrunn.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-schunbrunn.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-center.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-center.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>The next day I used a city bike rental. I&rsquo;m glad I did because I saw a very different Vienna. First stop was to checkout
the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hundertwasser_Haus">Hundertwasserhaus</a>. It was so interesting and pretty that I wondered why beautiful buildings
like it had to be the exception to the rule. His <a href="http://www.hundertwasser.com/">website</a> is full of interesting ideas. His 5-skins
concept is one I find myself conflicted about. I wonder what it would have been like to have him and
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gene_Roddenberry">Gene Roddenberry</a> had a conversation.</p>

<p>I then went through <a href="http://www.wien-vienna.com/prater.php">Prater</a> which was a scary amusement park. The weather was a bit gloomy and there were some
giant clown shaped buildings that made me think of the book IT.</p>

<p>Since I was on a bike I could cover
a bit more distance so I went towards the bridge and crossed North to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donau_City">Donaucity</a>. It was like riding into a dystopian
story! The streets were stark and there was a cold feeling to the area. I rode away to the nearby park and found it odd
to see such a large expanse of greenery vacant on a Saturday afternoon. It reminded me again that big design up front
for cities does not work. What you end up with is something functional but complete devoid of any human feel. After
riding back to the center I parked the bike at another area and checked out another <a href="http://www.1516brewingcompany.com/cms/">brewery</a>. I think I
went there during shift change because it took a long time to get the attention of a waitress. The beer and the currywurst was really
good, but the poor service at the obnoxious sounding Australian behind me (probably was just my mood) was wearing me
down and I took the metro back to the apartment and hung out in the flat with Roman and his cats.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-hundertwasser.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-hundertwasser.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-donaucity.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-donaucity.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-golden-boy.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/vienna-golden-boy.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>After one more sleep it&rsquo;s time for me to leave Vienna and head to L&#8217;viv, Ukraine!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Growing an Open Source Project: The Pester Story]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/growing-an-open-source-project-the-pester-story/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-07T16:50:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/growing-an-open-source-project-the-pester-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/github-pester.png"></a></p>

<h3>In the Beginning</h3>

<p>In 2010 I was on a project that focused on build and release software for a bunch of .Net projects (and a few Java
projects). Our &ldquo;glue&rdquo; was written in PowerShell because of the wonderful remoting capabilities and it&rsquo;s integration with
Windows automation. Our code was untested and our code base was growing over time because our tools proved to be useful and
we were getting more and more feedback. Thus, the code required change more frequently. Without the safety net of tests
for the most basic logic, our feedback loop was slow as it required us to run builds and deploys to adequately cover our
bases.</p>

<p>It was January 1st, 2011. I was a touch hungover from the previous night and was chilling in my apartment in Calgary.
The difficulty in changing our PowerShell code was bothering me enough that I got a bunch of coffee from
<a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/caffe-beano-calgary">Cafe Beano</a> and attempted to make an <code>rspec</code> like testing tool for PowerShell. The next day I was able to make a <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester/commit/a1d6a0e01f58375175ed090647ab8245a049f1a6">commit</a>
with actual working code! A few days later I was able to <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/PowerYaml/commits/master?page=1">add tests</a> to PowerYaml. That&rsquo;s how
<a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester">Pester</a> was born.</p>

<p>In the next couple months I integrated Pester into our project. It was a real superficial integration as we didn&rsquo;t have
too much time to retroactively add a lot of tests. So for me, my consumption of Pester was a few months in early 2011!</p>

<h3>The Early Days (2011 &ndash; 2012)</h3>

<p>Over the course of the year, the tool seemed to be adopted by a few. A <a href="http://mrtn.nrd.io/">friend in Vancouver</a> apparently had begun using it
in one of his projects. He&rsquo;s also the first <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester/commits/master?author=mrtns">contributor</a> to the project! It wasn&rsquo;t until the next year
that <a href="https://twitter.com/ferventcoder">Rob Reynolds (aka ferventcoder)</a> used Pester in the <a href="http://chocolatey.org/">Chocolatey</a> project. That was my
first hint that there&rsquo;s potential in this project.</p>

<p>In 2012 there wasn&rsquo;t much going on until <a href="https://twitter.com/mwrockx">Matt Wrock</a> added mocking support and contributed a whole lot of fixes.
It was then that Pester got a new core maintainer. It was very cool to meet him during my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a>
in Seattle and give him a proper thank you for the work that&rsquo;s done. I believe he also wrote the <a href="http://www.mattwrock.com/post/2012/11/15/Unit-Testing-Powershell-and-Hello-Pester.aspx">earliest post</a>
on Pester. I then noticed a comprehensive post on the <a href="http://blogs.endjin.com/?s=pester">endjin.com</a> blog website.</p>

<p>Seeing other people use Pester was a massively ego boosting thing. I&rsquo;m afraid I&rsquo;m one of those people in the software
community that does feed off of this kind of thing. For some reason it made me feel validated as a professional in the
software community. Despite the pleasure I got from Pester being associated with me, I decided to move Pester from my
personal github user to a Pester organization. I&rsquo;m really happy I did that, because it made it feel more like a
community project than a personal one. A <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/pester">google group</a> was eventually created too as to not clutter
Github with conversations in the issue tracker.</p>

<p>Later on I would find out that it&rsquo;s been used in several <a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/">ThoughtWorks</a> projects! These use cases weren&rsquo;t
even initiated by me. Someone wanted to test their PowerShell code, found Pester, and started using it. They would find
out I also worked for ThoughtWorks and would ping me on our internal chat and ask me questions.</p>

<h3>The Year of Change (2013)</h3>

<p>While I was living in India I had several months with some extra time that I used to update Pester. Throughout the year
I spent quite a bit of time maintaining the project. There definitely was a motive for this activity. I knew that
projects that have activity in the codebase are usually favoured by other devs. I still haven&rsquo;t used Pester on a project
since early 2011! There&rsquo;s no functionality that I could possibly need out of Pester but I carved out time to take care
of a few niggling design flaws and close some issues. This resulted in a <a href="http://scottmuc.com/powershell-pester-2-and-1-dot-2-released/">major release</a> which is pretty
much the last time I really did anything to the code. It was great to see another <a href="http://johanleino.wordpress.com/2013/09/13/pester-unit-testing-for-powershell/">quality blog post</a> by
Johan Leino appear on the Web.</p>

<h3>The Year of Transition (2014)</h3>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/LogicalDiagram/status/461638955725631488"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/pester-mention.png"></a>
2014 marked a large surge in Pester interest. During the PowerShell Summit it was rumoured that the creator of
PowerShell, <a href="http://www.jsnover.com/blog/">Jeffrey Snover</a>, mentioned Pester in one of his talks! Heck, I was even <a href="http://powershell.org/wp/2014/03/23/episode-262-powerscripting-podcast-scott-muc-on-testing-with-pester/">interviewed</a> for the
PowerScripting Podcast!</p>

<p>Another contributor by the name of <a href="https://twitter.com/nohwnd">Jakub Jareš</a> was very active and soon became a core member of the Pester team. During
my travels on my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a> I got to meet up with him in Prague! He also wrote a
<a href="http://www.powershellmagazine.com/author/jjakub/">couple</a> great articles too.</p>

<p>Now it looks like there&rsquo;s another one joining in too. Welcome <a href="https://twitter.com/MSH_Dave">Dave</a> to the Pester team!</p>

<p>Looking at the logs of the Beta branch, it&rsquo;s wonderful to see my commit percentage diminishing. I&rsquo;ve now only committed
30% of the code base!</p>

<h3>Lessons Learned</h3>

<p>Though not a big project, I can say I learned a lot maintaining this open source project. There&rsquo;s something very
different than working with a colocated team and random contributors around the world. Colocated teams develop unwritten
rules (a culture) and there&rsquo;s less debate over small issues. I didn&rsquo;t realize how much brace alignment, trailing
whitespace, tab stops, and other petty things would annoy me. What&rsquo;s harder is that I didn&rsquo;t want to complain about it
to the community afraid that I would come across as an OCD control freak. My biggest mistake with Pester was thinking
too much on how it reflected upon me, and not what is good for the community. If I had lived and breathed Windows
projects over the last few years, I think that would have been different. I&rsquo;m happy that Pester has a few excellent
maintainers now and that I&rsquo;ve participated in an open source project from first commit to stepping away.</p>

<p>Another lesson was that empowering would be contributors was an investment well worth doing. It&rsquo;s hard to say, but I
feel that doing this is what&rsquo;s enabled me to lessen my involvement over time.</p>

<p>This talk also resonated with me a bit (the last 4-5 minutes):</p>

<iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UIDb6VBO9os " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h3>Stepping Down</h3>

<p>The adventure of watching a project grow and have a life on its own has been a wonderful experience. Looking at the
project history and correspondance it&rsquo;s pretty easy to see that I&rsquo;m not nearly as active. That&rsquo;s really thanks to Jakub
and Dave doing nearly all the maintenance.</p>

<p>That being said, I&rsquo;m &ldquo;officially&rdquo; stepping down and retiring from Pester. This will be done by unsubcribing from any
e-mail notifications (the google group, and the github project).</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://pesterbdd.com/images/Pester.png">
I would like to shout a big thank you to everyone who made this project so wonderful. Especially to <a href="https://twitter.com/manojlds">Manoj
Mahalingam</a> who did some great work in the early days and really helped me get this project off the ground.
Another shout out to <a href="http://vant.ca/">Stefan Vant</a> for the excellent logo!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prague, Budapest, and the Hungarian Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T13:23:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 22nd &ndash; July 29th</em></p>

<h3>Prague</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>Next portion of the trip is to Eastern Europe! I had a nice simple itinerary to Prague: <strong>Heidelberg &ndash;> Munich &ndash;> Prague</strong>.
Unfortunately something was going on with the brakes on the train and I missed my train in Munich so it
turned into: <strong>Heidelberg &ndash;> Munich &ndash;> Neurberg &ndash;> Cheb &ndash;> Prague</strong>. By now I&rsquo;m a seasoned itinerary refactorer so this
didn&rsquo;t phase me. These little <em>adjustments of the universe</em> can sometimes end up with interesting things happening. At
the Plzen stop, a woman sat across from me in the couchette. She started speaking to me in Czech and my response was the
standard Canadian response: I&rsquo;m sorry?</p>

<br />


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry?&rdquo; or &ldquo;sowry&rdquo; in the short form is Canadian for: I apologize that I don&rsquo;t speak your language and I&rsquo;m embarassed to
ask you to repeat yourself in English because I&rsquo;ve never had to deal with speaking and understanding multiple languages. Of course
I&rsquo;m also making the assumption that you can speak English because a world without English is just unfathomable. Again,
I&rsquo;m sorry</p></blockquote>

<p>Then in English she said I looked Czech and was just inquiring about the train. Turns out
she spoke excellent English, lives in San Diego and was just in the country to visit her family. Eventually we
started chit chatting and the conversation about my trip became the focus of interest. I had fun demoing her the <a href="http://scottmuc.com/twinery/independent-accord.html">cargo ship tour</a>
and got some usability feedback as a result. Next thing I knew we were in Prague. Even with my limited
social ability to pick up on body language, I think she was flirting with me! In my usual fashion I dropped the ball. We
parted ways with a handshake and me wishing her a pleasant visit with her family.</p>

<p>After hitting my head against a wall for what seemed like a decade, I continued on to a rendezvous point in the
train station where I was to meet up with <a href="https://twitter.com/nohwnd">Jakub Jareš</a>. He&rsquo;s a core contributor to <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester">Pester</a>,
who in the last 6 months, has taken pretty much all the maintenance burden off of my shoulders. He offered to take me out for beers and I obviously
couldn&rsquo;t resist an offer like that. It was the rainiest day of the summer and he guided me to the <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2094840">airbnb</a>
where I was to stay for the next couple days. Then we proceeded to a <a href="http://www.pivovarskyklub.com/">bar</a> (and got soaked in the process). We enjoyed many beers,
discussed much about software development, and my ineptness with the woman on the train was soon forgotten.</p>

<p>Sandeman operates in Prague too so I did a couple tours:</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague-castle.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/prague-castle.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/daily-tours/new-prague-free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: I can&rsquo;t really talk about this tour without talking about the guide. <a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/our-guides/pavel.html">Pavel</a>
was quite the character. He had an entertaining dry wit and personalized the tour with stories of his own family. I
was blown away when he said is grandmother has lived in the same flat her whole life and has lived in 9 different
countries as a result. It was a good reminder on the craziness humans have to deal with all the time.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/daily-tours/prague-castle-tour.html">Castle Tour</a>: Fortunately, Pavel was the guide for this tour too! He sort of stumbled over a
little late and asked the group if we could deviate from the standard tour itinerary and visit a
<a href="http://europeupclose.com/article/st-norberts-brewery-in-prague/">monastery</a> where some award winning beer is brewed. No one was opposed and I got to have a fantastic
beer at the beginning of the tour. The castle was very different than other castles I&rsquo;ve seen. The distictive
feature was the cathedral but the surrounding buildings were much different. At the end of the tour, I really
enjoyed walking through the <a href="http://www.hrad.cz/en/prague-castle/guidepost-for-visitors/gardens-of-the-prague-castle.shtml#a5">garden around the ramparts</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Overall, I really enjoyed Prague. You really need to avoid the square as much as possible. Once out of the tourist area,
everything is quite afforable and less hectic. Even though my stay was short, I felt that I got the most out of it. I
would like to go back and explore further and do some hacking with Jakub though.</p>

<h3>Arriving in Budapest</h3>

<p>My stay was short in Prague because I had to get to Budapest for the last of my Grand Prix adventure. Fortunately it was
a direct train! The <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/1767274">airbnb</a> was close to the station and was able to take the metro there. I was really happy with the
location, and the host was exceptional in responding to my queries. One interesting thing about taking the train around
Europe is that you start to see patterns in the train stations from different countries. There was quite a difference
between the stations in Czech Republic and Slovakia compared to Germany and Hungary. Now I want to create an archive of
train stations so I can do more comparing and contrasting.</p>

<h3>Hungarian Grand Prix</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-bags.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-bags.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>Getting to the race track was a fairly painless experience in Budapest. The transit workers were also extremely helpful
and knowledgable about the logistics of the race. The track was located in a beautiful area just outside Budapest. I
spent the Friday walking around the track (in 35C weather). The track area was super clean and I think that&rsquo;s owed to
the fact that bright blue garbage bags were never more than 20ft away from you. Overall, I would say this Grand Prix had
the most pleasant logistics experience. More importantly though, this was an <a href="http://www.autoblog.com/2014/07/28/race-recap-2014-hungarian-grand-prix-a-thrilling-wet-mess/">incredible race</a>! A cloud burst occured
around 60 minutes before the race began. All the drivers had to change their strategies and start with wet tyres. Then
an accident occured a few laps in that caused some pit lane confusion resulting in the leaders being in the middle of
the pack. Nearly every lap had battles going on from all positions. I think this ranks up there as one of the best races
of the year (Bahrain was pretty close). I&rsquo;m sort of sad that my stream of F1 races is over, but also happy because now
the rest of my time is entirely unscheduled. Who knows, maybe I&rsquo;ll do a quick detour to Belgium and go to the race there
at the end of the month.</p>

<br />


<br />


<h3>Dream Theater in Budapest</h3>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dream-theater.jpg"><img class="right" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/dream-theater.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>As a bonus I saw posters stating that <a href="http://www.dreamtheater.net/">Dream Theater</a> is playing nearby! I&rsquo;ve been a fan of them since 1998 and have never
seen them live! Everything looked too perfect: the venue was a beautiful tram ride away, it starts after the majority of
the F1 events are done, it ended at a decent hour so I could be rested for race day, and tickets were still available!
After freshening up after another hot day at the track I walk to the tram and arrive at the venue around an hour before
the show starts. I was in line to grab some food when the woman next to me asks me a question in Hungarian. Here we go
again! I respond with &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry?&rdquo;. She switches to English and asks if I was
ahead of her. I had no idea, and it didn&rsquo;t really matter to me so I said she was first. As I get my food, she asks where
I&rsquo;m from. I tell her I&rsquo;m going to find some beer and she offers to show me where I can sample some
proper Hungarian liquor. I follow her lead and she orders me palinka which is a fruit brandy. Fortunately I&rsquo;m well
adapted to plum whiskey from hazy memories of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G7Eb7a8-LvQ">ThoughtBoarder</a> trips (thanks <a href="http://www.yycapps.com/2012/09/developer-interview-radu-muresan/">Radu</a>), so the shot goes down easy. She says
she needs to bring the food back to her group and I bid farewell and find a spot in the crowd to watch the show. Ten or
fifteen minutes pass and she finds me in the crowd. We continue to chat about music, travel and Hungary. It turns out
that her dad brought her to the concert (coolest dad in the world!), and she asked if it was ok to hang out with me
during the show (you had to ask?!). You would think that I would have learned my lesson from my previous female
encounter&hellip; nope. Though I did do a bit better. I wrote down my website and she asked if she could find me on Facebook
(I wasn&rsquo;t sure if my profile was searchable, but I said yes). The show was fantastic and made better by having her company.
I got a message from her a few days later and we&rsquo;re still corresponding! Clearly something supernatural was going on as
you can tell from this image of the show.</p>

<p><a href="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-view.jpg"><img class="left" src="http://scottmuc.com/images/blog/career-break/budapest-view.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>The weather following the race was not so good. I managed to explore a little bit around the vicinity of where I was
staying, but spent most of the time catching up with Coursera. Sandeman did not have any presence in Budapest so I took
a free tour by another organization. I can&rsquo;t say it was up to the same standard, but it was still informative
nevertheless. It ended near the castle and I enjoyed a relatively rain free walk back to my flat and prepared for my
next destination, Rome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
