<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Yearly-goals | More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/yearly-goals/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-06-10T18:41:05+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Resolutions for 2019]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2019/"/>
    <updated>2019-02-16T20:12:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2019</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Reflections on <a href="/my-resolutions-for-2018/">2018</a></h2>

<p>This will be easy because I didn’t set any goals last year! It felt great to take a break from goal setting
because 2018 was a big year of transition. I <a href="/moving-back-to-berlin/">moved yet again</a> and I started a new role at work.
I then found that it didn’t fit me and I finally had some self awareness to reach out for help and was able
to switch roles again to something that suits me at this moment in time.</p>

<p>Here are some things I discovered about myself in 2018:</p>

<ul>
<li>Working from home for the first time and I absolutely love it! I don&rsquo;t believe I&rsquo;ll ever go back to
having a regular commute again.</li>
<li>My travel hunger has been satiated. I will be minimizing my travel until my appetite grows for it again.</li>
<li>Berlin is truly where I want to settle down in the long term. So much so that I’ve bought a home
here and I&rsquo;ve just finished moving in!</li>
<li>I love writing, but sometimes my output doesn&rsquo;t reach the public domain. I&rsquo;ve written more in 2018
than probably any other year.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Goals for 2019:</h2>

<p>As always there are so many things I would like to do. I had a dozen blog post drafts that I ended up purging. I need to work
on my physical health too. Those who know me know that I have some very specific financial goals. To keep things
simple, I&rsquo;m going to stick with one goal and approach it more like a project. For 2019, I would like to end the
year with a published <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let's_Play">Let&rsquo;s Play</a> that has at least 50 views of the final
video in the series. This ought to be a good test on whether or not game recordings is something worth pursuing.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve sneakily already started on my goal with a completed series of Civilization VI! So far it&rsquo;s only been shared
with a private group of friends.</p>

<p>By-the-way, journaling (<a href="/my-resolutions-for-2016/">goal from 2016</a>) has been the one habit that I’ve cultivated
and has lasted several years! Here are the numbers:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/journaling-at-end-of-2018.png"></p>

<p><em>No pomodoros were harmed in the making of this post (I composed this while watching a Stellaris stream)</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Resolutions for 2018]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2018/"/>
    <updated>2018-01-02T01:13:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2018</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Reflections on <a href="/my-resolutions-for-2017/">2017</a></h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Perform 1 pull up</strong> &ndash; This didn&rsquo;t go so well. I&rsquo;m now the heaviest that I&rsquo;ve ever been (95kg). My psoriasis (scalp) has become really annoying and gets worse when I exercise. So 2017 wasn&rsquo;t a good year for my health. It&rsquo;s very clear that I don&rsquo;t handle disruption of my routine very well. Below is a graph of my workouts:</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/workouts-2017.png" width="1024"></p>

<p>Only 1 or 2 of those gaps was related to illness; most of them were due to travel (work and play). The last few months was me being preoccupied with my move to Berlin (yet another excuse).</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>journaling</strong> &ndash; I also took a look at if I adhered to my <a href="/my-resolutions-for-2016/">2016</a> goal to maintain a journal. The following graph shows that I started the year off strong and then it faded away for a bit.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/journal-entries-2017.png" width="1024"></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been looking back in my journal periodically now and finding it a great source of insight into what my previous self was thinking. I&rsquo;m happy I&rsquo;ve started picking it up last month.</p>

<h2>Goal for 2018:</h2>

<p>Inspired by <a href="https://medium.com/@catehstn/the-2018liberation-list-4e229bdbb919">Cate Huston</a>, I&rsquo;m going to liberate myself from making a goal for this year. I&rsquo;ve just moved back to Berlin and will spend this year settling in and exploring.</p>

<p>This doesn&rsquo;t mean I&rsquo;m not going to doing anything about my personal health, I just am not deciding what it is at this current moment.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>2018 is going to be a year of settling down and some reflection. I&rsquo;m happy to have found a home where I&rsquo;m excited by the prospect of being there for many years. I&rsquo;m just going to let that feeling spawn iniatives as the year goes on.</p>

<p><em>This post took 2 pomodoro to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Resolutions for 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2017/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-02T14:07:40+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2016 was the first time I accomplished my goal!</p>

<h2>Reflections on <a href="/my-resolutions-for-2016/">2016</a></h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Write in a Journal</strong> &ndash; This one I am marking as a success.  Here are the (manually) calculated stats:</li>
</ul>


<p><code>
Jan 9
Feb 3
Mar 12
Apr 9
May 15
Jun 9
Jul 13
Aug 14
Sep 12
Oct 14
Nov 9
Dec 12
</code></p>

<p>I wrote <strong>143</strong> journal entries over the course of 2016.  After counting them all up there are far fewer than I thought,
but the frequency is actually more consistent than I thought. I had imagined I had more months that only had a couple
entries. I see this as my first step in writing more and hopefully bringing it to this website. Seeing that my
journalling actually increased by the end of the year makes me really happy. I&rsquo;m going to continue this in 2017 for
sure.</p>

<h2>Goal for 2017:</h2>

<p>In the spirit of keeping my goal(s) simple and achievable I&rsquo;m going to stick to a similar strategy as 2016.</p>

<h3>Perform 1 Perfect Pullup</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s been many years since I&rsquo;ve been able to do a pullup. My body finally feels recovered from my previous injuries, but
it&rsquo;s certainly weaker than it&rsquo;s ever been. My <a href="/health/">health dashboard</a> has already helped me reach a gym
going habit, but now I need to direct this routine to a different end. I cannot do the physical things I used to because
I&rsquo;ve gotten so out of shape and my previous focus on running put too much pressure on my weak body.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>As I grow older, the length of a year seems much shorter. I wonder if my previous <a href="/blog/categories/yearly-goals/">goals</a> were a result of not
acknowledging how much I can possibly do in that time frame.</p>

<p><em>This post took 1 pomodoro to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Resolutions for 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-02T02:08:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post almost didn&rsquo;t happen. 2015 holds a lot of dead-air from me in the blogging world, but I&rsquo;m so compelled by my
routines that I felt that I had to do it! Honouring a self-made routine/tradition is my achilles heel and my biggest
strength at the same time.</p>

<h2>Reflections on <a href="/my-resolutions-for-2015/">2015</a></h2>

<p>2015 wasn&rsquo;t a good year for sticking to my goals, but I still learned a lot on the way:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Brew Beer</strong> &ndash; Didn&rsquo;t do well here since I didn&rsquo;t brew a single batch, but there was a lot of taste testing!</li>
<li><strong>Nurture a Healthy Habit</strong> &ndash; The year was off to a great start until I injured my leg. I attempted to get back into
running a bit too strong and injured myself again. If there&rsquo;s something positive I can take from this though is
that I still wish to run. It&rsquo;s been a very frustrating year as a result because I missed running in Berlin during
the best time of the year! I ended up gaining weight, which made me not feel so good about myself and other healthy
habits collapsed as well. The good news is that the desire is still there and I just need get back slowly.</li>
<li><strong>Think More Critically</strong> &ndash; This one is a strange one because I don&rsquo;t have anything countable to associate with it. In the
end I feel more clueless about everything. As I put a critical focus on anything it opens up complexity that I had
never imagined. Now I&rsquo;m not sure how people are so sure about anything! I need to stop listening to so many economics
podcasts ;&ndash;).</li>
</ul>


<p>That being said, I kicked arse on a <a href="/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014/">2014 resolution</a> which was to learn <a href="https://www.docker.com/">Docker</a>! Docker is a core
piece of technology in what I was working on at <a href="/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">SoundCloud</a>.</p>

<p>Looking back, 2015 was a difficult year to make such goals. I&rsquo;ve found a lot of interesting tactics on
<a href="http://jamesclear.com/good-habits">James Clear&rsquo;s article about good habits</a>. How would things been different had I set the goal to 1 run
per month? Even with my injury I&rsquo;m sure I would have been more proactive in testing the waters with a single 3k run each month.
Also, why not make the beer brewing goal a single brew for the entire year? I held back on brewing because I was
intimidated by the equipment I would have had to purchase and store. If it was one brew, I would have simply
brewed with the few people that I&rsquo;ve met in Berlin that do home brewing. Then again, it&rsquo;s easy to say that
in retrospect.</p>

<h2>Goal for 2016:</h2>

<p>This year I&rsquo;m going on a bit of a tangent from previous years. I feel I pushed 2015 too hard. It was more work than I
had anticipated. A good challenge but I set my expectations too high. 2016 is likely to be similar with moving to a new
city and starting a new job (post on that coming later this month). So I&rsquo;m only going to make 1 goal. I see it as a
realigning goal, a course correction from the journey that started when I left <a href="/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">ThoughtWorks back in 2014</a>.</p>

<h3>Write in a Journal</h3>

<p>I have the urge to write, but the public forum doesn&rsquo;t feel right. A real physical book where my text doesn&rsquo;t flow
through prying eyes wanting to find patterns, so that they can serve me better ads. I&rsquo;ve been
fairly public with my life and I&rsquo;m curious about taking that down a notch. My head feels like a swirling mass of
ideas that hasn&rsquo;t quite found its outlet (though those who have been out drinking with me when the topic of
economics comes up, would beg to differ).</p>

<p>Think of it as close-sourcing my thoughts. Once public, it&rsquo;s hard to make things private, but the other way is
certainly possible.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>A bit of a change from the usual. Let&rsquo;s see how things are in a year, shall we?</p>

<p><em>This post took 2 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Resolutions for 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-02T02:08:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/my-resolutions-for-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This has become a bit of a tradition for me so I can&rsquo;t quite writing these now. This one will be a bit different than
the previous ones though. Normally these posts are my <em>technical</em> resolutions. I&rsquo;m not that ambitious anymore when it
comes to technical learning so I&rsquo;ve dropped that from the title. Even though I tend to despise meaningless dates, I look
at resolutions as one large <a href="http://pomodorotechnique.com/">pomodoro</a>. So the tradition lives on!</p>

<h2>Reflections on <a href="/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014/">2014</a></h2>

<p>Going on a <a href="/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a> sort of twisted everything around in 2014. Still, it was interesting to see how
I did:</p>

<ul>
<li>Increase Signal to Noise Ration &ndash; I&rsquo;m only following 118 people on Twitter now as opposed to 627, but my &ldquo;friend&rdquo;
count on FaceBook went up to 507 from 480. Considering that Twitter is where most of the noise comes from, I think I
succeeded in this goal.</li>
<li>Learn Docker &ndash; I&rsquo;ve yet to run the docker CLI, so didn&rsquo;t go far with this. I&rsquo;m not terribly interested in it now as my
frustration with tech is still there. 2015 may be a success if I still don&rsquo;t touch docker.</li>
<li>Do Meaningful Work &ndash; Does quitting my job and traveling the world for 9 months count as success? It does to me so I
think I slayed this resolution! I&rsquo;m also getting back into the <a href="/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">workforce</a> with a company that is in a domain I care
about and I&rsquo;ve gotten the opportunity to be on the board of advisors for an interesting <a href="http://zolair-energy.com/">clean energy start up</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Goals for 2015:</h2>

<p>I think the time off has given me a new perspective. These goals are more about looking at myself externally and
figuring out what kind of design changes to I want to make on myself.</p>

<h3>Brew Beer</h3>

<p>Given that I want to look into the business of beer, it would help if I&rsquo;ve actually brewed some. I believe brewing 10
batches is a reasonable goal. If I can&rsquo;t do this, then I can safely drop the idea of building a beer related business in
the future. I enjoy publishing my <a href="https://twitter.com/todayschai">chai</a> experiments and I&rsquo;ll do the same thing with my beer brewing. Will
probably publish them on this blog for now.</p>

<p><strong>Progress</strong>: 0 batches brewed</p>

<h3>Nurture a Healthy Habit</h3>

<p>Over the last 15 years of my life I&rsquo;ve ridden a health rollercoaster. I can&rsquo;t recall any year where I didn&rsquo;t go
off the routine and regress to my old unhealthy habits. This year I&rsquo;m aiming to be more proactive around my habits and
plan a bit better when I can see potential for a habit to break (eg: when traveling, or a busy period). My goal is run
at least 10 times every month. Be sure to verify my results on <a href="http://www.strava.com/athletes/6575733">Strava</a>. I am training for a half marathon but
this is very typical of my health ambitions. Do something big, and then stop.</p>

<p><strong>January</strong>: 19 runs<br/>
<strong>February</strong>: 13 runs<br/>
<strong>March</strong>: 6 runs (strained hamstring injury)<br/>
<strong>April</strong>:<br/>
<strong>May</strong>:<br/>
<strong>June</strong>:<br/>
<strong>July</strong>:<br/>
<strong>August</strong>:<br/>
<strong>September</strong>:<br/>
<strong>October</strong>:<br/>
<strong>November</strong>:<br/>
<strong>December</strong>:<br/></p>

<h3>Think More Critically</h3>

<p>This could be due to having a lot of time to consume too much media over the last year, but I feel that I should be more
thoughtful in my communication and critical of my messages. It&rsquo;s easy to type out a pithy tweet skipping a load of
context. When being critical I will do due dilligence in citing research when trying to impose my ideas, or at least be
more transparent in pointing out how much is anecdotal. This one is a tougher one to measure. The only thing I can think
of is comparing the number of tweets over the course of the years, and having source lists in all my blog posts (or
stating the source are my own observations and are completely theoretical).</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>When reading my <a href="/my-developer-resolutions-for-2014/">2014 post</a> I can tell that I was getting jaded about the IT industry. It looks like I&rsquo;m still a bit
jaded, but this time I&rsquo;m steering the ship away from IT a bit. Let&rsquo;s see what these new waters are like.</p>

<p><em>This post took 2 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
