<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Career Break | More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-13T09:55:45-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaving Vancouver and North America]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-13T09:10:36-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After another relaxing two weeks in Vancouver (and attending <a href="http://www.sasquatchfestival.com/">Sasquatch</a>), it&rsquo;s time to leave. Here&rsquo;s the
last sunset I watched from the beach. If you can believe it, the weather in Vancouver was 99% rain free!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/kits-sunset.jpg"></p>

<h3>Schools Out for Summer</h3>

<p>During my downtime I&rsquo;ve enrolled in the <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/money">Economics of Banking and Money</a> on <a href="https://www.coursera.org">Coursera</a>. I never
thought I would find learning this stuff so much fun! To supplement the course material, I&rsquo;ve been listening to the
following podcasts too:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/">Planet Money</a></li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/radio/">Freakanomics Radio</a></li>
</ul>


<p>This is the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course">MOOC</a> I&rsquo;ve taken and I really enjoy the format. It could be the fact that I&rsquo;m older and have
already been established in a career for a while that my approach to learning is different. School always seemed to be
about grades to me growing up. With this course, I&rsquo;m more focused on learning and developing an intuition for the
subject.</p>

<p>From this course I&rsquo;ve learned that the banking and money system is a lot more complicated than I thought. I also now
feel that the system itself isn&rsquo;t altogether evil, it&rsquo;s just trying to facilitate trade the best that it can. I&rsquo;m still
not confident in my ability to summarize what I&rsquo;ve learnt so far, but I think I&rsquo;m going to come out of this much more
empowered.</p>

<h3>Ship Happens</h3>

<p>Today I finally start my voyage on a container ship! You can track where I am on this <a href="http://www.marinetraffic.com/ais/details/ships/636091353/vessel:INDEPENDENT_ACCORD">Facebook for ships</a>
website. If you search for the name &ldquo;Independent Accord&rdquo; in your favourite online search website
you&rsquo;ll see there are dozens of websites that have databases of ships. The websites are pretty well done too. I had no
idea this shipping world can be so interesting. I&rsquo;m sure the captain and crew are going to be sick of my questions over
the next 11 days.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested, <a href="http://www.cruisepeople.co.uk/">here&rsquo;s</a> that I booked my travel through. If you&rsquo;re nostalgic for the 90&rsquo;s you&rsquo;ll
enjoy it a lot.</p>

<h3>Map Reduce</h3>

<p>Since I have all this time on my hands, I&rsquo;ve started journalling the places that I&rsquo;m staying (and coffee shops I leech
Internet off of) in this <a href="https://mapsengine.google.com/map/edit?mid=znoHAqfzfPKU.k2lUp8fKHDCg">online map</a>. It&rsquo;s work in progress and will be fleshed out more as I go.</p>

<h3>Back to Life, Back to Reality</h3>

<p>One question I&rsquo;ve been getting asked frequently is &ldquo;when are you coming back to reality?&rdquo;. I find it an odd question.
This is reality. There&rsquo;s nothing to get back to (unless I could travel in time). Sure, I&rsquo;ll be figuring out what to do
work wise. Not sure how that&rsquo;s coming &ldquo;back&rdquo; to reality though. I think we&rsquo;re living in an era where social norms are
shifting all over the place. Hopes and aspirations appear to be more varied than before. One persons normality is
another persons exceptionality. So when I hear this question my interpretation is &ldquo;when are you coming back to the
lifestyle of yours that I consider normal?&rdquo;.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m starting to feel the career break settling in. I&rsquo;ve slowed things down a lot. My favourite thing to do now is leave
my phone behind and go for a wander. Writing blog posts like this is much more fulfilling than a series of micro-blogs
(aka tweets) that lack context, albeit they are more timely.</p>

<p>See you on the other side!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Weeks Living Off the Clock]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/two-weeks-living-off-the-clock/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T19:14:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/two-weeks-living-off-the-clock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the last two weeks I&rsquo;ve been house sitting for a friend in the beautiful area of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kitsilano">Kitsalano</a> in Vancouver. The
goal for the two weeks was to figure out the rest of my travel plans and to meet up with a lot of my friends and
acquaintances that I haven&rsquo;t seen for a while.</p>

<h3>According to Plan?</h3>

<p>The two weeks went by quickly. I mainly organized myself around other people&rsquo;s clocks. This meant meeting people for
lunch or after work the majority of the time. Since I had gaps in time between meet ups, I spent a lot of time walking
everywhere (and sometimes biking). Experiencing many modes of transportation ends up being an influence on me later on.
It was refreshing to not be the dictator of my time, albeit my intentions did dictate who to meet. So by a transitive
relationship, I was still directing my time?</p>

<h3>Natural Time Management</h3>

<p>As an experiment I decided to not turn my morning alarm clock on. I&rsquo;ve always thought of myself as a morning person and
wanted to see if that held true. What ended up happening was that I rolled out of bed around 8:30pm every morning
regardless of when I went to bed (range: 11:00pm &ndash; 1:00am). I&rsquo;m curious about whether or not work pressure (or pressure
in general) has been the cause of my normal much earlier natural wake up time.</p>

<p>Another normal time structure that I thought my body adhered to strictly was when to eat. I started to eat when I was hungry
and found that some days I only ate 1 meal, or my lunch ended up happening at 4pm. There wasn&rsquo;t any natural rhythm to my
eating times.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s interesting to start following nature&rsquo;s conventions rather than socially, and I guess structurally imposed ones.</p>

<h3>Career Ideas</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s nice when part of my &ldquo;mission&rdquo; with this career break moves forward in some dimension. During my many walks along
the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seawall_(Vancouver)">seawall</a> I&rsquo;ve listened to many episodes of <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a>. One in particular got me a little bit
inspired. The episode was about <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/charles_marohn.html">Strong Towns</a>, and revealed that I have a lot of interest in urban
development. Shortly after that, I had dinner with a colleague, and conversation with his girlfriend got me inspired
too. It turns out she works for <a href="http://www.translink.ca/">TransLink</a> and she mentioned there&rsquo;s work available for someone with my
skills. What fascinated me was my initial feeling of joy to chat with someone regarding this topic.</p>

<p>Did I mention that I&rsquo;m slowing getting addicted to <a href="http://www.positech.co.uk/democracy3/">Democracy 3</a>?</p>

<h3>Speaking of Transport</h3>

<p>Being mobile via foot, bike, bus, train, and car share has reinforced my thoughts on urban planning. Another part of my
&ldquo;mission&rdquo; is to figure out where to live. Being mobile, while having a low impact, is an opinion that has been further
strengthened while being here. The bicycle is such a wonderful piece of engineering that has changed, relatively, little
over the years. It&rsquo;s an efficient form of transport and it&rsquo;s fun. I can&rsquo;t imagine living anywhere where I wouldn&rsquo;t feel
comfortable riding a bike much of the time.</p>

<h3>Discovering the Source of My Anxiety</h3>

<p>In my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month/">previous post</a> I alluded to a sense of anxiousness that I was feeling. It dawned on me that I was spending a lot of
time coordinating what was going to be a hurried and expensive road trip across the continent. Eventually I realized
that I didn&rsquo;t have to do that trip. I&rsquo;m already going to be doing plenty of travel in the coming months. It also
occurred to me that I spent a good amount of my &ldquo;relaxing&rdquo; time trying to make this trip work. So I&rsquo;ve canceled the
road trip and am going to spend an extra two weeks in Vancouver!</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the list of reasons that convinced that this was the right decision:</p>

<ul>
<li>Not providing ample time to truly enjoy the trip</li>
<li>Not being able to spend a proper amount of time visiting each and every person</li>
<li>Going to be more expensive than the cargo ship cruise!</li>
<li>Goes against the principles of this career break which is to take things slowly and this road trip would be a dash to Wilmington, NC</li>
<li>Lessons learned from the SF road trip (I should have slowed it down)</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m not doing any of the tech related practice I&rsquo;ve wanted to do</li>
</ul>


<p>Not sure if the software analogy fits, but it felt like removing scope from an unfinished project.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>Responding to feedback is important. On my road trip to San Francisco I learned that I&rsquo;m not going slow enough during my
time off. During the last two weeks in Vancouver I learned that it&rsquo;s nice to stand still and I wasn&rsquo;t doing too much of
that. The speed of the journey and the complexity in coordinating amongst many people and locations was resulting in an
energy level overhead that was creating anxiety (and how can someone who&rsquo;s not working possibly feel anxious about
anything). Responding to this feedback by canceling the road trip made me feel like a weight was lifted off of my
shoulders.</p>

<p>Along with the negative feedback, I&rsquo;m going to explore the positive feedback my mind felt when pondering ideas around
urban planning and public transport.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I won&rsquo;t get to see a lot of people that I wanted to, but I realized the quality of the interactions is more
important than the quantity of the interactions. This touches on my principle of doing things slowly during this break.
No better way to go slow than to stand still. Queue the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dMSFqXGZ5TQ">Rush</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections of Being Unemployed and Homeless for 1 Month]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-12T22:13:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For some context, you may want to read my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">previous post</a> about quitting my job.</p>

<p>I am homeless and unemployed in probably the most priveleged meaning of the terms. Both states of being are choices I&rsquo;ve
explicitly made. From what I&rsquo;ve read, I&rsquo;m not really on a sabbatical, but I&rsquo;m on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Career_break">Career Break</a>, except the homeless
aspect of it is not as conventional.</p>

<p>So here are the reflections:</p>

<h3>Where Am I Sleeping Tonight</h3>

<p>On September 1st 2012 I gave up my awesome apartment in Calgary as I prepared for an assignment in India (without
really knowing where I was going after that). I changed my mailing address to my brothers place and really didn&rsquo;t feel
much had changed. I had already been travelling weekly for my work assignments since April 2011, and I picked up my life
and departed <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/a-new-beginning-or-goodbye-20-s-hello-30-s/">Vancouver to Calgary</a> in January 2010.</p>

<p>In the last month I&rsquo;ve spent 13 nights in different beds. One of those nights was part of a 30 hour trip from
Johannesburg to Vancouver, and another night was one where I lost my dignity in Vegas (ask me to show you the scar one
day). I&rsquo;ve learned there&rsquo;s a lot of overhead in figuring out where you&rsquo;re going to sleep (and I have it easy compared to
those who aren&rsquo;t homeless by choice).</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s hit me those most is the disappearance of the sense of belonging. For 8 months I &ldquo;lived&rdquo; in a Residence Inn in
Bellevue, Washington and it was as much of a home as anywhere. I belonged there, had my routine haunts, and knew where I
was going to be for weeks on end. Nowadays I&rsquo;m either imposing on friends and family, or spending too much for a
hotel&hellip; ok, and using home sharing websites which is like a hybrid of the two.</p>

<p>So I guess this break has been successful in teaching me something already. I need to find a place to live. I do like
the traveling lifestyle, but only when I have a home base.</p>

<h3>Talk Talk Talk</h3>

<p>For some reason, this first month break started off strong with lots of conversations with people in the tech industry.
Maybe I was seeking the familiar so these conversations fit in my comfort zone. I&rsquo;ve probably spoken to over 10 or so
companies and am journaling my pursuits as I go. I&rsquo;ve added a constraint on my life that I won&rsquo;t work for 6 months so
it&rsquo;s hard to not jump on what seem to be great opportunities.</p>

<h3>No Startup For Me</h3>

<p>As a technologist, I&rsquo;m passionate about open standards and infrastructure that makes the Internet work. The last thing I
would want as a startup is for my company name to be a verb (eg: Uber, Tweet). Technology like: SMTP, HTTP, HTML, DNS
aren&rsquo;t corporate brand names. I like to live in abstractions, and as a business owner, I think that&rsquo;s probably the worst
characteristic I could probably have in order to be successful.</p>

<p>In fact, I&rsquo;ve challenged myself to minimize the brands names I speak unless it&rsquo;s trully an endorsement for the brand.
Here are some of the translations I&rsquo;m attempting to do:</p>

<ul>
<li>Tweet &ndash;> microblog</li>
<li>Uber &ndash;> rideshare</li>
<li>Nexus 4 &ndash;> phone</li>
<li>Coke &ndash;> cola</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://www.marriott.com/">Marriott</a>, on the other hand, is a brand I&rsquo;m happy to publicly endorse.</p>

<p>So yeah&hellip; given that one aspect of success for a startup is something I&rsquo;m not advocating, I think it&rsquo;ll be hard for me
to be part of a startup. Though, I think this really depends on the state of the startup.</p>

<h3>I&rsquo;m Super Lucky</h3>

<p>Part of what has made this break possible is the amazing network of friends and aquaintances I&rsquo;ve made over the years. There
are couches available to me all over the world and that&rsquo;s something I feel super blessed about. I really have to thank
<a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/join">ThoughtWorks</a> for enabling me to meet people from everywhere and make these connections.</p>

<h3>A Hint of Concern</h3>

<p>You would think after 1 month of not working I would feel stress free. For some reason there&rsquo;s still a hanging anxiety.
Part of it is probably my first point about finding a home. The other is that I feel there&rsquo;s something bigger that I
should be doing. Being in Vancouver for the last little while has sparked a stream of nostalgia and reflections on a
simpler and a more naive past.</p>

<h3>Familiar is Good</h3>

<p>This probably isn&rsquo;t a surprise to anyone that knows me, but I&rsquo;m a fan of the familiar. When I drove down to Seattle, I
visited <a href="http://www.oobatooba.com/">Ooba Tooba</a> and <a href="http://bathtubginseattle.com/">Bathtub Gin</a>. In San Francisco I went to the <a href="http://www.beresford.com/beresford/restaurant.htm">White Horse Tavern</a>. Anytime I go back to a place I
haven&rsquo;t been to in a while, I favour hitting the familiar places rather than trying something new. This is clearly part
of who I am and find it something I can&rsquo;t negotiate.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I have no idea how to summarize anything right now. The focus is on data ingress and going to delegate the analysis to a
later time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaving a Dream Job and Going on an Adventure]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-26T14:28:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On January 4th 2010 I joined <a href="/blog/a-new-beginning-or-goodbye-20-s-hello-30-s/">ThoughtWorks</a> and it has been an amazing journey. I&rsquo;ve seen more systems,
worked with more people, and seen more countries than the entire 30 years that preceded that date. I still can&rsquo;t believe
how lucky I&rsquo;ve been to have such a wonderful opportunity. That&rsquo;s why it took me a long time to decide to leave it, and
go on a bit of an adventure.</p>

<h2>Why Leave Such a Good Thing?</h2>

<p>For some reason I&rsquo;ve had every job I&rsquo;ve had for 4 years since I was 12 years old, so I&rsquo;m just keeping to my routine! To
be honest though, there were a few things that instigated this change.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Consulting Fatigue</strong> &ndash; It&rsquo;s hard work always coming in as an outsider and trying to convince people to change their
ways. You never know if what you suggest is correct, and there&rsquo;s always so much context to process. One thing that I&rsquo;ve gotten
out of this though is becoming much more of a critical thinker. I&rsquo;ve learned to hold off on knee-jerk reactions and to
actively listen to the problem at hand. This has been something I apply on a day-to-day basis.</li>
<li><strong>Product Complacency</strong> &ndash; Though, I&rsquo;ve worked on some interesting projects (the latest being very cool), I can&rsquo;t shake
the satisfaction I got from working at <a href="http://music.cbc.ca/radio3/">CBC Radio 3</a> where I got to essentially build the product I wanted to
build on my own anyways. This may have been mitigated but the following reason adds to this one.</li>
<li><strong>Miss Small Teams</strong> &ndash; For some reason people thought I was great at working on large programs of work. While I thought
the challenges were interesting, I&rsquo;m more a small business person at heart. Some may be surprised by this because I&rsquo;ve
been on small teams, but they were in these large programs of work. I&rsquo;ve learned that I&rsquo;m more of a system thinker than I
thought and I find myself getting lost in the system thinking and see myself as this tiny insignificant cog just
wanting to make some impactful change.</li>
</ul>


<p>Though I&rsquo;m listing things related to ThoughtWorks, a lot of my weariness is more from IT in general. It could be an age
thing, but I&rsquo;ve been around long enough to see a lot of terrible things going on in this industry. No one seems to care
about security, and the innovation that is making billions in the stock market are consumer products that mean almost
nothing to me. It&rsquo;s hard to be optimistic after <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Snowden">Edward Snowden</a> revealed the NSA privacy issues.</p>

<p>In the last few years I&rsquo;ve managed to save some money, and given that I&rsquo;m still relatively young and healthy, I thought
now is the time to take a break before I get too cynical.</p>

<h2>What am I Going to do?</h2>

<p>The plan right now is pretty loose, but I have made a rough 6 month itinerary:</p>

<ul>
<li>Head back to North America. This will involve crashing at my brother&rsquo;s places and spend some time with family
and friends.</li>
<li>Do some roadtrips in Canada and the USA.</li>
<li>Taking a cargo ship across the Atlantic.</li>
<li>July is the month of Formula 1! I have tickets for the British GP and the German GP.</li>
<li>Visit Eastern Europe.</li>
<li>Hang out in India for a couple months.</li>
</ul>


<p>Along with the travels, I will be taking some mental journeys</p>

<ul>
<li>I want to study economics and capitalism. If we&rsquo;re in this prison of a system, I want to be an educated prisoner.</li>
<li>Get back to the basics of software development and attempt to unlearn all this &ldquo;Enterprise&rdquo; cruft I&rsquo;ve picked up.
Hoping to to this by learning a few new languages, doing code katas daily and releasing tiny side projects.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a stretch, but I would like to do some athletic training (mainly running).</li>
</ul>


<p>Like most things, I&rsquo;m probably thinking about it too much, but in this case it&rsquo;s the planning that&rsquo;s been valuable and
not the plan itself.</p>

<h2>Sounds Awesome, but That Cannot Last Forever</h2>

<p>During this time I&rsquo;m attempting to figure out future career ideas. At the end I&rsquo;ll
figure out a place to live and what on my list of interesting domains to pursue:</p>

<ul>
<li>Formula 1</li>
<li>Health care</li>
<li>Beer / Cocktails</li>
<li>Golf</li>
<li>Energy</li>
<li>Public Transportation</li>
<li>Music Distribution</li>
<li>Billiards</li>
<li>Space Exploration</li>
<li>City Planning</li>
<li>Software Delivery</li>
</ul>


<p>Heck, I haven&rsquo;t ruled out re-applying to ThoughtWorks.</p>

<h2>ThoughtWorks Made Me Do This</h2>

<p>The irony is that that ThoughtWorks has opened up my mind in such a way that it&rsquo;s empowered me to make this decision.
The ingress of information, concerns, cultures, opinions and experience is a storm brewing in my head trying it&rsquo;s best to
synthesize itself the best it can. If you&rsquo;re thinking about applying at ThoughtWorks, please ping me. It&rsquo;s an awesome
place to work, and full of great people. During this sabbitcal I plan on visiting as many ThoughtWorkers as I can!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking forward to reading this post a year from now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
