<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Career Break | More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-12T11:20:21+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belgium, France, London and the British Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-08T14:42:19+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Shipment Delivered</h3>

<p>Upon arrival in Antwerp I saw my taxi from the deck. I had all my belongings ready and made my way down
to the port. The ship crew was busy with the offloading of containers so I decided it probably wasn’t a good idea
to disturb them to say farewell. It was a long drive to the immigration office, and there I found out that I needed
a passenger manifest to get the stamp of approval. This meant going all the way back to the ship and back. This
added around an extra hour of taxi travel. The chief mate was ready for my return as he had the document in his
hand. After that confusion, I made it to central Antwerp and found a hotel near the train station.</p>

<p>Antwerp is a fairly small city. The port area takes up more space than the actual city. After a quick nap I wandered
around old Antwerp and in the evening found a little pub. I ended up having more drinks than necessary with a couple
that were a lot of fun. The lady has been in the shipping industry and even knew the ship that I came in on!</p>

<h3>In Bruges</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/bruges.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/bruges.small.jpg" width="300"></a> The trip
from Antwerp to Bruges was pretty easy. As was finding the <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/2176619">residence</a> I was going to stay in. The house was
just outside the old town so after getting some travel logistics out of the way I set out to do a walking tour.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bruges">Bruges</a> is one of the prettiest towns I’ve ever seen. It’s like a snapshot
in time of Belgium several hundred years ago.  In some spots it was insanely crowded, but in other spots it
was quiet and peaceful, which made me stick to those areas. When I got back, I met Lander, the
host of the house. He was very personable and enjoyed conversing with him about my travels.</p>

<p>The next day I did another self guided walking tour. My favourite moment was just relaxing having a couple beers at the
<a href="http://fr.yelp.be/biz/caf%C3%A9-vlissinghe-brugge">oldest tavern</a> in Bruges. After a full day in the town I went back to the house where Lander invited some friends over for
the game. We then headed out to watch the Belgium game in the town square. It was so much fun! I lost the group for a
bit so I gave my round of beers to some random strangers in the crowd. That seemed to make people happy. Next thing I
know it&rsquo;s 5:00am and I&rsquo;m chatting away with a fellow drunk.</p>

<p>These are the beers I had in Belgium:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.dekoninck.be/en">De Koninck</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.boon.be/en/our-beers/geuze-boon-old-style">Gueze Boon</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.rodenbach.be/">Rodenbach</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.trappistwestmalle.be/en/page/dubbel.aspx">Westmalle Trappist Dubbel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.duvel.com/en-us">Duvel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.orval.be/en/58/How-Orval-beer-is-made">Orval</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.abbaye-de-leffe.be/the_beer/en_5_varieties_of_beer_article200.html">Leffe Dark</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/index.php?id=15&amp;L=2">Brugse Zot</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bestbelgianspecialbeers.be/main_eng.html">Tripel Karmeliet</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/index.php?id=14&amp;L=2">Straffe Hendrik</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.achouffe.be/en/beers#la-chouffe">La Chouffe</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Of all of these, I would say the <strong>Tripel Karmeliet</strong> and <strong>Orval</strong> were my favourites. There are so many beers to try
that I really want to come back and spend several weeks sampling all the wonderful beers. There&rsquo;s something about
a country where the monks participate in the brewing process. The day before I got to Bruges, the <a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/">De Halve Maan</a>
had a priest come in and bless their new brewing equipment!</p>

<h3>Dieppe Thoughts</h3>

<p>The next leg of my trip is to Dieppe, France. Unfortunately I woke up hungover and slept through my alarm. This meant
I missed my train which had the best connections to Dieppe. Armed with the
<a href="http://www.eurail.com/plan-your-trip/rail-planner-app">Eurail app</a>, I tried to make a new itinerary.
Due to my decisions of last night, I slept through my connection and passed Brussels. Turned out it didn’t really matter
because at the following station I learned it was the first day of holidays in France and all reservation trains were booked.
Using the app, I figured out an itinerary that could get me to Dieppe without reserved seating. One of the trains was delayed
and I just made my only connecting train with only a minute to spare. Last part of the journey was the walk to to where
I <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/1157655">stayed</a>. The only issue was that I forgot to cache the map, but at least I had a star showing where it
was and functional gps.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/dieppe.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/dieppe.small.jpg" width="300"></a> My primary motivation
for visiting Dieppe was to see the beaches the Canadian troops attempted to invade in WWII. The
invasion of Dieppe preceded D-Day and was used as an information gathering invasion. Essentially they learned a lot at
the expenses of thousands of lives. I’m not a patriotic person, but I couldn’t help but feel moved by the lives that were lost
there. You can read more at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dieppe_Raid">Wikipedia</a> (notice that my picture of the beach
is very close to the image in Wikipedia!</p>

<p>After my walk about, I walked some more! I headed down to where all the restaurants were and had a nice meal and then
proceeded to hang around the beach area to catch the sunset. It was definitely worth it.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/dieppe-sunset.jpg"><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/dieppe-sunset.medium.jpg" width="1024"></a></p>

<h3>A Boat Time</h3>

<p>At 3:30am I left the residence and walked to the ferry terminal. Luckily I walked there the day before so I knew how long
it would take, and that I had to be there at 4:30am. I wasn’t initially planning on being there that early so I’m glad I did
my exploratory research. The ferry was pleasant, but spent the majority of the journey falling asleep and hitting my head against the window.</p>

<h3>London Calling</h3>

<p>The ferry arrived in Newhaven on time. I had a nice chat with the immigration officer who supported my goal of seeing
all the Formula 1 races. I got my luggage and took a series of trains to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hitchin">Hitchin</a> where
I met up with <a href="https://twitter.com/zoodor">Mark</a>, a old ThoughtWorks colleague. It was quite refreshing to see a familiar face!</p>

<p>My next few days were lunch and dinner plans with people I know in London. I got a chance to talk about where my mind
is at regarding my future. It was also nice to see more familiar faces. I really like London, but all the tubing around I was
doing unfortunately left me with a cold before I left.</p>

<h3>Milton Keynes</h3>

<p>This was to be my face for the first F1 on my trip. My <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/1433999">hosts</a> picked up from the
train station. They were amazing hosts and were very pleasant to talk to. I had a lot of fun talking shop
with them as they run an <a href="http://evidencetalks.com/en/">IT business</a> in the city centre.
Their <a href="http://mxcl.github.io/">son</a> is also note-worthy as he created <a href="http://brew.sh/">Homebrew</a>!</p>

<p>The city of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milton_Keynes">Milton Keynes</a> was interesting because it was a planned city.
It was easy to get around, there were plenty of trails that made walking around the periphery quite pleasant.</p>

<h3>This Place is the Bombe!</h3>

<p>I planned for a free day before the race so I could visit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bletchley_Park">Bletchley Park</a>.
It was such an amazing experience to see where
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing">Alan Turing</a> worked and observing a working Colossus, WITCH, and
Bombe machines (in the <a href="http://www.tnmoc.org/">National Museum of Computing</a>)! While visiting the grounds it made
me think about NSA’s involvement in security. If the NSA had a facility that celebrated its ability to crack codes, I don’t think
people would have the same feeling. WWII was great a creating a binary view of activities. Bletchley Park was also
dismantled after the war. I guess things were simpler and less ambiguous then.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what the Colossus sounds like! I wish I recorded a lot more audio because I can hear a song wanting to come out.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no"
src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/157140660&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;visual=true"></iframe>


<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h3>Race 1 of 3</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/british-gp.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/british-gp.small.jpg"></a> The commute to the
track was quite reasonable, but Friday was a bit much for me as I was in the worst part of my cold.
Saturday had the most comfortable weather and I spent a lot of time at the track enjoying different vantage points. Race
day was a big spectacle as it was the 50th race at Silverstone. Before the race there was an air display by the Red Arrows.
It was far better than I had expected. Afterwards I went up to me seat and watched a great race. Lots of drama on the first
lap as Raikonnen had an accident. This red flagged the race as they had to repair a barrier on the track. The rest of the
race was rather uneventful, but the battle between Alonso and Vettel (below) was a show of great driver talent. It was
a shame Roseberg had a malfunction because the battle for 1st could have been just as great.</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/jyhz5c0mR4c 1024 " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<h3>To Glasgow</h3>

<p>The journey continues to Glasgow, Scotland! The write up for that will have to wait though as this post is long
enough. I was going to write about my learnings over the last few weeks, but will hold that thought for a bit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossing the Atlantic via Container Ship]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/crossing-the-atlantic-via-container-ship/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-24T06:02:51+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/crossing-the-atlantic-via-container-ship</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned in my <a href="/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america/">last post</a>, I finished the crossing of the Atlantic ocean via container ship. It was a great
experiene that I&rsquo;ll happily do again. 11 days wasn&rsquo;t enough, and would be happy to spend a month next time around.</p>

<h3>Too Much Twine on my Hands</h3>

<p>A blog post probably wouldn&rsquo;t due the experience justice so I decided to play around with a basic word game engine to
give you a more <a href="/twinery/independent-accord.html">self-directed tour</a>. Hope you enjoy it!</p>

<p>Working with <a href="http://twinery.org/">Twine</a> was quite enjoyable and I could see myself using it a lot in many different lines of work. If I was
still consulting, it would become a prominent tool in my tool-belt. My biggest complaint with it is that the
documentation is all online so I couldn&rsquo;t figure out how to do anything more sophisticated than what I created.</p>

<h3>Man Over-bored</h3>

<p>Honestly, that header was just for the pun factor. What amazed me about the voyage was how quick it went by. I didn&rsquo;t
think <strong>once</strong> that I wanted it to end and that I was bored. I savoured not being in a rush to do anything. The only structure to my
days revolved around meals which were at: 07:30, 12:30, and 17:30. That set my rythym for the 11 days.</p>

<h3>Crew Man Group</h3>

<p>The ship was run by a crew of 21, all male. The captain was Romanian and the rest of the officers were Croation. The chief
engineer was Ukrainian and the rest were Filipino. Everyone was very nice, but when asked for their name, they simply
asked to be addressed by their position (Third, Chief, etc&hellip;).</p>

<h3>Retrospective</h3>

<p><strong>What Went Well</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Scotch &ndash; Sipping 18yo Glenlivet was a wonderful way to be even <em>more</em> relaxed</li>
<li>Jambox &ndash; This dependable gadget has been filling rooms with tunes well for several years now</li>
<li>Offline Wikipedia &ndash; Wow! I cannot believe how much I perused Wikipedia while I was on this trip.</li>
<li>11 days of no expenses &ndash; Being disconnected is a good way to not spend money.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Not So Well</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Gym clothes &ndash; There&rsquo;s an exercise room with a stationary bike. I wasn&rsquo;t always allowed on the main deck (to do laps
around the ship) so being able to do 30min of hard cardio would have been good to stave off the belly I grew.</li>
<li>Scotch &ndash; One bottle was definitely not enough.</li>
<li>Offline map &ndash; I would have liked to better explorer the route and plan the rest of my trip better.</li>
<li>Making Twine tour at the last minute &ndash; I wish I had a skeleton of it done much earlier so I could get more details
from the crew.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Action Items</strong>: I&rsquo;ll definitely do this again and I&rsquo;ll be sure to come with a fitness plan. Though that directly opposes the action to
bring more liquor.</p>

<h3>Offline By Default</h3>

<p>Being disconnected from the world for 11 days was a far better experience than I had expected. It&rsquo;s made me realize I
need to create a habit of disconnecting. It brought me back to the era when your computer was offline by default, and
you had to explicitly connect to see what&rsquo;s going on in the rest of the Internet universe. This experience has showed me
that I like that. It may sound backwards to a lot of people, but the computer has always been a tool, not an
entertainment device (gaming being the exception). My phone may eventually be the only always-connected device, but even
then, I turn off all notifications and keep it silent.</p>

<h3>Let the Eurotrip Begin</h3>

<p>After a 140 euro ride through immigration and into Antwerp, I can begin the next phase of my journey!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaving Vancouver and North America]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-13T15:10:36+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After another relaxing two weeks in Vancouver (and attending <a href="http://www.sasquatchfestival.com/">Sasquatch</a>), it&rsquo;s time to leave. Here&rsquo;s the
last sunset I watched from the beach. If you can believe it, the weather in Vancouver was 99% rain free!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/kits-sunset.jpg"></p>

<h3>Schools Out for Summer</h3>

<p>During my downtime I&rsquo;ve enrolled in the <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/money">Economics of Banking and Money</a> on <a href="https://www.coursera.org">Coursera</a>. I never
thought I would find learning this stuff so much fun! To supplement the course material, I&rsquo;ve been listening to the
following podcasts too:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/">Planet Money</a></li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/radio/">Freakanomics Radio</a></li>
</ul>


<p>This is the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course">MOOC</a> I&rsquo;ve taken and I really enjoy the format. It could be the fact that I&rsquo;m older and have
already been established in a career for a while that my approach to learning is different. School always seemed to be
about grades to me growing up. With this course, I&rsquo;m more focused on learning and developing an intuition for the
subject.</p>

<p>From this course I&rsquo;ve learned that the banking and money system is a lot more complicated than I thought. I also now
feel that the system itself isn&rsquo;t altogether evil, it&rsquo;s just trying to facilitate trade the best that it can. I&rsquo;m still
not confident in my ability to summarize what I&rsquo;ve learnt so far, but I think I&rsquo;m going to come out of this much more
empowered.</p>

<h3>Ship Happens</h3>

<p>Today I finally start my voyage on a container ship! You can track where I am on this <a href="http://www.marinetraffic.com/ais/details/ships/636091353/vessel:INDEPENDENT_ACCORD">Facebook for ships</a>
website. If you search for the name &ldquo;Independent Accord&rdquo; in your favourite online search website
you&rsquo;ll see there are dozens of websites that have databases of ships. The websites are pretty well done too. I had no
idea this shipping world can be so interesting. I&rsquo;m sure the captain and crew are going to be sick of my questions over
the next 11 days.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested, <a href="http://www.cruisepeople.co.uk/">here&rsquo;s</a> that I booked my travel through. If you&rsquo;re nostalgic for the 90&rsquo;s you&rsquo;ll
enjoy it a lot.</p>

<h3>Map Reduce</h3>

<p>Since I have all this time on my hands, I&rsquo;ve started journalling the places that I&rsquo;m staying (and coffee shops I leech
Internet off of) in this <a href="https://mapsengine.google.com/map/edit?mid=znoHAqfzfPKU.k2lUp8fKHDCg">online map</a>. It&rsquo;s work in progress and will be fleshed out more as I go.</p>

<h3>Back to Life, Back to Reality</h3>

<p>One question I&rsquo;ve been getting asked frequently is &ldquo;when are you coming back to reality?&rdquo;. I find it an odd question.
This is reality. There&rsquo;s nothing to get back to (unless I could travel in time). Sure, I&rsquo;ll be figuring out what to do
work wise. Not sure how that&rsquo;s coming &ldquo;back&rdquo; to reality though. I think we&rsquo;re living in an era where social norms are
shifting all over the place. Hopes and aspirations appear to be more varied than before. One persons normality is
another persons exceptionality. So when I hear this question my interpretation is &ldquo;when are you coming back to the
lifestyle of yours that I consider normal?&rdquo;.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m starting to feel the career break settling in. I&rsquo;ve slowed things down a lot. My favourite thing to do now is leave
my phone behind and go for a wander. Writing blog posts like this is much more fulfilling than a series of micro-blogs
(aka tweets) that lack context, albeit they are more timely.</p>

<p>See you on the other side!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Weeks Living Off the Clock]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/two-weeks-living-off-the-clock/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-23T01:14:14+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/two-weeks-living-off-the-clock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the last two weeks I&rsquo;ve been house sitting for a friend in the beautiful area of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kitsilano">Kitsalano</a> in Vancouver. The
goal for the two weeks was to figure out the rest of my travel plans and to meet up with a lot of my friends and
acquaintances that I haven&rsquo;t seen for a while.</p>

<h3>According to Plan?</h3>

<p>The two weeks went by quickly. I mainly organized myself around other people&rsquo;s clocks. This meant meeting people for
lunch or after work the majority of the time. Since I had gaps in time between meet ups, I spent a lot of time walking
everywhere (and sometimes biking). Experiencing many modes of transportation ends up being an influence on me later on.
It was refreshing to not be the dictator of my time, albeit my intentions did dictate who to meet. So by a transitive
relationship, I was still directing my time?</p>

<h3>Natural Time Management</h3>

<p>As an experiment I decided to not turn my morning alarm clock on. I&rsquo;ve always thought of myself as a morning person and
wanted to see if that held true. What ended up happening was that I rolled out of bed around 8:30pm every morning
regardless of when I went to bed (range: 11:00pm &ndash; 1:00am). I&rsquo;m curious about whether or not work pressure (or pressure
in general) has been the cause of my normal much earlier natural wake up time.</p>

<p>Another normal time structure that I thought my body adhered to strictly was when to eat. I started to eat when I was hungry
and found that some days I only ate 1 meal, or my lunch ended up happening at 4pm. There wasn&rsquo;t any natural rhythm to my
eating times.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s interesting to start following nature&rsquo;s conventions rather than socially, and I guess structurally imposed ones.</p>

<h3>Career Ideas</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s nice when part of my &ldquo;mission&rdquo; with this career break moves forward in some dimension. During my many walks along
the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seawall_(Vancouver)">seawall</a> I&rsquo;ve listened to many episodes of <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a>. One in particular got me a little bit
inspired. The episode was about <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/charles_marohn.html">Strong Towns</a>, and revealed that I have a lot of interest in urban
development. Shortly after that, I had dinner with a colleague, and conversation with his girlfriend got me inspired
too. It turns out she works for <a href="http://www.translink.ca/">TransLink</a> and she mentioned there&rsquo;s work available for someone with my
skills. What fascinated me was my initial feeling of joy to chat with someone regarding this topic.</p>

<p>Did I mention that I&rsquo;m slowing getting addicted to <a href="http://www.positech.co.uk/democracy3/">Democracy 3</a>?</p>

<h3>Speaking of Transport</h3>

<p>Being mobile via foot, bike, bus, train, and car share has reinforced my thoughts on urban planning. Another part of my
&ldquo;mission&rdquo; is to figure out where to live. Being mobile, while having a low impact, is an opinion that has been further
strengthened while being here. The bicycle is such a wonderful piece of engineering that has changed, relatively, little
over the years. It&rsquo;s an efficient form of transport and it&rsquo;s fun. I can&rsquo;t imagine living anywhere where I wouldn&rsquo;t feel
comfortable riding a bike much of the time.</p>

<h3>Discovering the Source of My Anxiety</h3>

<p>In my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month/">previous post</a> I alluded to a sense of anxiousness that I was feeling. It dawned on me that I was spending a lot of
time coordinating what was going to be a hurried and expensive road trip across the continent. Eventually I realized
that I didn&rsquo;t have to do that trip. I&rsquo;m already going to be doing plenty of travel in the coming months. It also
occurred to me that I spent a good amount of my &ldquo;relaxing&rdquo; time trying to make this trip work. So I&rsquo;ve canceled the
road trip and am going to spend an extra two weeks in Vancouver!</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the list of reasons that convinced that this was the right decision:</p>

<ul>
<li>Not providing ample time to truly enjoy the trip</li>
<li>Not being able to spend a proper amount of time visiting each and every person</li>
<li>Going to be more expensive than the cargo ship cruise!</li>
<li>Goes against the principles of this career break which is to take things slowly and this road trip would be a dash to Wilmington, NC</li>
<li>Lessons learned from the SF road trip (I should have slowed it down)</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m not doing any of the tech related practice I&rsquo;ve wanted to do</li>
</ul>


<p>Not sure if the software analogy fits, but it felt like removing scope from an unfinished project.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>Responding to feedback is important. On my road trip to San Francisco I learned that I&rsquo;m not going slow enough during my
time off. During the last two weeks in Vancouver I learned that it&rsquo;s nice to stand still and I wasn&rsquo;t doing too much of
that. The speed of the journey and the complexity in coordinating amongst many people and locations was resulting in an
energy level overhead that was creating anxiety (and how can someone who&rsquo;s not working possibly feel anxious about
anything). Responding to this feedback by canceling the road trip made me feel like a weight was lifted off of my
shoulders.</p>

<p>Along with the negative feedback, I&rsquo;m going to explore the positive feedback my mind felt when pondering ideas around
urban planning and public transport.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I won&rsquo;t get to see a lot of people that I wanted to, but I realized the quality of the interactions is more
important than the quantity of the interactions. This touches on my principle of doing things slowly during this break.
No better way to go slow than to stand still. Queue the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dMSFqXGZ5TQ">Rush</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections of Being Unemployed and Homeless for 1 Month]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-13T04:13:53+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For some context, you may want to read my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">previous post</a> about quitting my job.</p>

<p>I am homeless and unemployed in probably the most priveleged meaning of the terms. Both states of being are choices I&rsquo;ve
explicitly made. From what I&rsquo;ve read, I&rsquo;m not really on a sabbatical, but I&rsquo;m on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Career_break">Career Break</a>, except the homeless
aspect of it is not as conventional.</p>

<p>So here are the reflections:</p>

<h3>Where Am I Sleeping Tonight</h3>

<p>On September 1st 2012 I gave up my awesome apartment in Calgary as I prepared for an assignment in India (without
really knowing where I was going after that). I changed my mailing address to my brothers place and really didn&rsquo;t feel
much had changed. I had already been travelling weekly for my work assignments since April 2011, and I picked up my life
and departed <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/a-new-beginning-or-goodbye-20-s-hello-30-s/">Vancouver to Calgary</a> in January 2010.</p>

<p>In the last month I&rsquo;ve spent 13 nights in different beds. One of those nights was part of a 30 hour trip from
Johannesburg to Vancouver, and another night was one where I lost my dignity in Vegas (ask me to show you the scar one
day). I&rsquo;ve learned there&rsquo;s a lot of overhead in figuring out where you&rsquo;re going to sleep (and I have it easy compared to
those who aren&rsquo;t homeless by choice).</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s hit me those most is the disappearance of the sense of belonging. For 8 months I &ldquo;lived&rdquo; in a Residence Inn in
Bellevue, Washington and it was as much of a home as anywhere. I belonged there, had my routine haunts, and knew where I
was going to be for weeks on end. Nowadays I&rsquo;m either imposing on friends and family, or spending too much for a
hotel&hellip; ok, and using home sharing websites which is like a hybrid of the two.</p>

<p>So I guess this break has been successful in teaching me something already. I need to find a place to live. I do like
the traveling lifestyle, but only when I have a home base.</p>

<h3>Talk Talk Talk</h3>

<p>For some reason, this first month break started off strong with lots of conversations with people in the tech industry.
Maybe I was seeking the familiar so these conversations fit in my comfort zone. I&rsquo;ve probably spoken to over 10 or so
companies and am journaling my pursuits as I go. I&rsquo;ve added a constraint on my life that I won&rsquo;t work for 6 months so
it&rsquo;s hard to not jump on what seem to be great opportunities.</p>

<h3>No Startup For Me</h3>

<p>As a technologist, I&rsquo;m passionate about open standards and infrastructure that makes the Internet work. The last thing I
would want as a startup is for my company name to be a verb (eg: Uber, Tweet). Technology like: SMTP, HTTP, HTML, DNS
aren&rsquo;t corporate brand names. I like to live in abstractions, and as a business owner, I think that&rsquo;s probably the worst
characteristic I could probably have in order to be successful.</p>

<p>In fact, I&rsquo;ve challenged myself to minimize the brands names I speak unless it&rsquo;s trully an endorsement for the brand.
Here are some of the translations I&rsquo;m attempting to do:</p>

<ul>
<li>Tweet &ndash;> microblog</li>
<li>Uber &ndash;> rideshare</li>
<li>Nexus 4 &ndash;> phone</li>
<li>Coke &ndash;> cola</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://www.marriott.com/">Marriott</a>, on the other hand, is a brand I&rsquo;m happy to publicly endorse.</p>

<p>So yeah&hellip; given that one aspect of success for a startup is something I&rsquo;m not advocating, I think it&rsquo;ll be hard for me
to be part of a startup. Though, I think this really depends on the state of the startup.</p>

<h3>I&rsquo;m Super Lucky</h3>

<p>Part of what has made this break possible is the amazing network of friends and aquaintances I&rsquo;ve made over the years. There
are couches available to me all over the world and that&rsquo;s something I feel super blessed about. I really have to thank
<a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/join">ThoughtWorks</a> for enabling me to meet people from everywhere and make these connections.</p>

<h3>A Hint of Concern</h3>

<p>You would think after 1 month of not working I would feel stress free. For some reason there&rsquo;s still a hanging anxiety.
Part of it is probably my first point about finding a home. The other is that I feel there&rsquo;s something bigger that I
should be doing. Being in Vancouver for the last little while has sparked a stream of nostalgia and reflections on a
simpler and a more naive past.</p>

<h3>Familiar is Good</h3>

<p>This probably isn&rsquo;t a surprise to anyone that knows me, but I&rsquo;m a fan of the familiar. When I drove down to Seattle, I
visited <a href="http://www.oobatooba.com/">Ooba Tooba</a> and <a href="http://bathtubginseattle.com/">Bathtub Gin</a>. In San Francisco I went to the <a href="http://www.beresford.com/beresford/restaurant.htm">White Horse Tavern</a>. Anytime I go back to a place I
haven&rsquo;t been to in a while, I favour hitting the familiar places rather than trying something new. This is clearly part
of who I am and find it something I can&rsquo;t negotiate.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I have no idea how to summarize anything right now. The focus is on data ingress and going to delegate the analysis to a
later time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
