<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Career Break | More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-13T10:22:16-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections of Being Unemployed and Homeless for 1 Month]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-12T19:13:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/reflections-of-being-unemployed-and-homeless-for-1-month</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For some context, you may want to read my <a href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">previous post</a> about quitting my job.</p>

<p>I am homeless and unemployed in probably the most priveleged meaning of the terms. Both states of being are choices I&rsquo;ve
explicitly made. From what I&rsquo;ve read, I&rsquo;m not really on a sabbatical, but I&rsquo;m on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Career_break">Career Break</a>, except the homeless
aspect of it is not as conventional.</p>

<p>So here are the reflections:</p>

<h3>Where Am I Sleeping Tonight</h3>

<p>On September 1st 2012 I gave up my awesome apartment in Calgary as I prepared for an assignment in India (without
really knowing where I was going after that). I changed my mailing address to my brothers place and really didn&rsquo;t feel
much had changed. I had already been travelling weekly for my work assignments since April 2011, and I picked up my life
and departed <a href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/a-new-beginning-or-goodbye-20-s-hello-30-s/">Vancouver to Calgary</a> in January 2010.</p>

<p>In the last month I&rsquo;ve spent 13 nights in different beds. One of those nights was part of a 30 hour trip from
Johannesburg to Vancouver, and another night was one where I lost my dignity in Vegas (ask me to show you the scar one
day). I&rsquo;ve learned there&rsquo;s a lot of overhead in figuring out where you&rsquo;re going to sleep (and I have it easy compared to
those who aren&rsquo;t homeless by choice).</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s hit me those most is the disappearance of the sense of belonging. For 8 months I &ldquo;lived&rdquo; in a Residence Inn in
Bellevue, Washington and it was as much of a home as anywhere. I belonged there, had my routine haunts, and knew where I
was going to be for weeks on end. Nowadays I&rsquo;m either imposing on friends and family, or spending too much for a
hotel&hellip; ok, and using home sharing websites which is like a hybrid of the two.</p>

<p>So I guess this break has been successful in teaching me something already. I need to find a place to live. I do like
the traveling lifestyle, but only when I have a home base.</p>

<h3>Talk Talk Talk</h3>

<p>For some reason, this first month break started off strong with lots of conversations with people in the tech industry.
Maybe I was seeking the familiar so these conversations fit in my comfort zone. I&rsquo;ve probably spoken to over 10 or so
companies and am journaling my pursuits as I go. I&rsquo;ve added a constraint on my life that I won&rsquo;t work for 6 months so
it&rsquo;s hard to not jump on what seem to be great opportunities.</p>

<h3>No Startup For Me</h3>

<p>As a technologist, I&rsquo;m passionate about open standards and infrastructure that makes the Internet work. The last thing I
would want as a startup is for my company name to be a verb (eg: Uber, Tweet). Technology like: SMTP, HTTP, HTML, DNS
aren&rsquo;t corporate brand names. I like to live in abstractions, and as a business owner, I think that&rsquo;s probably the worst
characteristic I could probably have in order to be successful.</p>

<p>In fact, I&rsquo;ve challenged myself to minimize the brands names I speak unless it&rsquo;s trully an endorsement for the brand.
Here are some of the translations I&rsquo;m attempting to do:</p>

<ul>
<li>Tweet &ndash;> microblog</li>
<li>Uber &ndash;> rideshare</li>
<li>Nexus 4 &ndash;> phone</li>
<li>Coke &ndash;> cola</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://www.marriott.com/">Marriott</a>, on the other hand, is a brand I&rsquo;m happy to publicly endorse.</p>

<p>So yeah&hellip; given that one aspect of success for a startup is something I&rsquo;m not advocating, I think it&rsquo;ll be hard for me
to be part of a startup. Though, I think this really depends on the state of the startup.</p>

<h3>I&rsquo;m Super Lucky</h3>

<p>Part of what has made this break possible is the amazing network of friends and aquaintances I&rsquo;ve made over the years. There
are couches available to me all over the world and that&rsquo;s something I feel super blessed about. I really have to thank
<a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/join">ThoughtWorks</a> for enabling me to meet people from everywhere and make these connections.</p>

<h3>A Hint of Concern</h3>

<p>You would think after 1 month of not working I would feel stress free. For some reason there&rsquo;s still a hanging anxiety.
Part of it is probably my first point about finding a home. The other is that I feel there&rsquo;s something bigger that I
should be doing. Being in Vancouver for the last little while has sparked a stream of nostalgia and reflections on a
simpler and a more naive past.</p>

<h3>Familiar is Good</h3>

<p>This probably isn&rsquo;t a surprise to anyone that knows me, but I&rsquo;m a fan of the familiar. When I drove down to Seattle, I
visited <a href="http://www.oobatooba.com/">Ooba Tooba</a> and <a href="http://bathtubginseattle.com/">Bathtub Gin</a>. In San Francisco I went to the <a href="http://www.beresford.com/beresford/restaurant.htm">White Horse Tavern</a>. Anytime I go back to a place I
haven&rsquo;t been to in a while, I favour hitting the familiar places rather than trying something new. This is clearly part
of who I am and find it something I can&rsquo;t negotiate.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I have no idea how to summarize anything right now. The focus is on data ingress and going to delegate the analysis to a
later time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaving a Dream Job and Going on an Adventure]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-26T11:28:28-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On January 4th 2010 I joined <a href="/blog/a-new-beginning-or-goodbye-20-s-hello-30-s/">ThoughtWorks</a> and it has been an amazing journey. I&rsquo;ve seen more systems,
worked with more people, and seen more countries than the entire 30 years that preceded that date. I still can&rsquo;t believe
how lucky I&rsquo;ve been to have such a wonderful opportunity. That&rsquo;s why it took me a long time to decide to leave it, and
go on a bit of an adventure.</p>

<h2>Why Leave Such a Good Thing?</h2>

<p>For some reason I&rsquo;ve had every job I&rsquo;ve had for 4 years since I was 12 years old, so I&rsquo;m just keeping to my routine! To
be honest though, there were a few things that instigated this change.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Consulting Fatigue</strong> &ndash; It&rsquo;s hard work always coming in as an outsider and trying to convince people to change their
ways. You never know if what you suggest is correct, and there&rsquo;s always so much context to process. One thing that I&rsquo;ve gotten
out of this though is becoming much more of a critical thinker. I&rsquo;ve learned to hold off on knee-jerk reactions and to
actively listen to the problem at hand. This has been something I apply on a day-to-day basis.</li>
<li><strong>Product Complacency</strong> &ndash; Though, I&rsquo;ve worked on some interesting projects (the latest being very cool), I can&rsquo;t shake
the satisfaction I got from working at <a href="http://music.cbc.ca/radio3/">CBC Radio 3</a> where I got to essentially build the product I wanted to
build on my own anyways. This may have been mitigated but the following reason adds to this one.</li>
<li><strong>Miss Small Teams</strong> &ndash; For some reason people thought I was great at working on large programs of work. While I thought
the challenges were interesting, I&rsquo;m more a small business person at heart. Some may be surprised by this because I&rsquo;ve
been on small teams, but they were in these large programs of work. I&rsquo;ve learned that I&rsquo;m more of a system thinker than I
thought and I find myself getting lost in the system thinking and see myself as this tiny insignificant cog just
wanting to make some impactful change.</li>
</ul>


<p>Though I&rsquo;m listing things related to ThoughtWorks, a lot of my weariness is more from IT in general. It could be an age
thing, but I&rsquo;ve been around long enough to see a lot of terrible things going on in this industry. No one seems to care
about security, and the innovation that is making billions in the stock market are consumer products that mean almost
nothing to me. It&rsquo;s hard to be optimistic after <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Snowden">Edward Snowden</a> revealed the NSA privacy issues.</p>

<p>In the last few years I&rsquo;ve managed to save some money, and given that I&rsquo;m still relatively young and healthy, I thought
now is the time to take a break before I get too cynical.</p>

<h2>What am I Going to do?</h2>

<p>The plan right now is pretty loose, but I have made a rough 6 month itinerary:</p>

<ul>
<li>Head back to North America. This will involve crashing at my brother&rsquo;s places and spend some time with family
and friends.</li>
<li>Do some roadtrips in Canada and the USA.</li>
<li>Taking a cargo ship across the Atlantic.</li>
<li>July is the month of Formula 1! I have tickets for the British GP and the German GP.</li>
<li>Visit Eastern Europe.</li>
<li>Hang out in India for a couple months.</li>
</ul>


<p>Along with the travels, I will be taking some mental journeys</p>

<ul>
<li>I want to study economics and capitalism. If we&rsquo;re in this prison of a system, I want to be an educated prisoner.</li>
<li>Get back to the basics of software development and attempt to unlearn all this &ldquo;Enterprise&rdquo; cruft I&rsquo;ve picked up.
Hoping to to this by learning a few new languages, doing code katas daily and releasing tiny side projects.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a stretch, but I would like to do some athletic training (mainly running).</li>
</ul>


<p>Like most things, I&rsquo;m probably thinking about it too much, but in this case it&rsquo;s the planning that&rsquo;s been valuable and
not the plan itself.</p>

<h2>Sounds Awesome, but That Cannot Last Forever</h2>

<p>During this time I&rsquo;m attempting to figure out future career ideas. At the end I&rsquo;ll
figure out a place to live and what on my list of interesting domains to pursue:</p>

<ul>
<li>Formula 1</li>
<li>Health care</li>
<li>Beer / Cocktails</li>
<li>Golf</li>
<li>Energy</li>
<li>Public Transportation</li>
<li>Music Distribution</li>
<li>Billiards</li>
<li>Space Exploration</li>
<li>City Planning</li>
<li>Software Delivery</li>
</ul>


<p>Heck, I haven&rsquo;t ruled out re-applying to ThoughtWorks.</p>

<h2>ThoughtWorks Made Me Do This</h2>

<p>The irony is that that ThoughtWorks has opened up my mind in such a way that it&rsquo;s empowered me to make this decision.
The ingress of information, concerns, cultures, opinions and experience is a storm brewing in my head trying it&rsquo;s best to
synthesize itself the best it can. If you&rsquo;re thinking about applying at ThoughtWorks, please ping me. It&rsquo;s an awesome
place to work, and full of great people. During this sabbitcal I plan on visiting as many ThoughtWorkers as I can!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking forward to reading this post a year from now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
