<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Career Break | More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-18T20:45:28-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Months in India]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/three-months-in-india/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-15T21:21:47-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/three-months-in-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>September 20th &ndash; December 16th</em></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/blr-lake.large.jpg" width="800"></p>

<p>Ugh, I left this post until way too late. Unfortunately I&rsquo;ll have to drop a lot of detail as 3 months is pretty hard to
sum up in a single blog post. Hopefully I can do it justice as India is a place I&rsquo;m very fond of. I feel bad for all the
wonderful little experiences that happened and didn&rsquo;t get written about. I&rsquo;ll just have to visit India again and
properly journal the whole experience.</p>

<h3>Arrival</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/blr-flood.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/blr-flood.medium.jpg" width="200"></a>
The minute I got off the plane I was greeted with the familiar scent of Bangalore. The city gives me a bizarre sense of
being home. My arrival to India this time around is much different than the paniced call to Calgary at 4am where my
arrange pickup wasn&rsquo;t there. This time I breezed through the crowd to the taxi line and made my way to Indiranagar where
I was to stay in a wonderful <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.in/rooms/1009953">guest house</a> for the next long while.</p>

<p>It was the end of monsoon season and there was a bit more rain than last time. It was quite refreshing because it kept
the air clean for a little while. There was one evening where the road leading up to my apartment was flooded and had to
wade through knee deep &ldquo;water&rdquo;.</p>

<h3>Work Life Balance</h3>

<p>My goal in India was to finish my job search and just chill out for a little while. But first, I had to find a place
where I could hang out for most of the day to use the Internet. I first tried <a href="http://www.cobaltblr.com/">Cobalt</a> which was on Church St,
just a few minutes away from MG Road metro station. It had good Internet and there were other people around that made it
feel nice. The next day I tried <a href="http://www.beaglesloft.com/">Beaglesloft</a> as it was started by an ex-ThoughtWorker. It was a short walk from Trinity metro station, and it was decent too. A bit too quiet though.</p>

<h3>Finding Nilenso</h3>

<p>There was one more place to check out. An ex-ThoughtWorker, <a href="https://twitter.com/deobald">Steve</a> from Calgary, has lived in Bangalore for a
while and has is part of a software collective called <a href="http://nilenso.com/">Nilenso</a>. I also recommend reading his
<a href="http://blog.deobald.ca/">blog</a> as he is an excellent writer and has written some very insightful posts about life.</p>

<p>After one day of hanging out with the folks at Nilenso I had realized I had found my home. The whole group was extremely
welcoming to me. I had met Steve once before (for like around 5 minutes) and didn&rsquo;t know the others yet I now consider
them friends and will visit them every time I go back to Bangalore. They set me up with good Internet, a workstation
setup and meals! It was really hard not to apply and work with them. They also were excellent test subjects for my
<a href="https://twitter.com/todayschai">chai experiments</a></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/blr-chai.large.jpg" width="800"></p>

<h3>Pune</h3>

<p>After a few weeks I scheduled a trip to Pune to see some old friends and meet a company for a job interview. I had
Internet issues at the place I was staying at so I had to go to Starbucks nearly everyday for interviews and other
correspondance.</p>

<p>The job interview went really well, but declined to pursue the job any further as it felt like it would be ThoughtWorks
part 2. I used the down time to write a couple blog posts and do a little cooking.</p>

<h3>Chennai</h3>

<p>I wanted to meet some friends in Chennai as well so I did another short outing to see them. Besides eating awesome South
Indian food all day long I collaborated with <a href="https://twitter.com/rdsubhas">Subhas Dandapani</a> on <a href="http://www.devopsbookmarks.com/">devopsbookmarks.com</a>. All I
really did was &ldquo;project manage&rdquo; and Subhas essentially did all the work.</p>

<h3>Beer Tour</h3>

<p>Bangalore has a beer scene that&rsquo;s growing strong. In this trip alone I was able to visit 10 brewpubs and that&rsquo;s not
hitting them all!</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://toit.in/">Toit</a> &ndash; Definitely one of my favourites. I think I went there at least once a week. I highly recommend their
weiss beer.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.murphysbrewhouse.in/">Murphy&rsquo;s</a> &ndash; Only went their once for lunch. None of their beers really stood out to me. I regret not going
again because the view is quite nice.</li>
<li><a href="http://windmillscraftworks.com/">Windmills</a> &ndash; Overall, I think Windmills makes the best beer in Bangalore. It&rsquo;s a bit of a trek because
it&rsquo;s all the way in Whitefield.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.barleyz.com/">Barleyz</a> &ndash; The beer isn&rsquo;t that great, but the rooftop terrace is a good reason to go there. All the beers
tasted too watery.</li>
<li><a href="http://thebiereclub.com/">Biere Club</a> &ndash; A decent spot with decent beers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.arborbrewing.com/locations/india/">Arbor</a> &ndash; Arbor always shows up as the place to go for the best beer in Bangalore. I do think the beer is ok,
but it&rsquo;s not even close to Windmills in quality. I also found their beer gave me an allergic reaction. The beer is not
filtered and I know sometimes that can affect me, but it was more pronounced there.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/VapourBangalore">Vapour</a> &ndash; I ignored this spot for a while due to people around me saying it wasn&rsquo;t very good. While not all
beers were of consistent quality, the red ale was pretty good and their weiss beer was decent too. It&rsquo;s also a nice
roof top patio that serves decent food.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/Bigpitcher">Big Pitcher</a> &ndash; A giant establishment. Only checked it out once. There were a couple decent beers, but
the others tasted really off.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.brewsky.in/">Brewsky</a> &ndash; Best IPA I&rsquo;ve had in India. The dunkel was also really good, but the rest were quite bad.</li>
<li><a href="http://prost.in/">Prost</a> &ndash; I&rsquo;ve heard mixed reviews about the beers, but I found them to be pretty good. The Big Ben ale reminds
me a lot of the English Bay Pale Ale, which is an old favourite of mine. Their stout is quite good too, which is a
beer that doesn&rsquo;t seem to get much love in other Bangalore pubs.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Pun Town</h3>

<p>One of the reasons why Bangalore is close to my heart has to be their love of puns. Here are some of the stores that
were within 1km of where I was staying:</p>

<ul>
<li>Blind Love</li>
<li>Berry'ed Alive</li>
<li>Phobidden Fruit</li>
<li>Wearhouse</li>
<li>Infinitea</li>
<li>Chaipatty</li>
</ul>


<h3>Oh, and I Got a Job!</h3>

<p>Over the course of a few months I had interviewed with several companies. It was interesting trying to manage all of
this while moving around and being in terribly inconvenient time zones. I&rsquo;ve already <a href="/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">written</a> and huge post
about the job hunt process. Now I have a blog that if read in order really doesn&rsquo;t make any sense.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>All and all, this trip to India is a very stark contrast compared to my previous visit. I didn&rsquo;t do a whole lot of
traveling. It was really a low-key retreat so that I could do lots of reading, podcast listening, computering, and
reflecting. Sort of makes me wish I wrote about my previous trip because that one was definitely a lot more things going
on, but this trip was exactly what I needed/wanted.</p>

<p>*This post took an unknown number of pomodoros because I lack discipline :&ndash;( *</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joining SoundCloud and Moving to Berlin]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-05T05:09:37-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/berlin-reichstag.medium.jpg" width="900"></p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t say exactly when the job search began. It began with the creation of a Note in Evernote (great tool
for this type of task). It was much different than any other job search I&rsquo;ve done, though I haven&rsquo;t done many as I tend
to stick to job for at least 4 years at a time. The key difference with this search was that I wasn&rsquo;t working, and
wasn&rsquo;t in a hurry to find a job. This allowed me to stick to some rules and a manifesto:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>&ndash; Being open to being located anywhere I&rsquo;ve been before, and know at least someone there<br/>&ndash; Someone I know and respect must have worked there or works there now<br/>&ndash; The company must have cloud in the name ;&ndash;)</p><footer><strong>Scott Muc</strong> <cite>Job Application Criteria</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>manifesto:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>&ndash; People happiness over company success<br/>&ndash; Autonomy over being embedded in a machine<br/>&ndash; Physical and mental health over product growth<br/>&ndash; Access to beer over location</p><footer><strong>Scott Muc</strong> <cite>Preferred Employer Manifesto</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Those set me up much better to see if the company was a fit for me. It remains to be seen, but I think that being open
about my job search, my principals, and not being in a rush will result in a much better mutual partnership. It was a
zero stress endevour and I wish more people had the same privilege to be more precise about the work they apply for.</p>

<p>After several months I interviewed with a handful of companies, but eventually I narrowed it down.</p>

<h2>Then There Were Two</h2>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/cloudfoundry.jpg" width="300">
<strong><a href="http://cloudfoundry.org/">Cloud Foundry</a></strong> &ndash; Creators of an open source <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Platform_as_a_service">PaaS</a> software that allows for companies to create
their own <a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a>. I&rsquo;m not too familiar with the details of the product. It&rsquo;s not like you take a
piece of PaaS enabling software for a test drive every day. Despite not being knowledgable about their product, my
desire to work with them grew as a result of their fantastic interview process.</p>

<p>Every interview required pairing and coding. For me, this delivered a clear idea on how they work and that they prefered
a show me don&rsquo;t tell me approach to interviewing (which I think is awesome). The first pairing
exercise was pretty simple and I was the navigator. As remote pairing exercises go, this was great.
Because I wasn&rsquo;t driving, I wasn&rsquo;t self-conscious about my IDE skills or typing. <strong>David</strong>, who interviewed me, was
clearly prepared and made the interview smooth and fun.</p>

<p>The other two interviews were both roughly around 3 hours long. I was pairing with someone on some small code change
they were assigned to do. Both of them were with code and libraries I wasn&rsquo;t familiar with (go lang, anguluarJS), but
I was amazed at how much that didn&rsquo;t seem to matter. I asked questions, got the gist of what they were trying to do,
and did my best to keep iterating forward as much as possible given my knowledge constraints. The pairs were fun to work
with and I appreciated how they were able to slow down to my level to include me in the process of solving the issue.
I&rsquo;ve learned a lot on how to conduct an interview from this process.</p>

<p>I came away really feeling like these were people I would love to work with. More than that, I loved their discipline in
XP practices. Working with Cloud Foundry, I could become an expert in this field. They also respected employees work/life
balance and that&rsquo;s crucial for me.</p>

<p>The job would be located in San Francisco, and the pay would reflect that, though the cost of living would offset it.
It&rsquo;s a city I&rsquo;ve lived in before and enjoyed. I have a lot of friends there and would be immersed in beer culture.
My role would be a developer working on pieces of Cloud Foundry. So it&rsquo;s an opportunity to develop my dev chops again.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/soundcloud.png" width="300">
<strong><a href="https://soundcloud.com/">Soundcloud</a></strong> &ndash; The only way I can describe it is Twitter for audio. I&rsquo;ve only used the basic recording
functionality of their service (<a href="https://soundcloud.com/scottmuc">my profile</a>) and do listen to a few podcasts that are hosted by them.</p>

<p>Their interview process felt a bit more ad hoc compared to Cloud Foundry. After the initial screening interview with
<strong>Chris</strong>, who I would correspond with during the whole process, there was a developer assignment.</p>

<p>I had a blast working on the dev assignment! I had the luxury of not having a job so I got to spend a decent amount of
time on it. I&rsquo;m unsure about my code, but what I enjoyed was the process of how I grew the solution. Something that you
can&rsquo;t really demonstrate with a code submission. A pairing interview would have been nice so I could better get to know
how they work on a problem. I never did get any feedback on my submission. It would be nice to receive some just to get
a better feel for how they review code and deliver feedback.</p>

<p>After that I had a few more interviews more related to the role that they had envisioned I would fill and that would be
a member of the <a href="http://continuousdelivery.com/">Continuous Delivery</a> team. When I heard that my reaction was on how that&rsquo;s a bit
of an anti-pattern. After discussing it with them, I could see the team that they have formed aligns very much with I
would do if I were asked to create a &ldquo;Continuous Delivery&rdquo; team. It was great to see a bit of a shared mindset.</p>

<p>The location would be in Berlin, and the pay also reflects that. Though the cost of living is lower. I&rsquo;ve visited Berlin
twice and really enjoyed the city. I only know a handful of people there, but it is closer to people I know from all
around the area. The beer culture is definitely a huge plus, and can be great if I meet up with beer brewers in the
community. Being part of a CD team that&rsquo;s breaking down a monolith should provide some valuable experience and put me in
a position to practice a lot more than I preach.</p>

<h2>What Did I Choose?</h2>

<p>Both opportunities aligned well with my rules and manifesto. After a week of thinking (<strong>cough</strong> over-analyzing) about
it, I decided to accept the offer from <strong>Soundcloud</strong>! That means I&rsquo;ll be moving to Berlin in January 2015.</p>

<p>My mind kept flipping back and forth. Initially I thought for sure I was going to <strong>Cloud Foundry</strong>. I had already told
friends that I was going to San Francisco. The professionalism of the interview process had me convinced
that&rsquo;s where I would be most comfortable.</p>

<p>One of my best friends taught me a trick when it comes to making choices. Flip a coin and assign each choice to a
side. Treat the coin as if it&rsquo;s deciding your fate. If what results makes you feel joy and happiness, that&rsquo;s the right
choice. If you sort of deep down wish that the other side won, then you pick the other one. She suggested it with this
decision and I chickened out. Though what I ended up doing had the same result. I created a poll and posted it on Twitter.
It didn&rsquo;t really matter what the results were, but I noticed something. One, I voted for Berlin. Two, I was cheering on
Berlin while the votes were coming in.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/strawpoll.png" width="800"></p>

<h3>Choosing What Scares You</h3>

<p>SoundCloud felt like the riskier and scarier option to me which usually means a greater chance to grow and learn. Don&rsquo;t
get me wrong, Cloud Foundry would been a great chance to grow and learn, but I felt that it would be focused in the
technology spectrum. There looks to be more potential to grow as a person with SoundCloud.</p>

<h3>Learning a Language (That&rsquo;s Not a Programming Language)</h3>

<p>I have a hidden life goal of learning a second language. When I was a coach at ThoughtWorks University I had some
tough experiences with learners that did not speak English as their first language. I want to feel and understand better
what it&rsquo;s like to speak another language. There&rsquo;s a lot of potential for transfer of knowledge (ooh, applying my
<a href="/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/">Learning how to Learn</a> lessons already) when translating. SoundCloud provides German lessons as a benefit and I plan on
taking advantage of that perk.</p>

<h3>More F1</h3>

<p>Nearly the entire F1 calendar is accessible from Berlin! I can continue fulfilling my other life goal which is to attend
all F1 races in my life time. These are the tracks that I can reach by train or a short flight that I haven&rsquo;t attended
yet: Monaco, Sochi, Abu Dhabi, Bahrain, Spain, and Austria.</p>

<h3>Access to Beer</h3>

<p>This leads to another life goal. To break off from technology and have a business in the beer domain.
In my Evernote journal I had a grade on each company/location on beer alignment. Of course both locations are
exceptional locations for a beer fan. San Francisco had a bit of a higher score because I know people there that do home
brewing. I&rsquo;m sure I can find a home brew community in Berlin.</p>

<h3>Music/Audio Domain</h3>

<p>Working in the music/audio domain! At CBC it was awesome being surrounded by music nerds. Sorry, but I&rsquo;ll choose
music nerds over tech nerds. Especially as my interest in the tech world is diminishing.</p>

<h3>More Travel</h3>

<p>So many travel opportunities being in central Europe. I hope to visit my relatives in Ukraine and friends in
Switzerland, England, Turkey, Czech Republic, Germany, and Hungary. With 5 weeks of holidays I&rsquo;ll be exploring and
visiting as much as possible.</p>

<p>Also, a part of me doesn&rsquo;t want to live in the USA. Cloud Foundry is also in London, but I would
want to be at the hub of the product development which is primarily in San Francisco. There would have been an option to
move to London after a year though, but my decision making was based more on the immediate change.</p>

<h2>Show Me the Money</h2>

<p>At first I was really concerned about how much less SoundCloud offered compared to Cloud Foundry. I took a look at a
<a href="http://www.numbeo.com/cost-of-living/compare_cities.jsp?country1=United+States&amp;country2=Germany&amp;city1=San+Francisco%2C+CA&amp;city2=Berlin">cost of living</a> website and calculated that to get the equivalent of an SF salary in Berlin, it would
have to be 56.3% percent (eg: making $56,300 in Berlin is equivalent to $100,000 in SF). Comparing the salary I was
offered it&rsquo;s at 55.7%. So it&rsquo;s a little bit lower, but not as crazy low as I thought.</p>

<p>It did take me on a tangent and wonder why we tend to care so much about salaries (I really wish salaries were public, I
don&rsquo;t keep mine much of a secret). My hypothesis is that your salary is a concrete tangible thing, whereas how much you
spend is harder to determine. If you&rsquo;re in Berlin making $56,300 and spend $50,000, then you&rsquo;ve save $6,300. If you make
$100,000 in SF and spend $95,000, you&rsquo;ve actually saved less. Unfortunately figuring out the amount you spend is left to
discipline around budgets.</p>

<h3>What I Don&rsquo;t Like</h3>

<p>This means I&rsquo;m joining a company that is becoming more tied to the big labels and entering the advertising space. I&rsquo;m
hoping to learn more about how this system works so that I can learn to be a more educated critic.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>I just reread <a href="/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">my post</a> from the beginning of this career break. This post and that one seem to align really
well and it gives me comfort in my decision. I really love the cadence my life has had for almost the last 20 years.
Keep an eye here for my next steps 5 years from now. Wish me luck!</p>

<h5>Looking for work? Both companies are still hiring:</h5>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://soundcloud.com/jobs">http://soundcloud.com/jobs</a></li>
<li><a href="http://cloudfoundry.com/jobs">http://cloudfoundry.com/jobs</a></li>
</ul>


<p><em>This post took 9 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Siófok/Tihany, Italian Grand Prix, and Istanbul]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/siofok-tihany-italian-grand-prix-and-istanbul/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-02T01:48:21-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/siofok-tihany-italian-grand-prix-and-istanbul</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>August 30th &ndash; September 19</em></p>

<h3>Hungary for More (Siófok/Tihany)</h3>

<p>Remember the woman that I met at the <a href="/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix/">Dream Theater concert</a>? We have kept in touch and she promised to show me around the
Hungarian country side! She recommended <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_Balaton">Balaton Lake</a> area so I found a <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2522686">place to stay</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Si%C3%B3fok">Siófok</a> and worked
on scheduling a day to meet up.</p>

<p>Unfortunately the weather did not cooperate as it rained most of the time I was there. On the plus side, I picked up a
cold on my way from Ukraine and wasn&rsquo;t feeling very adventurous anyways. I spent 3 days enjoying the sound of the rain,
and watching all of the Harry Potter movies. I picked up some groceries the day I arrived and was able to be pretty
self-sufficient.</p>

<p>On the last day my cold was disappearing and the weather outlook was brighter. Just in time for my meet up with <strong>Orsolya</strong> and a tour of
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Veszpr%C3%A9m">Veszprém</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tihany">Tihany</a>. Both places had the European charm that I&rsquo;ve enjoyed so much on this trip.
The sun came out while walking around Inner Lake (pic 3 below). <strong>Orsolya</strong> explained what life is like in rural Hungary
and I shared stories of my life. My favourite question was when she asked how I planned my travels. I never really
thought about it, but I replied saying that it was just a combination of many little trips. With each little trip I had
to plan the transition to the next trip and the opened up opportunities for other little trips.</p>

<p>After the day I was feeling recovered from my cold, and happy to have a new friend. Then I headed back to Budapest to
catch a flight to Milano for the last F1 in my travels.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle2.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/hungary-castle2.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/hungary-tihany.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/hungary-tihany.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h3>Italian Grand Prix (Milano)</h3>

<p>Figured that I could fit one more F1 race in this trip! I used some points to get a <a href="http://www.marriott.com/hotels/travel/milit-milan-marriott-hotel/">free hotel</a> in Milano. The
commute to the race track is pretty long so I didn&rsquo;t really have much time to explore the city. <a href="https://twitter.com/sragu">Srini</a>, who went
to the <a href="/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix/">British GP</a> with me, got his <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schengen_Area#Schengen_visa">Shengen visa</a> and was finally able to explore outside
of Istanbul and the UK. He couldn&rsquo;t come to the race but we got to hang out in the evenings when our respective daily
activities were done.</p>

<p>At the race track there&rsquo;s an abundance of people playing versions of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shell_game">shell game</a> . I watched it for
a bit and thought it looked pretty easy. I played once and was absolutely sure of my pick and lost 50 euros. I realized
I got scammed and was initially upset. Then I realized why I played the game. I wanted to win some easy money; how was I
any different than the perpetrators of the scam? It reminded me that no matter how &ldquo;good&rdquo; you try to be, temptation is
always there. I thought I could win a quick buck and I was being just as greedy as the scam artists. I laugh at the
experience now, and see it as a valuable lesson. I spent some time watching these games and saw all the tricks they play
and now understand why it&rsquo;s called a &ldquo;confidence game&rdquo;. I could see ways to &ldquo;win&rdquo;, but I would be playing against a
person who plays for hours everyday. I think their confidence will win in the long run.</p>

<p>As I alluded to earlier, the commute to my seat was quite long. My record time to my seat was 1 hour and 40 minutes, but
it was 2 hours most of the time. One of the nice things about F1 is that they aren&rsquo;t too strict about what you can bring
to the track. Each day I bought food from a local grocery store. Below is a picture of my breakfast on race day (yes
beer at 9:00am, don&rsquo;t judge). Buying from the on track vendors is a complete rip-off. For the price of a couple beers, I
was stocked up for the day.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/milano-breakfast.jpg"><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/milano-breakfast.medium.jpg" width="700"></a></p>

<p>As for the race, the weekend was full of awesome moments. I watched both GP2 and GP3 races, and the F1 race was full of
awesome passes. I was sitting at the first turn which is at the end of a very fast straight (<a href="http://www.formula1.com/races/in_detail/italy_928/circuit_diagram.html">circuit diagram</a>).
Hopefully this historic track doesn&rsquo;t close, but I am so happy that I got to experience Monza before anything happens to
the event.</p>

<p>Of course my travels wouldn&rsquo;t be complete without meeting up with <a href="https://twitter.com/iliasbartolini">Ilias Bartolini</a>, a ThoughtWorker I met when I
was in India. He&rsquo;s on a project in Milano and we caught up over dinner at <a href="http://www.pizzeriamaruzzellamilano.it/">Maruzzella</a>. Again, a reminder of the
network that grew out of working at ThoughtWorks is global and full of such wonderful people.</p>

<h3>Turkish Delight</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-view.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-view.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
The last leg of my European travels is a stay in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Istanbul">Istanbul</a> (<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vsQrKZcYtqg">not Constantinople</a>). There&rsquo;s a big ThoughtWorks
project there and was able to stay in <a href="https://twitter.com/sragu">Srini</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/noppanit">Toy&rsquo;s</a> apartment (picture of the view to the right).
I wasn&rsquo;t sure how long I was going to be there so it was nice to have the flexibility of a ThoughtWorker&rsquo;s accommodation.</p>

<p>The reason for the uncertain length is that I would be applying for my <a href="http://indianvisaonline.gov.in/">Indian visa</a> from here. I won&rsquo;t go
into too much detail, but the process was relatively painless. The website is horrible and doesn&rsquo;t work in all browsers,
but once I got my application submitted, the rest of the process was straightforward. In a little over a week I got my
visa.</p>

<p>At this point in time I was beginning the interview process for several organizations. Much of my time was spent doing
coding exercises and submitting them, or doing calls. I really felt things were going forward and that in some time I&rsquo;ll
actually have figured out where I&rsquo;ll be living after all of this traveling.</p>

<p>It was a bit of a mini reunion with several people too. I met up with <a href="http://davidpetersimon.com/">David Simon</a>, who I climbed Kilimanjaro
with. There was also a bit of a Calgary reunion where I met up with <a href="http://isa.io/">Isa Goksu</a> who was my roommate for
over a year and I probably hadn&rsquo;t seem him in over 2 years! When I met up with Isa, <a href="http://www.cengizhan.com/">Cengiz Han</a>
was also there, smoking sheesha. He too was in Calgary, usually complaining about the cold, yet both of them talked
about how much they miss the Calgary days.</p>

<p>Oh right, I&rsquo;m in Istanbul! In the slack time, I spent many days wandering around this incredible city. My friend
<strong>Rose</strong> has a <a href="http://adidav9.blogspot.in/2014/07/illustrious-istanbul.html">picture filled post</a> that better captures the beauty of the city (and of other European
cities I&rsquo;ve visited).</p>

<p>Most of my day trips started out at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taksim_Square">Taksim Square</a>, which was the space that the <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-22732139">Gezi Park Riots</a> took
place at in 2013. Taking the metro from where I was staying was easy and efficient. From there I went down <a href="http://istiklalstreet.org/">Istiklal Street</a>
which is a big shopping area. My first stop was <a href="http://istanbuleats.com/2009/04/durumzade-wrap-artists/">Dürümzade</a> which was made famous by <strong>Anthony Bordain&rsquo;s</strong>
visit. Let&rsquo;s just say I went there 3 times during my stay! The adana dürüm was one of my favourite meals in Istanbul.
The area is a maze of winding hilly streets and I was content to wander this part of the city for a long time. Some days
I would hangout at <a href="http://kronotrop.com.tr/">Kronotrop</a> which is an excellent coffee bar. There&rsquo;s wifi and friendly people who are
very open to helping out a tourist with their Turkish. The pictures below are of: Istiklal Street, small street leading
to Dürümzade, and outside of Dürümzade.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-large-street.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-large-street.small.jpg" width="385"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-small-street.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-small-street.small.jpg" width="224"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-durumzade.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-durumzade.small.jpg" width="385"></a></p>

<p>On another day I walk down further and crossed the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galata_Bridge">Galata Bridge</a> and navigated through all the
fishermen to the other side (pic 1 below, you can see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galata_Tower">Galata Tower</a> in the background). Once on Old
Istanbul side I follow the meandering alleys in the direction of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hagia_Sophia">Hagia Sophia</a> (pic 2 below). How I arrive there I
don&rsquo;t know because the roads go in many different directions and they are very crowded. I kept on having to back track
as I took many wrong turns. It was a lot of fun to be lost in the shuffle. Unfortunately I arrived there after the
museum was closed so I didn&rsquo;t get to see inside. Last destination was the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sultan_Ahmed_Mosque">Blue Mosque</a> which is probably
one of the most famous landmarks (hard to say because there are so many). I was lucky to arrive in between prayer times
and was able to go inside. It was so majestic on the inside that I believe I sat there for at least 45 minutes just
soaking in the atmosphere. I couldn&rsquo;t get a decent picture inside with my phone (which has been my only camera on this
trip). I did manage to get a decent snap as the sun was getting low on the horizon (pic 3 below).</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-fishing.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-fishing.small.jpg" width="330"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-hagia-sophia.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-hagia-sophia.small.jpg" width="330"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-blue-mosque.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/istanbul-blue-mosque.small.jpg" width="330"></a></p>

<p>One day walking around beautiful Old Istanbul wasn&rsquo;t enough so I made another walking tour from Taksim Square. This
time, instead of going east to all the great mosques and monuments I kept on going South to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_Bazaar,_Istanbul">Grand Bazaar</a>.
Walking through the bazaar is like being transported in time. I used to think India was a sensory explosion, but this
place comes pretty close. It was also a &lsquo;90s time warp as I couldn&rsquo;t get the following song out of my head:</p>

<div style="width:660px;margin-left:200px;">
<iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/JCye7v79Tz0 " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Never have I felt so immersed in history. I&rsquo;ve seen some historic places in my travels. The throngs of people that
still populate these places made the history feel more alive. At some point I&rsquo;ll have to go back to Turkey when I&rsquo;m not
quite so traveled out and explore more of the countries beauty and friendly people.</p>

<h3>Onward to India</h3>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for my travels in Europe for nearly 3 months. I now have the idea of writing a post about the metrics of this
career break. It&rsquo;ll be a good way to close out the series. But not yet! Now off to India for a few months to hang out
with friends, and get re-invigorated about software development.</p>

<p><em>This post took 10 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visiting the Motherland - Ukraine]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/visiting-the-motherland-ukraine/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-06T07:31:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/visiting-the-motherland-ukraine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>August 17th &ndash; August 29th</em></p>

<h3>Ukraine</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
The next leg of the journey was a long slog from Vienna to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lviv">L’viv</a>. I took a noon train to Budapest and had to pass
some time there for a little while. From Budapest it was an overnight journey with many frequent stops in the
middle of the night for immigration and customs. If you’ve ever played <a href="http://papersplea.se/">Papers, Please</a>, it felt like that. Ukraine
isn’t part of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schengen_Agreement">Schengen agreement</a> so you can’t just cross the border without a documents check. Around a few
hours from L’viv the attendant asks me about my purpose in Ukraine. She then points at my &ldquo;ringless&rdquo; ring finger and
smiles. I knew of the Russian/Ukrainian bride thing, but found it crazy that her first guess was for that purpose.
I thought it was a hyped up, but after watching a few <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8wW7c58nMI4">youtube documentaries</a> about it, I learned
it’s sadly alive and well.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train2.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-train2.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
Even with such a long journey the train pretty much arrived on time within a couple minutes. When I exited the train I
immediately could recognize my cousin <a href="https://twitter.com/RusalkaUA">Lilia</a>. She ran up to me and gave me a proper family style hug. Looks like I’m
home! We took a bus to her home in the Northern part of the city. I was introduced to her roommate,
<a href="https://twitter.com/uPadavan">Vitalik</a>. He and I got along really well. He’s a web designer and looks to have a knack for it!
Lilia had to go back to work so I unpacked and made myself at home. Later that evening Lilia’s sister, Natalia, arrived
by train from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ternopil">Ternopil</a>. She had a huge package of food from her parents and we all enjoyed a feast as I
did my best to tell the story of myself and the Myц family Canadian history.</p>

<h2>L'viv</h2>

<p>I felt immediately comfortable in L’viv. As Lilia was at work, Vitalik and Natalia guided me around the city. Here
are some of the noteworthy places we checked out:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-high-castle.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-high-castle.small.jpg" width="190" title="&ldquo;High Castle&rdquo;" ></a>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lviv_High_Castle">High Castle</a> &ndash; On my first day in L'viv I was antsy to go out and explore. I never feel comfortable
  in a location until I spend at least a whole day walking around exploring and knowing my surroundings. Natalia likes
  to sleep in (she&rsquo;s going to kill me), so instead of waiting for her to wake up, I decide to explore L'viv on my own.
  The high castle name is more of a memory as the castle isn&rsquo;t there anymore. Getting to the top of the hill was
  good exercise and rewarded me with a beautiful 360 degree view of the city.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-dim-legend.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-dim-legend.small.jpg" width="190" title="&ldquo;Dim Legend&rdquo;" ></a>
<a href="http://ukraineallaboutu.com/travel-in-ukraine/hotels-and-restaurants/lviv/house-of-legends/">Dim Legend (House of Legend)</a> &ndash; There are a collection of restaurants owned by a company that&rsquo;s doing some interesting
  setups. Dim Legend has a room for every story (or a story for every room). The restaurant takes
  the entire building and you can go up to the roof top where there&rsquo;s patio with a car, and a chimney with a ladder so
  that you can climb to the top. There&rsquo;s something refreshing about being in a country that doesn&rsquo;t have the same
  restrictive safety regulations of most western countries.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-rynok.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-rynok.small.jpg" width="190" title="&ldquo;Rynok Square&rdquo;" ></a>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Market_Square_(Lviv)">Rynok Square</a> &ndash; Like most Eastern European cities, L'viv has a beautiful (albeit touristy) city
  square. You&rsquo;ll find the &ldquo;floating&rdquo; statue people and dudes making giant bubbles. Overall though, the atmosphere is
  quaint and relaxing. Ukrainian culture is inviting so it&rsquo;s pretty hard to feel like you&rsquo;re too far out of place.
  This is probably where I spent the most time as all the coffee shops and restaurants are all near this location.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-chocolate-chili.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-chocolate-chili.small.jpg" width="190" title="&ldquo;Melted Chocolate with Chili&rdquo;" ></a>
<a href="http://ukraineallaboutu.com/travel-in-ukraine/hotels-and-restaurants/lviv/lviv-handmade-chocolate/">Lviv chocolate</a> &ndash; One of the most unique experiences I had in L'viv was drinking melted chocolate
  flavoured with a whole whack load of chili powder! This place was not good for any thought about losing weight. Not
  sure how everyone here stays so fit! At least I was getting a lot of walking in, but not sure if it&rsquo;s enough for
  all the sweets I&rsquo;ve been having.</p>

<p>&nbsp;
&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.lvivbeermuseum.com/uk/muzey">Lviv brewery</a> &ndash; On my own I stopped by the brewpub to sample a few of their beers. I was really
intrigued by the style of beer they make there. In general, I found Ukrainian beer sweeter than most beers I&rsquo;ve
had around the world. I visited the brewery a second time with Natalia and Vitalik. We took a brewery tour but
it was done in Ukrainian. I&rsquo;ve never heard Ukrainian spoken so fast, but it was pretty comprehensive. She started
the tour talking about the origins of beer in Egypt.</li>
<li><a href="http://trumitlu.virtual.ua/?lang=en">Try Mitly (3 Brooms)</a> &ndash; My cousins are huge Harry Potter fans and they said that there&rsquo;s a place to have
butter beer in L'viv! A lot of places were kitschy but that didn&rsquo;t bother me in this environment. I found them a lot
of fun. It could be that I felt like I was in an environment where people aren&rsquo;t as judgemental about such kinds
of establishments.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.justlviv.it/en/1714/gas-lamp.html">Gas lamp</a> &ndash; Owned by the same person as Dim Legend, this restaurant had a unique feel for every floor
and was a fun environment to take some time and relax in.</li>
<li><a href="http://visittoukraine.com/en/unique-ukraine/lviv-coffee-mine">Lviv coffee manufacture</a> &ndash; L'viv is the coffee capital of Ukraine. Normally tea is the hot beverage
choice, but here coffee rules. A proper L'viv coffee is hot water mixed with the coffee grounds without a filter.
You wait a few minutes and the grounds settle to the bottom and you&rsquo;re left with a rich, flavourful cup of coffee.
The best part is that you don&rsquo;t need any fancy expensive equipment to make it! It&rsquo;s really the quality of the beans
that matter.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lychakiv_Cemetery">Lychakiv Cemetery</a> &ndash; I wanted to go somewhere outside the center and old gothic cemeteries seem to appeal
to me for some reason. The day that I visited Lychakiv Cemetery was sunny and warm. The whole area is like a maze and
it was nice to wander around witnessing the beautiful scenery.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-beer.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-beer.small.jpg" width="190" title="&ldquo;Beer Museum&rdquo;" ></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-butterbeer.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-butterbeer.small.jpg" width="190" title="&ldquo;Butterbeer!&rdquo;" ></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-books.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-books.small.jpg" width="190" title="&ldquo;Book Market&rdquo;" ></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-alley.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-alley.small.jpg" width="190"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-cemetary.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-cemetary.small.jpg" width="190" title="&ldquo;Cemetary&rdquo;" ></a></p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/lviv-tram.jpg" width="70">
L'viv is a city rich in culture, architecture, and friendly people. It&rsquo;s accessible with its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trams_in_Lviv">120 year old tram</a>
system, but remember to punch your ticket yourself (pictures to the left) and has all the things you need as a traveler.
The city is sort of a dream land for me. It has excellent beer, chocolate, coffee, books, and food. The people are
friendly and accomodating, I can&rsquo;t wait to be back!</p>

<h2>Ternopil</h2>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-home.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-home.small.jpg" width="200"></a>
For the weekend, Lillia had planned a trip to Ternopil to visit her parents and other relatives. Apparently they don’t
get many foreigners on the train and the attendant on the train made an effort to ask if I wanted tea or coffee in
English. He sort of chuckled and so did my cousins, not sure why. We took a bus from the train station to the outer area of Ternopil
where Lilias’s parents live. It was a classic pre 90’s looking apartment block. The door opens to their apartment and
I’m welcomed with a feast on the table! Lilia’s parents didn’t speak much English so poor Lilia had to spend a lot of
time translating (she eventually could tell me whole life story without me having to say a word). The meal started with
a shot of vodka. When Ivan offered me another, I replied “tak, bud laska!” (translation: yes, please!). That moment
signified me as an authentic family member.</p>

<p>First, I need to digress and talk about Lilia and Natalia’s parents, Ivan and Mariia. They are the sweetest couple and
so generous. I loved how they didn’t let the language barrier prevent us from getting to know each other. One of my
favourite moments was sitting with Ivan as he showed me pictures and we had a conversation. Lilia was busy packing
for the trip back and after she was done she asked what the heck we could possibly talk about. I’m not quite sure
myself, but we laughed a lot and didn’t let language stop us from at least trying to communicate. We even enjoyed
watching the Belgian GP (and what an awesome race!) with some Ukrainian craft beers. One day I hope to learn more
Ukrainian so we can communicate even more the next time we meet.</p>

<p>Mariia could easily be mistaken as a sister of her daughters. She’s actually my
cousin (Lilia and Natalia are my 2nd cousins 1st removed) and the family bond was definitely felt. She’s also an
amazing cook! The meals included home made: cabbage rolls, varenyky (perogies), shkvarky (pork rind), sour cream, borscht, milk, and juice.
I’m pretty sure I gained 5 kilos over those few days.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-beer1.jpg" width="180">
<img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-beer2.jpg" width="180">
The next day was spent driving to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Velyki_Birky">Velyki Birky</a>, a village outside of Ternopil. Our first stop was at Mariia’s parents (Hanna and
Fedoz). First we stopped by a house which was a family run brewery (business card pictured). One of the sons of the owner was there and he
happily (in excellent English) explained the whole operation. The beer was fresh, un-pasterized, un-filtered, and
very tasty. We then arrived and had a big family lunch (with more shots of vodka). Hanna is my dad’s cousin as she
is the daughter of Eve Myц who is the sister of Petro Myц, my dad’s father. The meal was of course fantastic and I
did my best to update them on my family back in Canada. During the afternoon, Lilia, Natalia, and I walked over to
where Hanna&rsquo;s other children live. Lilia gave her best rendition of my life story and we had fun playing more Q&amp;A
with more of my family. One of the big questions was on how Canada was receiving the news about the events going
on in Ukraine. Unfortunately I couldn&rsquo;t quite adequatley answer the question but from a generalized perspective I
could say that the West has been pretty weak in it&rsquo;s response.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family.medium.jpg" width="510"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.medium.jpg" width="510"></a></p>

<p>In the evening I went out with the girls to meet up with some of their friends. It was fun introducing them to some
of the games I played at TWU (eg: numbers game, and one-up one-down). The next day was a holiday for independence day
so we went walking around the city for a bit. The city had some very pretty areas and some interesting looking playgrounds.
After our walk we went to the train station (pic: don&rsquo;t we look like an intimidating group?).</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-playground.medium.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-playground2.medium.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-family2.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/ternopil-departing.medium.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<h2>Back to L'viv</h2>

<p>After an amazing weekend we headed back to L'viv. Lilia&rsquo;s roommate was returning so I had find a <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.in/rooms/451524">place of my own</a>
to for a few days. I wasn&rsquo;t prepared for how much I would miss being in the same place as my cousins and Vitalik (I&rsquo;m
considering him family). I did feel some sense of relief to give Lilia some time without having to worry
about entertaining me and it gave me a chance to practice my Ukrainian all on my own. The few days I spent on my
own was focused on hanging out in coffee shops and working on a browser plugin. I realized there&rsquo;s a reason why
people smiled when I asked for the wifi password when I hung out at a venue. Trying to be Ukrainian I would say
&ldquo;Internet bud laska&rdquo;. This is the equivalent of ordering the Internet off of a menu. My cousins got a good laugh
from this, and apparently so did all the wait staff I said this to.</p>

<p>Anyways, over a couple days I got the the basic functionality of a plugin working called <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/blockworthy">BlockWorthy</a>.
It scrubs links to viral websites and issues you a warning if you happen to go to one of those websites. It felt good
to be writing some code and exploring some ideas.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>Leaving Ukraine I thought about the bond of family. I had been watching Game of Thrones and seeing how important
bloodlines are in that show probably had some affect on me. I was really touched that my cousins would openly accept
me into their home and all because we share common ancestry (my great grandfater, their great great grandfather).
I didn’t even know who were my cousins were until my aunt
in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biggar,_Saskatchewan">Biggar</a> informed me there are relatives in Ukraine who would love to meet me. The thought about the subconscious
bond with family made me think about why we have countries and lines on maps. It’s like a higher level view of the
bond. Patriotism is like a larger version of nepotism. I can’t help connect more easily with someone from Canada than
I would USA. My bond with my cousins exists because of who my parents are. My ability to nearly walk into any country
is simply because of the country I was born in.</p>

<p>What I’m really trying to say is that I’m so freaking lucky to be born into an awesome family and country. Because
of these uncontrollable events (on my part), I’ve been afforded so many luxuries.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rome, Switzerland, and Vienna]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/rome-switzerland-and-vienna/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T05:09:31-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/rome-switzerland-and-vienna</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 30th &ndash; August 17th</em></p>

<h2>When in Rome</h2>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/rome-fountain.jpg"><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/rome-fountain.medium.jpg" width="900"></a></p>

<p>When I learned that my uncle and his family would be in Rome I looked at my schedule to see if I could make seeing them
work. It turned out it fit perfectly! The last time I saw them was in London while they were doing their 2013 summer
trip and I was on my Belgian Grand Prix vacation. My aunt and uncle are well versed in the world of business so we had
many evenings discussing what I&rsquo;ve learned from the economics courses and floating ideas of what&rsquo;s next for my life. Of
course I got to catch up with my cousins too. Can&rsquo;t believe how quickly they are growing up (I won&rsquo;t mention that I
remember seeing them in diapers to avoid their embarassment).  They had rented a flat near the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Steps">Spanish Steps</a>
which made it easy for me to cram in a bunch of sight-seeing in a short amount of time.</p>

<p>Touring Rome is pretty easy because all you have to do is step outside. Even on my first walk I stumbled across many
interersting sites. I did a couple free walking tours, but they weren&rsquo;t organized by Sandeman and weren&rsquo;t nearly the
same quality. Still, it was good to have a guided walk to the Colloseum and to the Vatican. My favourite place was the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Gallery_of_Maps">Hallway of Maps</a> in the Vatican Museum. Ever since I was a kid, I&rsquo;ve always loved looking at maps. On
roadtrips I would be the navigator, and my favourite thing about Ultima VII is the cloth map that was packaged with the
game</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/rome-colosseum.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/rome-colosseum.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/rome-square.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/rome-square.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/rome-st-peters.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/rome-st-peters.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>As beautiful as Rome was, I knew my time as a tourist was ending. I was at the point where I didn&rsquo;t want to elbow my
way through tourists anymore. Nor was I as interested as I was before in exploring musuems and historical places. The
brain can only hold so much. One thing I enjoyed immensely were the flavour of the tomatoes! Every meal I had I was sure
to have tomatoes as a part of it.</p>

<h2>Watching Time Go By in Switzerland</h2>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-home.jpg"><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-home.medium.jpg" width="900"></a></p>

<p>The other part that made Rome convenient was that I could travel to Switzerland to meet up with fellow ex-ThoughtWork
<a href="https://twitter.com/mhoefi">Marc Hofer</a>, who I worked with in India in ThoughtWorks University (TWU), and who&rsquo;s balcony view is displayed above.
He had a 1L bottle of scotch ready (we numbed our heads with scotch nearly every evening during TWU). Thankfully he was
generous enough to give me a couch for as long as I needed one. I ended up spending 10 days in beautiful <a href="http://www.myswitzerland.com/en/thun.html">Thun</a>!</p>

<p>Over the those days I did the following:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Dinners and chats with Marc</strong> &ndash; Catching up with Marc was a lot of fun. During the day I would accrue a lot of ideas and
he became my wall to bounce them off of. One such idea was my new currency that I called &ldquo;Sunset&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s a time based
currency where you determine the exchange rate of the base amount which is a Day. If your daily expenses are $100USD,
then that&rsquo;s the exchange rate into Days. If you have $1400 in the bank than you have 2 Weeks saved. It&rsquo;s a completely
personal currency because everyone&rsquo;s exchange into Days will be different. We of course
talked about our time in India and software development in Switzerland. We never really lacked of things to talk about
the whole time I was there.</li>
<li><a href="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bern.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bern.small.jpg" width="300"></a> <strong>Bern
Excursion</strong> &ndash; Marc had a meetup with some of his colleagues and invited me out. I took a train out to Bern a few
hours before the meetup started so I could wander around a bit. It didn&rsquo;t take long for me to find the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kindlifresserbrunnen">Kindlifresserbrunnen (Child Eater Fountain)</a> which is probably the most bizarre statue I&rsquo;ve ever seen. The old
town was beautiful (like Antwerp, Bruges, Heidelberg, Prague, etc&hellip;) and of course I found a nearby
<a href="http://www.altestramdepot.ch/htm/home.htm">brewery</a> to quench my thirst for a bit before heading to meet up with Marc and his colleagues.</li>
<li><strong>Coffee shops</strong> &ndash; During the day I looked to find cafes to hang out in and work on my blog (these posts seem to take me a
heck of a lot of time). There was <a href="https://plus.google.com/106555922181396502598/about?hl=en">one cafe</a> that I really liked. The staff were friendly, played good music, and the
coffee and beers available were very tasty. During this period I was getting working on my <a href="http://careers.stackoverflow.com/scottmuc">CV</a> and getting
excited about working again!</li>
<li><a href="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bike.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bike.small.jpg" width="300"></a> <strong>Bike
around Lake Thun</strong> &ndash; The weather was hit-and-miss, but for one day there was excellent weather. I rented a bike and
rode it to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interlaken">Interlaken</a> and back to Thun for a total of 60km. It was a beautiful ride, but I could feel that I&rsquo;m a bit
out of shape.</li>
<li><strong>Train tour</strong> &ndash; There were spare days on my Eurail pass so I decided to check out all the main city centers in the
country. I started by going to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geneva">Geneva</a>, then <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zurich">Zurich</a>, and finished in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lucerne">Luzern</a>.
Mike Wong, a ThoughtWorker from SF, was on vacation and we met up for dinner. Seriously, ThoughtWorkers are everywhere!</li>
<li><strong>Oberhofen Castle and Clock Museum</strong> &ndash; Over the weekend Marc played tourist with me and we headed over to Oberhofen. The
purpose of the trip was to go the <a href="http://www.myswitzerland.com/en/museum-of-clocks-and-mechanical-musical-instruments.html">clock museum</a> but it didn&rsquo;t open for a few hours. We walked around and decided to
tour the <a href="http://www.schlossoberhofen.ch/en/home">castle</a>. After a bit of walking and a quick snack we went back to the clock museum. They
didn&rsquo;t do tours in English so Marc played translator. Even in Swiss-German it was a fun tour. The guide was clearly
passionate about the watches and the music devices.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-spiez.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-spiez.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-thun-canal.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-thun-canal.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bridge.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-bridge.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>Since I was in the land of clocks I was hoping to purchase a watch there. Something to be a symbol of taking time to
enjoy life (a principle of my career break) and something to keep me from looking at my phone for the time. I was
inspired by the intricate work that goes into making a watch and thought having one on my wrist would remind me to take
pride in my work and take the necessary time to do it well. Unfortunately all the watch stores were posh and displayed
ideas around prestige and fashion more than engineering. It switched off my idea of purchasing a watch for now.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-currency.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/swiss-currency.small.jpg" width="180"></a>
It was hard to leave Switzerland because I was growing comfortable there. The people were friendly and forgiving of my
inability to speak any of the 4 official languages. Then again, paying over $30 (0.3 Days) was quickly draining my money
reserves. At least the best part of Switzerland is free; the scenery. Oh, and I also like how the currency folded nicely
in my money clip. The notes are sized in such a way that the denomination of the note aligns in such a way that you can
see all of your notes when folded! I can&rsquo;t say how many times I&rsquo;ve had a roll of US notes and found that they were all
$1 bills and I only had a total of $30 on me.</p>

<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h2>Composing my Thoughts in Vienna</h2>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-cats.jpg"><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-cats.medium.jpg" width="900"></a></p>

<p>The next leg of my journey is a long train trip to L'viv, Ukraine. I decided to break up the trip with a stop in Vienna
for a couple days. With only a couple days I had to pack in the sight-seeing. This was made easier with me being
museumed-out so I was mostly checking things out from the outside. To make things easy, I found a
<a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/1531563">great location</a> with a host with a couple cats (pictured above).</p>

<p>My first day was spent checking out the two largest palaces in Vienna. The highlight was a stop at a <a href="http://www.salmbraeu.com/index.php?id=2&amp;L=1">brewery</a> just
outside the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belvedere_(palace)">Belvedere</a> palace. The service was great, the food yummy, and every beer tasty. After 1.5L of beer I was set
for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sch%C3%B6nbrunn_Palace">Schönbrunn</a> palace. I took the metro there and climb up the hill to Gloriette and had a little nap on the grass there.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-belvedere.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-belvedere.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-schunbrunn.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-schunbrunn.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-center.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-center.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>The next day I used a city bike rental. I&rsquo;m glad I did because I saw a very different Vienna. First stop was to checkout
the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hundertwasser_Haus">Hundertwasserhaus</a>. It was so interesting and pretty that I wondered why beautiful buildings
like it had to be the exception to the rule. His <a href="http://www.hundertwasser.com/">website</a> is full of interesting ideas. His 5-skins
concept is one I find myself conflicted about. I wonder what it would have been like to have him and
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gene_Roddenberry">Gene Roddenberry</a> had a conversation.</p>

<p>I then went through <a href="http://www.wien-vienna.com/prater.php">Prater</a> which was a scary amusement park. The weather was a bit gloomy and there were some
giant clown shaped buildings that made me think of the book IT.</p>

<p>Since I was on a bike I could cover
a bit more distance so I went towards the bridge and crossed North to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donau_City">Donaucity</a>. It was like riding into a dystopian
story! The streets were stark and there was a cold feeling to the area. I rode away to the nearby park and found it odd
to see such a large expanse of greenery vacant on a Saturday afternoon. It reminded me again that big design up front
for cities does not work. What you end up with is something functional but complete devoid of any human feel. After
riding back to the center I parked the bike at another area and checked out another <a href="http://www.1516brewingcompany.com/cms/">brewery</a>. I think I
went there during shift change because it took a long time to get the attention of a waitress. The beer and the currywurst was really
good, but the poor service at the obnoxious sounding Australian behind me (probably was just my mood) was wearing me
down and I took the metro back to the apartment and hung out in the flat with Roman and his cats.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-hundertwasser.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-hundertwasser.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-donaucity.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-donaucity.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-golden-boy.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/vienna-golden-boy.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<p>After one more sleep it&rsquo;s time for me to leave Vienna and head to L'viv, Ukraine!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
