<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Career Break | More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/career-break/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-16T08:52:18+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rome, Switzerland and Transition]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/rome-switzerland-and-transition/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T14:09:31+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/rome-switzerland-and-transition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>When in Rome</h3>

<p>When I learned that my uncle and his family would be in Rome I looked at my schedule to see if I could make seeing them
work. It turned out it fit perfectly! The last time I saw them was in London while they were doing their 2013 summer
trip and I was on my Belgian Grand Prix vacation. My aunt and uncle are well versed in the world of business so we had
many evenings discussing what I&rsquo;ve learned from the economics courses and floating ideas of what&rsquo;s next for my life. Of
course I got to catch up with my cousins too. Can&rsquo;t believe how quickly they are growing up (I won&rsquo;t mention that I
remember seeing them in diapers to avoid their embarassment).  They had rented a flat near the Spanish Steps which made
it easy for me to cram in a bunch of sight-seeing in a short amount of time.</p>

<p>Touring Rome is pretty easy because all you have to do is step outside. Even on my first walk I stumbled across many
interersting sites. I did a couple free walking tours, but they weren&rsquo;t organized by Sandeman and weren&rsquo;t nearly the
same quality. Still, it was good to have a guided walk to the Colloseum and to the Vatican.</p>

<p>As beautiful as Rome was, I knew my time as a tourist was ending. I was at the point where I didn&rsquo;t want to elbow my
way through tourists anymore. Nor was I as interested as I was before in exploring musuems and historical places.</p>

<h3>Swiss Bliss</h3>

<p>The other part that made Rome convenient was that I could travel to Switzerland to meet up with fellow ex-ThoughtWork
Marc Hofer, who I worked with in India in ThoughtWorks University (TWU). He had a 1L bottle of scotch ready (we numbed our
heads with scotch nearly every evening during TWU). Thankfully he was generous enough to give me a couch for as long as
I needed one. I ended up spending 10 days in beautiful Thun!</p>

<p>I spent most of my days reading and catching up on my blog writing (it&rsquo;s surprising how long these take to write).
Though I did spend a day biking to Interlaken and another day visiting Geneve, Zurich, and Luzern by train.</p>

<h3>Times are a Changing</h3>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prague, Budapest, and the Hungarian Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T14:23:50+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/prague-budapest-and-the-hungarian-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 22nd &ndash; July 29th</em></p>

<h3>Prague</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/prague.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/prague.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>Next portion of the trip is to Eastern Europe! I had a nice simple itinerary to Prague: <strong>Heidelberg &ndash;> Munich &ndash;> Prague</strong>.
Unfortunately something was going on with the brakes on the train and I missed my train in Munich so it
turned into: <strong>Heidelberg &ndash;> Munich &ndash;> Neurberg &ndash;> Cheb &ndash;> Prague</strong>. By now I&rsquo;m a seasoned itinerary refactorer so this
didn&rsquo;t phase me. These little <em>adjustments of the universe</em> can sometimes end up with interesting things happening. At
the Plzen stop, a woman sat across from me in the couchette. She started speaking to me in Czech and my response was the
standard Canadian response: I&rsquo;m sorry?</p>

<br />


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry?&rdquo; or &ldquo;sowry&rdquo; in the short form is Canadian for: I apologize that I don&rsquo;t speak your language and I&rsquo;m embarassed to
ask you to repeat yourself in English because I&rsquo;ve never had to deal with speaking and understanding multiple languages. Of course
I&rsquo;m also making the assumption that you can speak English because a world without English is just unfathomable. Again,
I&rsquo;m sorry</p></blockquote>

<p>Then in English she said I looked Czech and was just inquiring about the train. Turns out
she spoke excellent English, lives in San Diego and was just in the country to visit her family. Eventually we
started chit chatting and the conversation about my trip became the focus of interest. I had fun demoing her the <a href="/twinery/independent-accord.html">cargo ship tour</a>
and got some usability feedback as a result. Next thing I knew we were in Prague. Even with my limited
social ability to pick up on body language, I think she was flirting with me! In my usual fashion I dropped the ball. We
parted ways with a handshake and me wishing her a pleasant visit with her family.</p>

<p>After hitting my head against a wall for what seemed like a decade, I continued on to a rendezvous point in the
train station where I was to meet up with <a href="https://twitter.com/nohwnd">Jakub Jareš</a>. He&rsquo;s a core contributor to <a href="https://github.com/pester/Pester">Pester</a>,
who in the last 6 months, has taken pretty much all the maintenance burden off of my shoulders. He offered to take me out for beers and I obviously
couldn&rsquo;t resist an offer like that. It was the rainiest day of the summer and he guided me to the <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2094840">airbnb</a>
where I was to stay for the next couple days. Then we proceeded to a <a href="http://www.pivovarskyklub.com/">bar</a> (and got soaked in the process). We enjoyed many beers,
discussed much about software development, and my ineptness with the woman on the train was soon forgotten.</p>

<p>Sandeman operates in Prague too so I did a couple tours:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/prague-castle.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/prague-castle.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/daily-tours/new-prague-free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: I can&rsquo;t really talk about this tour without talking about the guide. <a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/our-guides/pavel.html">Pavel</a>
was quite the character. He had an entertaining dry wit and personalized the tour with stories of his own family. I
was blown away when he said is grandmother has lived in the same flat her whole life and has lived in 9 different
countries as a result. It was a good reminder on the craziness humans have to deal with all the time.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newpraguetours.com/daily-tours/prague-castle-tour.html">Castle Tour</a>: Fortunately, Pavel was the guide for this tour too! He sort of stumbled over a
little late and asked the group if we could deviate from the standard tour itinerary and visit a
<a href="http://europeupclose.com/article/st-norberts-brewery-in-prague/">monastery</a> where some award winning beer is brewed. No one was opposed and I got to have a fantastic
beer at the beginning of the tour. The castle was very different than other castles I&rsquo;ve seen. The distictive
feature was the cathedral but the surrounding buildings were much different. At the end of the tour, I really
enjoyed walking through the <a href="http://www.hrad.cz/en/prague-castle/guidepost-for-visitors/gardens-of-the-prague-castle.shtml#a5">garden around the ramparts</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Overall, I really enjoyed Prague. You really need to avoid the square as much as possible. Once out of the tourist area,
everything is quite afforable and less hectic. Even though my stay was short, I felt that I got the most out of it. I
would like to go back and explore further and do some hacking with Jakub though.</p>

<h3>Arriving in Budapest</h3>

<p>My stay was short in Prague because I had to get to Budapest for the last of my Grand Prix adventure. Fortunately it was
a direct train! The <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/1767274">airbnb</a> was close to the station and was able to take the metro there. I was really happy with the
location, and the host was exceptional in responding to my queries. One interesting thing about taking the train around
Europe is that you start to see patterns in the train stations from different countries. There was quite a difference
between the stations in Czech Republic and Slovakia compared to Germany and Hungary. Now I want to create an archive of
train stations so I can do more comparing and contrasting.</p>

<h3>Hungarian Grand Prix</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/budapest-bags.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/budapest-bags.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>Getting to the race track was a fairly painless experience in Budapest. The transit workers were also extremely helpful
and knowledgable about the logistics of the race. The track was located in a beautiful area just outside Budapest. I
spent the Friday walking around the track (in 35C weather). The track area was super clean and I think that&rsquo;s owed to
the fact that bright blue garbage bags were never more than 20ft away from you. Overall, I would say this Grand Prix had
the most pleasant logistics experience. More importantly though, this was an <a href="http://www.autoblog.com/2014/07/28/race-recap-2014-hungarian-grand-prix-a-thrilling-wet-mess/">incredible race</a>! A cloud burst occured
around 60 minutes before the race began. All the drivers had to change their strategies and start with wet tyres. Then
an accident occured a few laps in that caused some pit lane confusion resulting in the leaders being in the middle of
the pack. Nearly every lap had battles going on from all positions. I think this ranks up there as one of the best races
of the year (Bahrain was pretty close). I&rsquo;m sort of sad that my stream of F1 races is over, but also happy because now
the rest of my time is entirely unscheduled. Who knows, maybe I&rsquo;ll do a quick detour to Belgium and go to the race there
at the end of the month.</p>

<br />


<br />


<h3>Dream Theater in Budapest</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/dream-theater.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/dream-theater.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>As a bonus I saw posters stating that <a href="http://www.dreamtheater.net/">Dream Theater</a> is playing nearby! I&rsquo;ve been a fan of them since 1998 and have never
seen them live! Everything looked too perfect: the venue was a beautiful tram ride away, it starts after the majority of
the F1 events are done, it ended at a decent hour so I could be rested for race day, and tickets were still available!
After freshening up after another hot day at the track I walk to the tram and arrive at the venue around an hour before
the show starts. I was in line to grab some food when the woman next to me asks me a question in Hungarian. Here we go
again! I respond with &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry?&rdquo;. She switches to English and asks if I was
ahead of her. I had no idea, and it didn&rsquo;t really matter to me so I said she was first. As I get my food, she asks where
I&rsquo;m from. I tell her I&rsquo;m going to find some beer and she offers to show me where I can sample some
proper Hungarian liquor. I follow her lead and she orders me palinka which is a fruit brandy. Fortunately I&rsquo;m well
adapted to plum whiskey from hazy memories of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G7Eb7a8-LvQ">ThoughtBoarder</a> trips (thanks <a href="http://www.yycapps.com/2012/09/developer-interview-radu-muresan/">Radu</a>), so the shot goes down easy. She says
she needs to bring the food back to her group and I bid farewell and find a spot in the crowd to watch the show. Ten or
fifteen minutes pass and she finds me in the crowd. We continue to chat about music, travel and Hungary. It turns out
that her dad brought her to the concert (coolest dad in the world!), and she asked if it was ok to hang out with me
during the show (you had to ask?!). You would think that I would have learned my lesson from my previous female
encounter&hellip; nope. Though I did do a bit better. I wrote down my website and she asked if she could find me on Facebook
(I wasn&rsquo;t sure if my profile was searchable, but I said yes). The show was fantastic and made better by having her company.
I got a message from her a few days later and we&rsquo;re still corresponding! Clearly something supernatural was going on as
you can tell from this image of the show.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/budapest-view.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/budapest-view.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<p>The weather following the race was not so good. I managed to explore a little bit around the vicinity of where I was
staying, but spent most of the time catching up with Coursera. Sandeman did not have any presence in Budapest so I took
a free tour by another organization. I can&rsquo;t say it was up to the same standard, but it was still informative
nevertheless. It ended near the castle and I enjoyed a relatively rain free walk back to my flat and prepared for my
next destination, Rome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glasgow, Berlin, Heidelberg and the German Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/glasgow-berlin-heidelberg-and-the-german-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-21T14:44:37+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/glasgow-berlin-heidelberg-and-the-german-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>July 7th &ndash; July 21st</em></p>

<h3>Reunions in Glasgow</h3>

<p>Since my train didn&rsquo;t leave until after noon, I decided to go back to Bletchley Park and spend the
morning there. It was so nice to just spend some idle time in the park and not hurry through the
exhibits. Unrushed, I made my way to the train station for a direct train to Glasgow.
Upon arrival at the station I was greeted by Derek and <a href="http://adidav9.blogspot.cz/">Rose</a> who I know from back in the Calgary
days. They&rsquo;ve been super generous and hosting me at their apartment which is close to the train station.
It was fun to look back at the tough project we worked on together and look at the experience with
fondness and nostalgia. Rose was my concert buddy and Derek was probably the only person I know
that likes <a href="http://www.sundance.tv/series/greenporno">Green Porno</a> as much as I do.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/glasgow-necropolis.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/glasgow-necropolis.small.jpg" width="300"></a> During my first
day I wandered around the city center and then went up to the <a href="http://www.glasgownecropolis.org/">Necropolis</a>. It was
a beautiful place and had a view over the city. Had I been more prepared I would have spent more time
there in search of graves of noteworthy people. On my walk back to the apartment I saw an e-mail from
the company that chartered my cargo ship cruise. Apparently BBC&rsquo;s Travel Show was looking for people
to interview! I got in touch with someone from the BBC, and was scheduled for an interview the next
day.</p>

<p>The next day I spent the morning doing laundry, and then walked over to the BBC for the interview (<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p0232gkn">the clip is online now</a>).
The camera man was a really cool dude named James Allen. He said he enjoyed the interview
because it was a break from more monotonous stuff he was doing earlier in the day (filming people cooking). Of course
I had to talk about my CBC experience with him and he revealed that he&rsquo;s in a band! They are called
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cJIndPO4OqE">Mummy Short Arms</a>, which is so fitting given the pun I posted on Facebook the day before! After the
interview and lots of walking, I met up with a bunch of ThoughtWorkers for dinner. It became very
clear to me that evening that I miss ThoughtWorkers a lot, but ThoughtWorks not as much.</p>

<h3>Edinburgh</h3>

<p>My last day was spent on a day trip to Edinburgh. People have always said that it&rsquo;s a beautiful city and
they are right. It was more beautiful than I expected and spent the day taking a couple tours. A big
thank you to Rose for telling me about <a href="http://www.neweuropetours.eu/">Sandeman</a> tours. I did the following:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/edinburgh-free-tour.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/edinburgh-free-tour.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newedinburghtours.com/daily-tours/new-edinburgh-free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: After this first tour, I was hooked on this style. The guides were young and
full of enthusiasm. My picture of a guided tour was of a slow moving parade of old people getting bombarded
with facts and dates. This tour group does a great job of keeping the energy up. One thing I observed was how focused
the audience got when the guide mentioned that something was a feature or inspiration for a movie, myself included.
It&rsquo;s interesting how pop culture somehow makes things more relevant to your mind.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newedinburghtours.com/daily-tours/castle-tour-edinburgh.html">Castle Tour</a>: Since I liked the free tour so much, I decided to do the castle tour. The guide
was a <a href="http://www.newedinburghtours.com/our-guides/billy.html">charismatic Scotsman</a> and told a story about the castle and Edinburgh in such a way that you could transport
yourself to that era.</li>
</ul>


<p>I was sad to leave Scotland because it&rsquo;s such a friendly place. Unfortunately it&rsquo;s also expensive,
although I guess it&rsquo;s cheaper than London, but that&rsquo;s not saying much.</p>

<h3>Berlin</h3>

<p>I had to wake up at 3:30am to begin my trip to Berlin! The interary was a bit complex: Glasgow &ndash;> London &ndash;> Brussels
&ndash;> Koln &ndash;> Berlin. Here I was going to stay with an ex-ThoughtWorker, <a href="https://twitter.com/pcalcado">Phil Calcado</a>. The interesting
thing about Phil is that I barely know him! I had a couple beers with him
the year before, but he happily hosted me in his awesome flat for several days. I eventually made it to
his place at around 11:00pm (I didn&rsquo;t quite navigate the Berlin metro optimally that evening). There
was a little <a href="https://soundcloud.com/">SoundCloud</a> gathering going on and another ex-ThoughtWorker, <a href="https://twitter.com/tomczarniecki">Tom Czarniecki</a>, was
there too! It seems the world has ThoughtWorks affiliates everywhere.</p>

<p>It appears I timed things well as I got to be in Germany for the world cup final! Myself and Phil went
down to <a href="http://www.pratergarten.de/d/">Prater Biergarten</a>. Tom joined us a bit later. Then for some odd reason, I got interviewed by
a Mexican journalist. I&rsquo;m not making it up, because Phil and Tom will vouch for me. The whole city turned
into a party and we stayed out til around 4:00am. I still can&rsquo;t get the Uber Deuchstland song out of my head.</p>

<p>Like in Edinburgh, Sandeman does tours in Berlin. I did these three:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/potsdam-tour.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/potsdam-tour.small.jpg" width="300"></a></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newberlintours.com/daily-tours/free-tour.html">Free Tour</a>: Like in Edinburgh, the guide was passionate and energetic. It was fascinating to
see the Jewish memorial, and place related to the war.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newberlintours.com/daily-tours/potsdam-city-of-emperors.html">Potsdam</a>: I was craving something different and this tour looked to offer that. I got the same
guide as the day before. I didn&rsquo;t know a single thing about the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prussia">Prussian empire</a> before and this tour made me start
reading tons of Wikipedia articles about it. My favourite part of this tour was wandering the gardens created by
emperors, especially <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sanssouci_Park">Sanssouci Park</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newberlintours.com/daily-tours/sachsenhausen-memorial.html">Sauchsenhausen</a>: I wasn&rsquo;t sure what to expect in a tour of a concentration camp. The
guide impressed me by how he approached the subject matter. I&rsquo;m glad I saw the camp, even
though it can&rsquo;t really be described as a pleasant tour. It&rsquo;s a reminder that normal people can do terrible things.</li>
</ul>


<p>Before I left I had one more evening of beers with yet another <a href="https://twitter.com/dtemme">ex-ThoughtWorker</a>, Daniel Temme!</p>

<h3>Heidelberg</h3>

<p>Travel from Berlin to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heidelberg">Heidelberg</a> was a direct train. I made my way to my <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2337045">airbnb</a>
and got settled for spending some time in this beautiful town. I purposely planned to have a free day before the F1. I wandered throughout
the old town and the castle. My favourite thing about this part of the trip are the picnics I had; the top one being
on a bench in Philospher&rsquo;s Way. The weather was so hot that I didn&rsquo;t really want to stay inside a restaurant, nor a
patio. It was really nice to simply purchase some groceries and wander around looking for a nice spot in the town to
eat.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-bridge.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-bridge.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-philosophersweg.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-philosophersweg.small.jpg" width="335"></a>
<a href="/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-castle.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/heidelberg-castle.small.jpg" width="335"></a></p>

<h3>German Grand Prix</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/hockenheim-podium.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/hockenheim-podium.small.jpg" width="300"></a>
Getting to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hockenheim">Hockenheim</a> was pretty straighforward. There&rsquo;s a bus from the train station, or I can take a
train with a single connection in Manheim. The race weekend was super hot with the air temperature around
35C and they said the track temperature was around 55C! I need to learn what exactly track temperature
means, but I&rsquo;m guessing it&rsquo;s how hot it is in you&rsquo;re sitting in the sun.</p>

<p>So far this race is where I&rsquo;ve had the best seats. I was amazing to actually see the cars start the race
and watch them go through the first turn. It was scary to see Massa&rsquo;s car flip during the start of the race but
was relieved to see him walk out of the car. The picture here is a first for me; I actually made it to the podium area for
the awards ceremony!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belgium, France, London and the British Grand Prix]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-08T14:42:19+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/belgium-france-london-and-the-british-grand-prix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>June 24th &ndash; July 7th</em></p>

<h3>Shipment Delivered</h3>

<p>Upon arrival in Antwerp I saw my taxi from the deck. I had all my belongings ready and made my way down
to the port. The ship crew was busy with the offloading of containers so I decided it probably wasn’t a good idea
to disturb them to say farewell. It was a long drive to the immigration office, and there I found out that I needed
a passenger manifest to get the stamp of approval. This meant going all the way back to the ship and back. This
added around an extra hour of taxi travel. The chief mate was ready for my return as he had the document in his
hand. After that confusion, I made it to central Antwerp and found a hotel near the train station.</p>

<p>Antwerp is a fairly small city. The port area takes up more space than the actual city. After a quick nap I wandered
around old Antwerp and in the evening found a little pub. I ended up having more drinks than necessary with a couple
that were a lot of fun. The lady has been in the shipping industry and even knew the ship that I came in on!</p>

<h3>In Bruges</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/bruges.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/bruges.small.jpg" width="300"></a> The trip
from Antwerp to Bruges was pretty easy. As was finding the <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/2176619">residence</a> I was going to stay in. The house was
just outside the old town so after getting some travel logistics out of the way I set out to do a walking tour.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bruges">Bruges</a> is one of the prettiest towns I’ve ever seen. It’s like a snapshot
in time of Belgium several hundred years ago.  In some spots it was insanely crowded, but in other spots it
was quiet and peaceful, which made me stick to those areas. When I got back, I met Lander, the
host of the house. He was very personable and enjoyed conversing with him about my travels.</p>

<p>The next day I did another self guided walking tour. My favourite moment was just relaxing having a couple beers at the
<a href="http://fr.yelp.be/biz/caf%C3%A9-vlissinghe-brugge">oldest tavern</a> in Bruges. After a full day in the town I went back to the house where Lander invited some friends over for
the game. We then headed out to watch the Belgium game in the town square. It was so much fun! I lost the group for a
bit so I gave my round of beers to some random strangers in the crowd. That seemed to make people happy. Next thing I
know it&rsquo;s 5:00am and I&rsquo;m chatting away with a fellow drunk.</p>

<p>These are the beers I had in Belgium:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.dekoninck.be/en">De Koninck</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.boon.be/en/our-beers/geuze-boon-old-style">Gueze Boon</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.rodenbach.be/">Rodenbach</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.trappistwestmalle.be/en/page/dubbel.aspx">Westmalle Trappist Dubbel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.duvel.com/en-us">Duvel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.orval.be/en/58/How-Orval-beer-is-made">Orval</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.abbaye-de-leffe.be/the_beer/en_5_varieties_of_beer_article200.html">Leffe Dark</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/index.php?id=15&amp;L=2">Brugse Zot</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bestbelgianspecialbeers.be/main_eng.html">Tripel Karmeliet</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/index.php?id=14&amp;L=2">Straffe Hendrik</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.achouffe.be/en/beers#la-chouffe">La Chouffe</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Of all of these, I would say the <strong>Tripel Karmeliet</strong> and <strong>Orval</strong> were my favourites. There are so many beers to try
that I really want to come back and spend several weeks sampling all the wonderful beers. There&rsquo;s something about
a country where the monks participate in the brewing process. The day before I got to Bruges, the <a href="http://www.halvemaan.be/">De Halve Maan</a>
had a priest come in and bless their new brewing equipment!</p>

<h3>Dieppe Thoughts</h3>

<p>The next leg of my trip is to Dieppe, France. Unfortunately I woke up hungover and slept through my alarm. This meant
I missed my train which had the best connections to Dieppe. Armed with the
<a href="http://www.eurail.com/plan-your-trip/rail-planner-app">Eurail app</a>, I tried to make a new itinerary.
Due to my decisions of last night, I slept through my connection and passed Brussels. Turned out it didn’t really matter
because at the following station I learned it was the first day of holidays in France and all reservation trains were booked.
Using the app, I figured out an itinerary that could get me to Dieppe without reserved seating. One of the trains was delayed
and I just made my only connecting train with only a minute to spare. Last part of the journey was the walk to to where
I <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/1157655">stayed</a>. The only issue was that I forgot to cache the map, but at least I had a star showing where it
was and functional gps.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/dieppe.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/blog/career-break/dieppe.small.jpg" width="300"></a> My primary motivation
for visiting Dieppe was to see the beaches the Canadian troops attempted to invade in WWII. The
invasion of Dieppe preceded D-Day and was used as an information gathering invasion. Essentially they learned a lot at
the expenses of thousands of lives. I’m not a patriotic person, but I couldn’t help but feel moved by the lives that were lost
there. You can read more at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dieppe_Raid">Wikipedia</a> (notice that my picture of the beach
is very close to the image in Wikipedia!</p>

<p>After my walk about, I walked some more! I headed down to where all the restaurants were and had a nice meal and then
proceeded to hang around the beach area to catch the sunset. It was definitely worth it.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/dieppe-sunset.jpg"><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/dieppe-sunset.medium.jpg" width="1024"></a></p>

<h3>A Boat Time</h3>

<p>At 3:30am I left the residence and walked to the ferry terminal. Luckily I walked there the day before so I knew how long
it would take, and that I had to be there at 4:30am. I wasn’t initially planning on being there that early so I’m glad I did
my exploratory research. The ferry was pleasant, but spent the majority of the journey falling asleep and hitting my head against the window.</p>

<h3>London Calling</h3>

<p>The ferry arrived in Newhaven on time. I had a nice chat with the immigration officer who supported my goal of seeing
all the Formula 1 races. I got my luggage and took a series of trains to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hitchin">Hitchin</a> where
I met up with <a href="https://twitter.com/zoodor">Mark</a>, a old ThoughtWorks colleague. It was quite refreshing to see a familiar face!</p>

<p>My next few days were lunch and dinner plans with people I know in London. I got a chance to talk about where my mind
is at regarding my future. It was also nice to see more familiar faces. I really like London, but all the tubing around I was
doing unfortunately left me with a cold before I left.</p>

<h3>Milton Keynes</h3>

<p>This was to be my face for the first F1 on my trip. My <a href="https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/1433999">hosts</a> picked up from the
train station. They were amazing hosts and were very pleasant to talk to. I had a lot of fun talking shop
with them as they run an <a href="http://evidencetalks.com/en/">IT business</a> in the city centre.
Their <a href="http://mxcl.github.io/">son</a> is also note-worthy as he created <a href="http://brew.sh/">Homebrew</a>!</p>

<p>The city of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milton_Keynes">Milton Keynes</a> was interesting because it was a planned city.
It was easy to get around, there were plenty of trails that made walking around the periphery quite pleasant.</p>

<h3>This Place is the Bombe!</h3>

<p>I planned for a free day before the race so I could visit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bletchley_Park">Bletchley Park</a>.
It was such an amazing experience to see where
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing">Alan Turing</a> worked and observing a working Colossus, WITCH, and
Bombe machines (in the <a href="http://www.tnmoc.org/">National Museum of Computing</a>)! While visiting the grounds it made
me think about NSA’s involvement in security. If the NSA had a facility that celebrated its ability to crack codes, I don’t think
people would have the same feeling. WWII was great a creating a binary view of activities. Bletchley Park was also
dismantled after the war. I guess things were simpler and less ambiguous then.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what the Colossus sounds like! I wish I recorded a lot more audio because I can hear a song wanting to come out.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no"
src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/157140660&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;visual=true"></iframe>


<h3>&nbsp;</h3>

<h3>Race 1 of 3</h3>

<p><a href="/images/blog/career-break/british-gp.jpg"><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/british-gp.small.jpg"></a> The commute to the
track was quite reasonable, but Friday was a bit much for me as I was in the worst part of my cold.
Saturday had the most comfortable weather and I spent a lot of time at the track enjoying different vantage points. Race
day was a big spectacle as it was the 50th race at Silverstone. Before the race there was an air display by the Red Arrows.
It was far better than I had expected. Afterwards I went up to me seat and watched a great race. Lots of drama on the first
lap as Raikonnen had an accident. This red flagged the race as they had to repair a barrier on the track. The rest of the
race was rather uneventful, but the battle between Alonso and Vettel (below) was a show of great driver talent. It was
a shame Roseberg had a malfunction because the battle for 1st could have been just as great.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="640" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/jyhz5c0mR4c" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h3>To Glasgow</h3>

<p>The journey continues to Glasgow, Scotland! The write up for that will have to wait though as this post is long
enough. I was going to write about my learnings over the last few weeks, but will hold that thought for a bit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossing the Atlantic via Container Ship]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/crossing-the-atlantic-via-container-ship/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-24T06:02:51+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/crossing-the-atlantic-via-container-ship</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned in my <a href="/leaving-vancouver-and-north-america/">last post</a>, I finished the crossing of the Atlantic ocean via container ship. It was a great
experiene that I&rsquo;ll happily do again. 11 days wasn&rsquo;t enough, and would be happy to spend a month next time around.</p>

<h3>Too Much Twine on my Hands</h3>

<p>A blog post probably wouldn&rsquo;t due the experience justice so I decided to play around with a basic word game engine to
give you a more <a href="/twinery/independent-accord.html">self-directed tour</a>. Hope you enjoy it!</p>

<p>Working with <a href="http://twinery.org/">Twine</a> was quite enjoyable and I could see myself using it a lot in many different lines of work. If I was
still consulting, it would become a prominent tool in my tool-belt. My biggest complaint with it is that the
documentation is all online so I couldn&rsquo;t figure out how to do anything more sophisticated than what I created.</p>

<h3>Man Over-bored</h3>

<p>Honestly, that header was just for the pun factor. What amazed me about the voyage was how quick it went by. I didn&rsquo;t
think <strong>once</strong> that I wanted it to end and that I was bored. I savoured not being in a rush to do anything. The only structure to my
days revolved around meals which were at: 07:30, 12:30, and 17:30. That set my rythym for the 11 days.</p>

<h3>Crew Man Group</h3>

<p>The ship was run by a crew of 21, all male. The captain was Romanian and the rest of the officers were Croation. The chief
engineer was Ukrainian and the rest were Filipino. Everyone was very nice, but when asked for their name, they simply
asked to be addressed by their position (Third, Chief, etc&hellip;).</p>

<h3>Retrospective</h3>

<p><strong>What Went Well</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Scotch &ndash; Sipping 18yo Glenlivet was a wonderful way to be even <em>more</em> relaxed</li>
<li>Jambox &ndash; This dependable gadget has been filling rooms with tunes well for several years now</li>
<li>Offline Wikipedia &ndash; Wow! I cannot believe how much I perused Wikipedia while I was on this trip.</li>
<li>11 days of no expenses &ndash; Being disconnected is a good way to not spend money.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Not So Well</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Gym clothes &ndash; There&rsquo;s an exercise room with a stationary bike. I wasn&rsquo;t always allowed on the main deck (to do laps
around the ship) so being able to do 30min of hard cardio would have been good to stave off the belly I grew.</li>
<li>Scotch &ndash; One bottle was definitely not enough.</li>
<li>Offline map &ndash; I would have liked to better explorer the route and plan the rest of my trip better.</li>
<li>Making Twine tour at the last minute &ndash; I wish I had a skeleton of it done much earlier so I could get more details
from the crew.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Action Items</strong>: I&rsquo;ll definitely do this again and I&rsquo;ll be sure to come with a fitness plan. Though that directly opposes the action to
bring more liquor.</p>

<h3>Offline By Default</h3>

<p>Being disconnected from the world for 11 days was a far better experience than I had expected. It&rsquo;s made me realize I
need to create a habit of disconnecting. It brought me back to the era when your computer was offline by default, and
you had to explicitly connect to see what&rsquo;s going on in the rest of the Internet universe. This experience has showed me
that I like that. It may sound backwards to a lot of people, but the computer has always been a tool, not an
entertainment device (gaming being the exception). My phone may eventually be the only always-connected device, but even
then, I turn off all notifications and keep it silent.</p>

<h3>Let the Eurotrip Begin</h3>

<p>After a 140 euro ride through immigration and into Antwerp, I can begin the next phase of my journey!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
