<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tls | More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/tls/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-07T20:57:36+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - TLS]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-tls/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-06T21:40:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-tls</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is embarassing to admit but I have to re-learn TLS on a continuous basis. This post is my cheatsheet to remembering
all the itty bitty details, which I&rsquo;ll forgot shortly after I do whatever TLS related task I have on my plate.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s The Difference Between SSL And TLS?</h2>

<p>The fact that I still think <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security">SSL</a> over <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security">TLS</a> is likely a result of my first exposure to dealing with
these sorts of things was in a multi-tenant Windows web hosting environment. I seriously can&rsquo;t believe I was able to do
the things I did back then without having one iota of understanding what was going on.</p>

<p>I only learned that the difference between <em>SSL</em> and <em>TLS</em> is so simple just a couple years ago. It boils down to this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Are you expecting a secure connection because the port you&rsquo;re connecting to is by definition intended to be a secure
port? Then we&rsquo;re talking about <strong>SSL</strong>.</li>
<li>Do you start connecting and switch to a secure mode based on the feedback coming back over the &ldquo;wire&rdquo;? Then we&rsquo;re
talking about <strong>TLS</strong>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Yup, it&rsquo;s as simple as that. Big thanks to the <a href="https://luxsci.com/blog/ssl-versus-tls-whats-the-difference.html">SSL vs TLS &ndash; What&rsquo;s the Difference?</a> post for helping
me finally understand this!</p>

<h2>What Are Certificates?</h2>

<p>When it comes to certifcates, I&rsquo;ve yet to find a resource that does a good high level explanation. For the time being
I&rsquo;ve found <a href="https://blog.talpor.com/2015/07/ssltls-certificates-beginners-tutorial/">SSL/TLS Certificates Beginners' Tutorial</a> the best resource because it does explain the <code>openssl</code>
command in a bit of detail and links to even more resources. Having a basic grasp of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Certificate_authority">Certificate Authorities</a>,
and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chain_of_trust">chain of trust</a> (not a 90&rsquo;s Christian metal band) is another piece
of the puzzle to understand well because it&rsquo;s where things can often go wrong and result in cryptic errors
(like the browser warnings that we all ignore).</p>

<p>My simplified understanding is that a certificate certifies hat the one (machine) with the certificate is the entity
that the certificate says it&rsquo;s certifying. I believe this is true for server and client certificates, but I am not 100% sure.</p>

<h2>What Goes On When You Use HTTPS?</h2>

<p>Nearly everytime I need to setup <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTPS">HTTPS</a> I find that I need to reread the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTPS">First Few Milliseconds of an HTTPS Connection</a> article. It&rsquo;s a long read but if you spend a day following
the links and focusing on understanding that article, you&rsquo;ll tackle any <em>HTTPS</em> related task with ease. You&rsquo;ll just
forget it all after a few days.</p>

<h2>How Do Things Go Wrong?</h2>

<p>The following video by <a href="https://moxie.org/">Moxie Marlinspike</a> is told at a nice slow pace on how certificates can break down.
It&rsquo;s a good reminder to be humble when dealing with these complex security tools. I tend to rewatch this video after
reading the above articles. If I can follow the video, then I&rsquo;ve chunked enough knowledge to move on.</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ibF36Yyeehw " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>Hope these help. It&rsquo;s inspired by all the other folks that also couldn&rsquo;t tell me the difference between SSL and TLS.
It&rsquo;s easy to feel ashamed about not knowing these technologies, security is a very hard domain. I&rsquo;ve kept my
explanations to a minimum because I don&rsquo;t feel confident I can provide correct information, nor am I able to explain it
simply. When in doubt, I&rsquo;ll look to the resources here. Hopefully this will give you a good starting ground if you&rsquo;ve
been asked to do anything related to <strong>SSL/TLS</strong> and <strong>certificates</strong>.</p>

<p><em>This post took 2 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
