<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Soundcloud | More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="https://scottmuc.com/archive/blog/categories/soundcloud/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://scottmuc.com/archive/"/>
  <updated>2024-01-30T22:08:23+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://scottmuc.com/archive/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joining Pivotal Cloud Foundry and Moving to Dublin]]></title>
    <link href="https://scottmuc.com/archive/joining-pivotal-cloud-foundry-and-moving-to-dublin/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-21T21:45:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://scottmuc.com/archive/joining-pivotal-cloud-foundry-and-moving-to-dublin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/pivotal-office.jpg" width="1024"></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I&rsquo;ve posted a &ldquo;life update&rdquo;. The <strong>TL;DR</strong> is that I have joined <a href="http://pivotal.io/platform">Pivotal Cloud Foundry</a> in
January and will be moving to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dublin">Dublin</a> in June.</p>

<h2>Reflections on Berlin and SoundCloud</h2>

<p>My guess is the most frequent question about this is: what happened? When I <a href="/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">posted</a> about my decision to
move to Berlin and join SoundCloud it appeared that I had found something I really wanted to do. Looking back at the
post you can see subtle hints of doubt, but went with the option that seemed a little more risky. In the end, the risk
was worth it as I learned a heck of a lot!</p>

<p><strong>The Awesome Stuff</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Berlin has been my favourite city I&rsquo;ve ever lived in. It&rsquo;s modified future projections of where I would like to live
long term. It&rsquo;s a city for humans with its comprehensive public transportation system, low cost of living, and its
openness to new cultures moving to the city.</li>
<li>I felt I managed to fulfill many of the goals I had set in mind in my earlier <a href="/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/">post</a>. My most important
take-away is having developed empathy for those who speak English as a second language.</li>
<li>More traveling (Ukraine for Easter, Prague, London, Paris, Germany, and Switzerland). There are still so many places
to check out.</li>
<li>New friends (you know who you are)</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Not So Awesome Stuff</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Working in the media domain is very different than the public media domain. As monetization became a focus and utilizing
advertising became a core piece of it, I felt that it wasn&rsquo;t a strategy I wanted to participate in. Watching <a href="http://thoughtmaybe.com/the-century-of-the-self/">Century of Self</a>
too many times has probably made me a bit too cynical about advertising.</li>
<li>Really missed the ThoughtWorks culture around software development. I missed pair-programming and the role was more
consulting than it was software-dev (which is one of the reasons why I left ThoughtWorks). At the same time, I learned
how important it is to be aligned with the &ldquo;how we do work&rdquo; at an organisation. I can&rsquo;t say SoundCloud is doing it
wrong&hellip; there&rsquo;s just too little data to make that call. All I know is that it left me drained and unmotivated (but
has the opposite effect for many of the great engineers there).</li>
<li>I injured my hamstrings (and later my back), that definitely affected my life, but unrelated to my decision to move to
Berlin and join SoundCloud.</li>
<li>My personal possessions didn&rsquo;t reach Berlin until July which may have made the whole move feel quite transitory since
I never quite got the chance to settle down properly. I had grown the thought of leaving SoundCloud only just a few
months after my things from Canada had arrived.</li>
</ul>


<h2>What Triggered the Change?</h2>

<p>The funny thing is when I explain the work I was a part of in SoundCloud many folks wonder why I would ever leave. The
technology was interesting and we had a lot of autonomy. This was true, but when it comes to work, I&rsquo;m a process over
product kind of person. After a few events occurred I felt the urge to explore my options. I reached out to <a href="https://twitter.com/mkocher">Mathew Kocher</a>
and he said that the offer from a year ago still stands! After living in Berlin, I didn&rsquo;t have much
desire to leave the city let alone move to North America. He encouraged me to go to London and go through another round
of interviews.</p>

<p>In London I had a fantastic day of pairing interviews then a good evening out with <a href="https://twitter.com/tammersaleh">Tammer Saleh</a>. We discussed
many things about the industry (he later was a receipient of my link bombs that I often send out after an evening discussion). I was
definitely engergized about the experience but still wasn&rsquo;t decided. A few weeks later, many people came to Berlin for
the <a href="http://berlin2015.cfsummit.com/">Cloud Foundry Summit</a> and there  was a chance to meet some more people. I expressed that I love Berlin a lot,
and that I wasn&rsquo;t ready to leave Europe. Then the option of Dublin came up. It would allow me to go to SF for 3 months
and move to Ireland in the summertime. If I do want to do consulting again, there&rsquo;s a <a href="http://pivotal.io/locations/berlin">Pivotal Labs office in Berlin</a>.</p>

<p>The energy I had after the pairing sessions still was on my mind. I learned that the 3rd pillar of the company is to &ldquo;Be
Nice&rdquo; and the people I interacted with definitely seemed to espouse this value. After a few more days of discussing the
contract and some e-mail back and forth, I gave my notice to SoundCloud and accepted the offer from Pivotal.</p>

<h2>So What is Happening Now?</h2>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Ireland_Dublin_Night.JPG"><img class="right" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/93/Ireland%5FDublin%5FNight.JPG/640px-Ireland%5FDublin%5FNight.JPG" width="640"></a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s quite common for companies to have a 2-3 month notice period. So I had 2 months to finish up my work at SoundCloud
and then figure out the process for a Canadian living in Germany soon to be employed in Ireland but going to begin work
in the USA. I&rsquo;ll spare the details, but I managed to get my passport the day before going to SF.</p>

<p>After 3 weeks I&rsquo;m feeling quite good about my decision. I&rsquo;ve been pairing every single day and really enjoy the people
that I&rsquo;m working with. There&rsquo;s a strong diversity initiative as well, so hopefully the demographics of the organisation
will be just as good as ThoughtWorks. The applications for Cloud Foundry are more large scale and focused on the
Enterprise which I&rsquo;ve learned is an area that I&rsquo;m much more interested in (as opposed to start up products).</p>

<p>Since I&rsquo;ve &ldquo;lived&rdquo; in SF before I&rsquo;m not feeling very rushed. I&rsquo;m spending my days as I normally would with meeting up
with friends periodically dotting my calendar. I&rsquo;m excited about living in Dublin even though I&rsquo;ve never set foot in
Ireland before!</p>

<p>Even my back is feeling a bit better. I managed to do 2 3k runs this weekend. :&ndash;)</p>

<p><em>This post took 6 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joining SoundCloud and Moving to Berlin]]></title>
    <link href="https://scottmuc.com/archive/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-05T13:09:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://scottmuc.com/archive/joining-soundcloud-and-moving-to-berlin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/berlin-reichstag.medium.jpg" width="900"></p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t say exactly when the job search began. It began with the creation of a Note in Evernote (great tool
for this type of task). It was much different than any other job search I&rsquo;ve done, though I haven&rsquo;t done many as I tend
to stick to job for at least 4 years at a time. The key difference with this search was that I wasn&rsquo;t working, and
wasn&rsquo;t in a hurry to find a job. This allowed me to stick to some rules and a manifesto:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>&ndash; Being open to being located anywhere I&rsquo;ve been before, and know at least someone there<br/>&ndash; Someone I know and respect must have worked there or works there now<br/>&ndash; The company must have cloud in the name ;&ndash;)</p><footer><strong>Scott Muc</strong> <cite>Job Application Criteria</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>manifesto:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>&ndash; People happiness over company success<br/>&ndash; Autonomy over being embedded in a machine<br/>&ndash; Physical and mental health over product growth<br/>&ndash; Access to beer over location</p><footer><strong>Scott Muc</strong> <cite>Preferred Employer Manifesto</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Those set me up much better to see if the company was a fit for me. It remains to be seen, but I think that being open
about my job search, my principals, and not being in a rush will result in a much better mutual partnership. It was a
zero stress endevour and I wish more people had the same privilege to be more precise about the work they apply for.</p>

<p>After several months I interviewed with a handful of companies, but eventually I narrowed it down.</p>

<h2>Then There Were Two</h2>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/cloudfoundry.jpg" width="300">
<strong><a href="http://cloudfoundry.org/">Cloud Foundry</a></strong> &ndash; Creators of an open source <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Platform_as_a_service">PaaS</a> software that allows for companies to create
their own <a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a>. I&rsquo;m not too familiar with the details of the product. It&rsquo;s not like you take a
piece of PaaS enabling software for a test drive every day. Despite not being knowledgable about their product, my
desire to work with them grew as a result of their fantastic interview process.</p>

<p>Every interview required pairing and coding. For me, this delivered a clear idea on how they work and that they prefered
a show me don&rsquo;t tell me approach to interviewing (which I think is awesome). The first pairing
exercise was pretty simple and I was the navigator. As remote pairing exercises go, this was great.
Because I wasn&rsquo;t driving, I wasn&rsquo;t self-conscious about my IDE skills or typing. <strong>David</strong>, who interviewed me, was
clearly prepared and made the interview smooth and fun.</p>

<p>The other two interviews were both roughly around 3 hours long. I was pairing with someone on some small code change
they were assigned to do. Both of them were with code and libraries I wasn&rsquo;t familiar with (go lang, anguluarJS), but
I was amazed at how much that didn&rsquo;t seem to matter. I asked questions, got the gist of what they were trying to do,
and did my best to keep iterating forward as much as possible given my knowledge constraints. The pairs were fun to work
with and I appreciated how they were able to slow down to my level to include me in the process of solving the issue.
I&rsquo;ve learned a lot on how to conduct an interview from this process.</p>

<p>I came away really feeling like these were people I would love to work with. More than that, I loved their discipline in
XP practices. Working with Cloud Foundry, I could become an expert in this field. They also respected employees work/life
balance and that&rsquo;s crucial for me.</p>

<p>The job would be located in San Francisco, and the pay would reflect that, though the cost of living would offset it.
It&rsquo;s a city I&rsquo;ve lived in before and enjoyed. I have a lot of friends there and would be immersed in beer culture.
My role would be a developer working on pieces of Cloud Foundry. So it&rsquo;s an opportunity to develop my dev chops again.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/blog/career-break/soundcloud.png" width="300">
<strong><a href="https://soundcloud.com/">Soundcloud</a></strong> &ndash; The only way I can describe it is Twitter for audio. I&rsquo;ve only used the basic recording
functionality of their service (<a href="https://soundcloud.com/scottmuc">my profile</a>) and do listen to a few podcasts that are hosted by them.</p>

<p>Their interview process felt a bit more ad hoc compared to Cloud Foundry. After the initial screening interview with
<strong>Chris</strong>, who I would correspond with during the whole process, there was a developer assignment.</p>

<p>I had a blast working on the dev assignment! I had the luxury of not having a job so I got to spend a decent amount of
time on it. I&rsquo;m unsure about my code, but what I enjoyed was the process of how I grew the solution. Something that you
can&rsquo;t really demonstrate with a code submission. A pairing interview would have been nice so I could better get to know
how they work on a problem. I never did get any feedback on my submission. It would be nice to receive some just to get
a better feel for how they review code and deliver feedback.</p>

<p>After that I had a few more interviews more related to the role that they had envisioned I would fill and that would be
a member of the <a href="http://continuousdelivery.com/">Continuous Delivery</a> team. When I heard that my reaction was on how that&rsquo;s a bit
of an anti-pattern. After discussing it with them, I could see the team that they have formed aligns very much with I
would do if I were asked to create a &ldquo;Continuous Delivery&rdquo; team. It was great to see a bit of a shared mindset.</p>

<p>The location would be in Berlin, and the pay also reflects that. Though the cost of living is lower. I&rsquo;ve visited Berlin
twice and really enjoyed the city. I only know a handful of people there, but it is closer to people I know from all
around the area. The beer culture is definitely a huge plus, and can be great if I meet up with beer brewers in the
community. Being part of a CD team that&rsquo;s breaking down a monolith should provide some valuable experience and put me in
a position to practice a lot more than I preach.</p>

<h2>What Did I Choose?</h2>

<p>Both opportunities aligned well with my rules and manifesto. After a week of thinking (<strong>cough</strong> over-analyzing) about
it, I decided to accept the offer from <strong>Soundcloud</strong>! That means I&rsquo;ll be moving to Berlin in January 2015.</p>

<p>My mind kept flipping back and forth. Initially I thought for sure I was going to <strong>Cloud Foundry</strong>. I had already told
friends that I was going to San Francisco. The professionalism of the interview process had me convinced
that&rsquo;s where I would be most comfortable.</p>

<p>One of my best friends taught me a trick when it comes to making choices. Flip a coin and assign each choice to a
side. Treat the coin as if it&rsquo;s deciding your fate. If what results makes you feel joy and happiness, that&rsquo;s the right
choice. If you sort of deep down wish that the other side won, then you pick the other one. She suggested it with this
decision and I chickened out. Though what I ended up doing had the same result. I created a poll and posted it on Twitter.
It didn&rsquo;t really matter what the results were, but I noticed something. One, I voted for Berlin. Two, I was cheering on
Berlin while the votes were coming in.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/career-break/strawpoll.png" width="800"></p>

<h3>Choosing What Scares You</h3>

<p>SoundCloud felt like the riskier and scarier option to me which usually means a greater chance to grow and learn. Don&rsquo;t
get me wrong, Cloud Foundry would been a great chance to grow and learn, but I felt that it would be focused in the
technology spectrum. There looks to be more potential to grow as a person with SoundCloud.</p>

<h3>Learning a Language (That&rsquo;s Not a Programming Language)</h3>

<p>I have a hidden life goal of learning a second language. When I was a coach at ThoughtWorks University I had some
tough experiences with learners that did not speak English as their first language. I want to feel and understand better
what it&rsquo;s like to speak another language. There&rsquo;s a lot of potential for transfer of knowledge (ooh, applying my
<a href="/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-by-barbara-oakley/">Learning how to Learn</a> lessons already) when translating. SoundCloud provides German lessons as a benefit and I plan on
taking advantage of that perk.</p>

<h3>More F1</h3>

<p>Nearly the entire F1 calendar is accessible from Berlin! I can continue fulfilling my other life goal which is to attend
all F1 races in my life time. These are the tracks that I can reach by train or a short flight that I haven&rsquo;t attended
yet: Monaco, Sochi, Abu Dhabi, Bahrain, Spain, and Austria.</p>

<h3>Access to Beer</h3>

<p>This leads to another life goal. To break off from technology and have a business in the beer domain.
In my Evernote journal I had a grade on each company/location on beer alignment. Of course both locations are
exceptional locations for a beer fan. San Francisco had a bit of a higher score because I know people there that do home
brewing. I&rsquo;m sure I can find a home brew community in Berlin.</p>

<h3>Music/Audio Domain</h3>

<p>Working in the music/audio domain! At CBC it was awesome being surrounded by music nerds. Sorry, but I&rsquo;ll choose
music nerds over tech nerds. Especially as my interest in the tech world is diminishing.</p>

<h3>More Travel</h3>

<p>So many travel opportunities being in central Europe. I hope to visit my relatives in Ukraine and friends in
Switzerland, England, Turkey, Czech Republic, Germany, and Hungary. With 5 weeks of holidays I&rsquo;ll be exploring and
visiting as much as possible.</p>

<p>Also, a part of me doesn&rsquo;t want to live in the USA. Cloud Foundry is also in London, but I would
want to be at the hub of the product development which is primarily in San Francisco. There would have been an option to
move to London after a year though, but my decision making was based more on the immediate change.</p>

<h2>Show Me the Money</h2>

<p>At first I was really concerned about how much less SoundCloud offered compared to Cloud Foundry. I took a look at a
<a href="http://www.numbeo.com/cost-of-living/compare_cities.jsp?country1=United+States&amp;country2=Germany&amp;city1=San+Francisco%2C+CA&amp;city2=Berlin">cost of living</a> website and calculated that to get the equivalent of an SF salary in Berlin, it would
have to be 56.3% percent (eg: making $56,300 in Berlin is equivalent to $100,000 in SF). Comparing the salary I was
offered it&rsquo;s at 55.7%. So it&rsquo;s a little bit lower, but not as crazy low as I thought.</p>

<p>It did take me on a tangent and wonder why we tend to care so much about salaries (I really wish salaries were public, I
don&rsquo;t keep mine much of a secret). My hypothesis is that your salary is a concrete tangible thing, whereas how much you
spend is harder to determine. If you&rsquo;re in Berlin making $56,300 and spend $50,000, then you&rsquo;ve save $6,300. If you make
$100,000 in SF and spend $95,000, you&rsquo;ve actually saved less. Unfortunately figuring out the amount you spend is left to
discipline around budgets.</p>

<h3>What I Don&rsquo;t Like</h3>

<p>This means I&rsquo;m joining a company that is becoming more tied to the big labels and entering the advertising space. I&rsquo;m
hoping to learn more about how this system works so that I can learn to be a more educated critic.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>I just reread <a href="/leaving-a-dream-job-and-going-on-an-adventure/">my post</a> from the beginning of this career break. This post and that one seem to align really
well and it gives me comfort in my decision. I really love the cadence my life has had for almost the last 20 years.
Keep an eye here for my next steps 5 years from now. Wish me luck!</p>

<h5>Looking for work? Both companies are still hiring:</h5>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://soundcloud.com/jobs">http://soundcloud.com/jobs</a></li>
<li><a href="http://cloudfoundry.com/jobs">http://cloudfoundry.com/jobs</a></li>
</ul>


<p><em>This post took 9 pomodoros to complete</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
