<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Links | More Muc Than You Can Handle]]></title>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/blog/categories/links/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scottmuc.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-11T08:52:55+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://scottmuc.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Muc]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scottmuc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - Podcasts]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-podcasts/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-16T07:29:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-podcasts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/podcast.jpg" width="300">
It&rsquo;s quite surprising that I haven&rsquo;t really brought up the topic of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Podcast">podcasts</a> on my blog considering that
I&rsquo;ve been consuming them for almost 10 years! My methods and taste have changed a lot over the years. I want a place
to point people when asked about what podcasts I listen to, and with a little more context than just a pure list.</p>

<h2>Software / Tools</h2>

<p>A podcast is such a simple concept (from the technical side) that it allows for a lot of tools and applications to be
created around the idea. Nowadays I pretty much use a single application on my phone. I&rsquo;m generally only concerned with
the mobile experience since I try to listen to podcasts when I&rsquo;m on the move and when I&rsquo;m not focusing on work. Ask me
to listen to a podcast while programming and you&rsquo;ll discover that I won&rsquo;t be able to recall anything from the podcast
(or that I don&rsquo;t do any programming). The application I use is <a href="http://www.shiftyjelly.com/android/pocketcasts">PocketCasts</a>. The homepage is full of
hyperbole and non-truthes (eg: &hellip; deliver the updates instantly&hellip;), but it&rsquo;s an alright application and fits my needs for
now. Most importantly, it allows me to export my subscribed shows as an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opml">OPML file</a> which I&rsquo;ve made
<a href="/podcasts_opml.xml">available to you</a>.</p>

<h2>The List</h2>

<p>Podcasts are a great way to tap into interests of all different types. You&rsquo;ll notice that only a few are related to my
professional life. Listening to podcasts is a wonderful activity and I do get a lot out of them, there becomes a point
where you&rsquo;ve found too much good content and there isn&rsquo;t enough time to listen to them all.</p>

<h2>Economics</h2>

<h3><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/">EconTalk</a><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/rss.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/econtalk.jpg" width="200">
I begun listening to this show at the beginning of my <a href="/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a>. The
host, <a href="http://russroberts.info/">Russ Roberts</a>, does a great job of letting the guests speak without pushing his views too often.
It&rsquo;s honestly changed how I think about problems in the world and how to best approach them. Economics is becoming a
tool that I use to help me understand how things are, and how to possibly alter them. The talks are well balanced and
help me see the other side of issues that I normally don&rsquo;t think of. When a new episode appears I look forward to
listening to it regardless of the topic!</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/charles_marohn.html">Charles Marohn on Strong Towns, Urban Development, and the Future of American Cities</a> &ndash; Conversations
around city design always fascinates me. There&rsquo;s a spectrum of that&rsquo;s a lot harder to accomplish than most people
realize. Living in an overly-designed city can be soul crushing, and a zero designed city can be too stressful.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/05/yuval_levin_on.html">Yuval Levin on Burke, Paine, and the Great Debate</a> &ndash; The difference between the right and left had been
something I hadn&rsquo;t thought deeply about. This conversation made me realize I&rsquo;m more right thinking than I thought. It
also made me understand that neither are &ldquo;bad&rdquo;.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2014/09/martha_nussbaum.html">Martha Nussbaum on Creating Capabilities and GDP</a> &ndash; There are other conversations around GDP, but this one
really stood out to me. I think Martha does an exceptional job of explaining how GDP is not a sufficient metric and
that we still have a long way to go to get people to the top of Maslow&rsquo;s Hierarchy.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/freakonomics-radio/">Freakonomics Radio</a><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/freakonomicsradio"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/freakonomics.jpg" width="200">
Sometimes hit or miss. Strives to be entertaining more than educational
sometimes, but overall the content is quite good. I identify a bit with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steven_Levitt">Steve Levitt</a> as he&rsquo;s more of an
intrespective quiet person.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/09/04/regulate-this-a-new-freakonomics-radio-podcast/">Regulate This!</a> &ndash; As a user of services like Uber and Airbnb, it&rsquo;s interesting to hear the issues that
these services raise. I find myself leaning towards the side of less regulation, but I still can&rsquo;t figure out where
the balance is. The term &ldquo;sharing economy&rdquo; also drives me nuts, because sharing implies no charge to me. These are
just peer-to-peer market places enabled by technology.</li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/09/25/fitness-apartheid-a-new-freakonomics-radio-podcast/">Fitness Apartheid</a> &ndash; An excellent example of how too little thought around a problem can lead to
bad consequences. It brings the concerns of both sides together and makes the listener understand that nothing is ever
as simple as you think it ought to be.</li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/05/29/the-upside-of-quitting-a-freakonomics-radio-rebroadcast/">The Upside of Quitting</a> &ndash; Very fitting for my <a href="/blog/categories/career-break/">career break</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://freakonomics.com/2014/06/05/failure-is-your-friend-a-new-freakonomics-radio-podcast/">Failure is your Friend</a> &ndash; A follow up to the previous episode.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/">Planet Money</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510289"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/planetmoney.png" width="200">
Short and to the point episodes that focus on very specific topics or issues. I
like this show because the pieces are bite-sized and frequently released. I find myself listening to this show when I
have to wait 15 minutes before something.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2014/09/26/351515481/episode-571-why-raising-money-for-ebola-is-hard">Why Raising Money for Ebola is Hard</a> &ndash; Excellent insights around why we give, and the pychology of charity.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2014/08/22/342232976/episode-562-a-mall-divided">A Mall Divided</a> &ndash; A peak into how economic policy can distrupt small businesses.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2014/07/11/330680385/episode-552-blockbusters-bombs-and-the-price-of-a-ticket">Blockbusters, Bombs, and the Price of a Ticket</a> &ndash; I had never put much thought into the cost of a movie
ticket, this episode explains all the details of why tickets cost the same regardless if it&rsquo;s sold-out or empty.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://mercatus.org/conversations-with-tyler">Conversations with Tyler</a><a href="http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:146429914/sounds.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/cwt.jpg" width="200">
A new one that I just got into. It&rsquo;s a bit more candid than EconTalk and more accessible. The guests are of the same
caliber and sometimes the Q&amp;A at the end can add interesting tidbits that may not neccessarily come up during an
interview.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/conversations-with-tyler/jeffrey-sachs-on-the-future-of-economic-development-2650c27b2776#.utox5d73q">Jeffrey Sachs</a> &ndash; I&rsquo;ve only listened to a few and they are all excellent but this one stands out because I
found Jeffrey Sachs inspires me a little bit. Instead of shrugging his shoulders and pointing out how all the terrible
things in the world can be explained by value functions and rational behaviour, he uses that knowledge to learn how to
tweak these systems. He&rsquo;s an interesting balance of idealist and a realist and I find that refreshing compared to
other economic speakers I&rsquo;ve listened to.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02nrss1">BBC More or Less</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02nrss1/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/bbc-mol.jpg" width="200">
This show takes a deeper look around statistics. It does the deeper critical view so you don&rsquo;t have to. Listening to
this makes me trust reports even less. Spin is such a problem and how information is presented requires a lot of effort
to reveal a non-biased presentation.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p03k2stg">When £10,000 Isn&rsquo;t a Good Incentive</a> &ndash; As a snooker fan I thought this was an interesting story of a
straightforward incentive behaviour.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p03lj18n">Fact Checking The Big Short</a> &ndash; I really enjoyed the movie <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1596363/">The Big Short</a> and the
timing of this episode was really good as I had just watched it.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006sz6t">BBC The Bottom Line</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006sz6t/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/bbc-bottom-line.jpg" width="200">
Provides a focus on what makes a business successful. It&rsquo;s a domain that I don&rsquo;t really have a clue. I find myself
wanting to be closer to the business in the work I do day to day so this has been good at introducing me to what
executives think about.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b070hns6">Data Privacy</a> &ndash; As someone on the sidelines watching the privacy debates from a technologist, it&rsquo;s
important to learn how these topics are perceived from a business owner level.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b0745q4l">Life After a Blockbuster</a> &ndash; The story about Angry Birds was fascinating. It reveals how often
the success we put on a pedestal comes from consistent tenanicity.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://podcast.ft.com/s/ft-alphachat/">FT Alphachat</a><a href="http://rss.acast.com/ft-alphachat"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/ft-alphachat.png" width="200">
Currently just trying this one out. Don&rsquo;t really have much to say about it at this point. It&rsquo;s more conversational than
some of the other business/economic podcasts.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/slate_money.html">Slate Money</a><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/SlateMoney"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/slate-money.png" width="200">
Yet another podcast that talks about world events and how they affect the economy. Each episode covers 2-4 topics. This
is starting become one of my required listening podcasts to stay informed about current events. The hosts discuss the
economics in a way that&rsquo;s targetted for people who don&rsquo;t know all the lingo.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/slate_money/2016/08/slate_money_takes_on_epipen_passive_investing_and_hedge_funds.html">The Worse than Marxism Edition</a> &ndash; As someone interested (and doing) passive investing, I wanted to
hear what they had to say about it.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/slate_money/2016/08/slate_money_on_three_of_today_s_top_online_products.html">The Product Edition</a> &ndash; Anything with Paul Ford is great to listen to. He has a nice down-to-earth
style of describing what Product Development is all about.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/slate_money/2016/06/slate_money_on_microsoft_s_acquisition_of_linkedin.html">The I&rsquo;d Like to Add You to my Professional Network Edition</a> &ndash; Another Paul Ford episode and it was
interesting to hear the conversation about the reasoning as to why such a massive purchase could happen.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hard-pass/id1090135741?mt=2">Hard Pass</a><a href="http://rss.acast.com/hardpass"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/hardpass.jpg" width="200">
I learned about Linette Lopez from the Slate Money podcast and really liked her style. She&rsquo;s punchy
and tells it like it is. Hard Pass is a good low-dose entertaining podcast about the business and
econmics news of the day. The episodes are so short that it&rsquo;s easy to digest any time.</p>

<hr />

<h3>Politics and World News</h3>

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006r4vz">BBC Analysis</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006r4vz/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/bbc-analysis.jpg" width="200">
For once it&rsquo;s nice to listen to something that isn&rsquo;t about US politics. I started listening to economic podcasts to
understand more of the world around me. Now it&rsquo;s pointing me in the direction of politics. This show is interesting to
hear about how ideas and policies gets introduced to society. They tackle some difficult issues as well which makes it a
bit heavier than some of the other lighter podcasts I have listed here.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b072j3g6">The End of Free</a> &ndash; I&rsquo;ve been incorporating ad blocking daily for over a decade. It was fascinating to
hear how it&rsquo;s hit a point where this practice is getting attention. Brands just want to engage with you! Why are we
being so mean to them!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p03qvxgb">Free Speech</a> &ndash; This is the first for a 4 part series. It asks the questions around the trade offs of
free speech. I find myself conflicted and tripping over my own thoughts on what should be allowed. Learning the types
of nullifiers to free speech I found interesting too.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://podcast.ft.com/s/world-weekly-with-gideon-rachman/">FT World Weekly</a><a href="http://rss.acast.com/ft-world-weekly"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/ft-worldweekly.png" width="200">
Another good source for global news how it influences the world markets. Can&rsquo;t really say I have any favourites, but I
do like how it&rsquo;s not just US news.</p>

<hr />

<h3>Culture and Curiosities</h3>

<h3><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/">99% Invisible</a><a href="http://feeds.99percentinvisible.org/99percentinvisible"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/99pi.png" width="200">
Now one of my favourites. You never know what to expect with this show because the
enigmatic host, <a href="https://twitter.com/romanmars">Roman Mars</a>, always finds something interesting that you likely have no idea about.
Roman started a group called <a href="http://www.radiotopia.fm/">Radiotopia</a> which is a collective of like minded artists to create
exceptional podcasts.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites (all of them):</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/thomassons/">Thomassons</a> &ndash; I dare you to listen to this episode and not look for Thomassons wherever you go!</li>
<li><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/the-straight-line-is-a-godless-line/">The Straight Line is a Godless Line</a> &ndash; Given that I was in Vienna and saw the Hundertwasserhaus, it
was very interesting to hear more about the architect. I love the fact that people like him exist, though I may not
want to completely follow his lead.</li>
<li><a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/clean-trains/">Clean Trains</a> &ndash; There are so many applications to the lesson of this episode. Frequent and consistent
feedback is necessary to promote any change.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.radiolab.org/">RadioLab</a><a href="http://feeds.wnyc.org/radiolab"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/radiolab.png" width="200">
One of the pioneers in story-telling podcasts. I&rsquo;ve been away from it for a while and have re-subscribed as I&rsquo;ve been
missing the excellent stories.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.radiolab.org/story/91500-emergence/">Emergence</a> &ndash; This episode is from 2007 and it still comes up as one
of the more influencial podcast episodes I&rsquo;ve listened to. I&rsquo;m a control freak and find the concept of emergence hard
to understand. A top-down controller is easier for me to understand. This episode reminds me to rethink how things
ought to be and be more flexible.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://toe.prx.org/">Theory of Everything</a><a href="http://feeds.prx.org/toe"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/toe.jpg" width="200">
A member of the <a href="http://www.radiotopia.fm/">Radiotopia</a> collective. Just started getting into this podcast recently.
I&rsquo;m already becoming a huge fan!</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://toe.prx.org/2014/11/paying-for-it-the-dislike-club-part-ii/">Paying For It</a> &ndash; This is part of a series called
&ldquo;Dislike Club&rdquo; which is focusing on the Internet. This episode calls to attention the problems happening with todays
monetization of the web through advertising. It sums up so many of the thoughts I&rsquo;ve had about technology recently.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/">Stuff You Should Know</a><a href="http://www.howstuffworks.com/podcasts/stuff-you-should-know.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/sysk.jpg" width="200">
An exceptional podcast hosted by two charismatic people. Normally I find tangents in podcasts to be distracting, but for
some reason these two often make it worthwhile. They cover a myriad of topics and they make the most mundane seem
fascinating. There are many excellent episodes but the following ones really stood out for me.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The two part series (<a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/podcasts/the-dark-origins-of-fairy-tales.htm">episode 1</a> <a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/podcasts/how-grimms-fairy-tales-work.htm">episode 2</a>) is a wonderful explanation of the origins of fairy tales
and how dark the originally were. The Juniper Tree one is quite horrifying.</li>
<li>Another two part series one <a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/podcasts/josh-and-chuck-make-it-through-male-puberty.htm">male puberty</a> and <a href="http://www.stuffyoushouldknow.com/podcasts/chuck-and-josh-make-it-through-female-puberty.htm">female puberty</a> discusses the awkward
phase of life that we all had with great clarity.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/podcasts/510308/hidden-brain">Hidden Brain</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510308"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/npr-hiddenbrain.jpg" width="200">
A topic that I&rsquo;ve been loving lately is learning how our brains work. Not at the micro level, but at the macro level.
What makes us make all the silly decisions that we make. How do we subtly use this knowledge to manipulate people for
good and bad. Whenever you find yourself asking the question &ldquo;why would anyone behave this way?&rdquo;, listen to this show
and it&rsquo;ll shed some light on us crazy humans.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/podcasts/510308/hidden-brain">Grit</a> &ndash; I found myself nodding at many of the points in this episode. It highlights how expertise requires
spending a large portion of your time performing deliberate practice. It also looks at why people love people that
show mastery in something but disregard the massive dedication these people spent on becoming a master.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/podcasts/510308/hidden-brain">AirBnB While Black</a> &ndash; As a western white male, the easiness of my life is often not very obvious,
that is until you hear the stories of others. I have a feeling that the Internet is exposing our unconscious biases
more frequently while at the same time providing people with techniques to overcome these hurdles.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b036tbly">The Human Zoo</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b036tbly/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/humanzoo.jpg" width="200">
Over time I have really started enjoying the topic of human behaviour and what makes us who we are.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b07j4ppt">Trust me&hellip; I&rsquo;m an expert</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b060zr3d">Perfect people</a></li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b00nrtd2">History of the World in 100 Objects</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b00nrtd2/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/history-of-world.jpg" width="200">
An excellent history of the world in small bite sized chunks. The format gives you a really good perspective of how
long civilization takes to change. I can only imagine how much time it took to determine which objects to use
from the last century. While listening to this I realized how much bias I have around change being technical.</p>

<hr />

<h2>Music</h2>

<h3><a href="http://music.cbc.ca/radio3/">CBC Radio 3</a><a href="http://www.cbcradio3.com/podcast/"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/cbcradio3.jpg" width="200">
It&rsquo;s likely that I&rsquo;m a bit biased, but this is where I discover new music. I worked
there from 2005-2009 during the rise of the podcast. I can attest to the quality of the curation of the content coming
from the folks at Radio 3. The superfeed subscribes you to all the different podcasts published by Radio 3, though I
don&rsquo;t think there are as many shows as there used to be.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://songexploder.net/">Song Exploder</a><a href="http://songexploder.libsyn.com/rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/songexploder.png" width="200">
This show satifies my curiosity about how a song gets made. It also makes me
appreciate songs that I wouldn&rsquo;t have given a second listen. By listening to this show, you can disover new artists, and
you&rsquo;ll learn how to listen to music and grow appreciation for the more subtle elements of song composition.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/podcasts/510019/all-songs-considered">All Songs Considered</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/rss/podcast.php?id=510019"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/npr-asc.jpg" width="200">
A podcast I tend to listen to when I going to sleep. I don&rsquo;t quite keep up with music as much as I should, but I find
listening to this keeps me somewhat informed of what&rsquo;s going on.</p>

<hr />

<h2>Tech / Programming</h2>

<p>As you can see, I don&rsquo;t really listen to any tech/programming podcasts anymore.</p>

<h2>Language</h2>

<h3><a href="http://www.theallusionist.org/">The Allusionist</a><a href="http://feeds.theallusionist.org/Allusionist"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/allusionist.png" width="200">
I could list to Helen Zaltzman speak all day. Her style and sense of humour is wonderful and I find that I learn a lot
about the origins of the words in my native language.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.theallusionist.org/allusionist/please">Please</a> &ndash; Listen to this episode and think again if someone from another culture is being rude.
Also, think about how other cultures may have perceived you as being rude by trying to be overly polite!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theallusionist.org/allusionist/wltm-i">WLTM</a> &ndash; The language surrounding dating from three hundred years ago.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/lexicon_valley.html">Lexicon Valley</a><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/SlateLexiconValley"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/lexvalley.jpg" width="200">
Each episode starts with a clue as to what the topic is going to be, and the hosts try to figure it out. They often have
great dialogues about the words and are well researched in trying to pinpoint the origin of term. They have a good sense
of humour too.</p>

<p><strong>Favourties:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/lexicon_valley/2015/06/lexicon_valley_the_pollyanna_hypothesis_all_languages_have_a_positivity.html">Language Positivity Bias</a> &ndash; This episode made me laugh out loud while grocery shopping. They
dive into the lyrics of Slayer and it&rsquo;s really a priceless moment.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/lexicon_valley/2015/11/pussy_the_etymology_and_history_of_a_cat_a_coward_and_female_genitalia.html">A Cat, a Coward, and Female Genitalia</a> &ndash; Where did the word pussy come from?</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>There are a lot of podcasts here and I&rsquo;m constantly re-evaluating which ones should remain. Finding the balance of time
and value is hard to figure out. Currently I&rsquo;m unemployed making it a lot easier to consume this much content. I also
listen to tech specific podcasts when I&rsquo;m spending some time in that technology. A good example of that would be the
<a href="http://rubyrogues.com/">ruby rogues</a> podcast. Or, I may take a look at <a href="http://hanselminutes.com/">HanselMinutes</a> to see if something
interesting has come up.</p>

<p>To subscribe to all the same podcasts that I do, import this <a href="/podcasts_opml.xml">OPML</a> file into your favourite podcast
listening software.</p>

<h2>Unsubcribed</h2>

<p>After a while I find myself changing my podcast listening tastes. Rather than delete them from this post, I&rsquo;ll list
them here and provide some context as to why I don&rsquo;t listen to them anymore.</p>

<h3><a href="http://a16z.com/tag/podcast/">a16z</a><a href="http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:62921190/sounds.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/a16z.jpg" width="200">
Getting into the startup world is not something I&rsquo;m terribly interested in, but I am critical
about the tech community, especially startups. This show helps me better understand the world of startups so I can
better understand the mechanics of startups. Over time this podcast has become to irritate me. The Valley speak gets to
you after a while (count how many questions are answered with an excited &ldquo;Absolutely!&rdquo;). I stopped listen to this
because I realized that I simply did not care about the startup world. Listening to this podcast started to depress me.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://a16z.com/2014/09/05/a16z-podcast-everything-you-need-to-know-about-amazon/">Everything You Need to Know About Amazon</a> &ndash; Explanation of how Amazon re-invests all of its profits to avoid
opportunity costs is a novel concept. Not sure why investors are ok with it. Makes me more curious about what Amazon
will be doing 20-30 years from now.</li>
<li><a href="http://a16z.com/2014/09/30/a16z-podcast-creating-new-silicon-valleys/">Creating New Silicon Valleys</a> &ndash; When something becomes trendy, people always want to figure out how
to replicate it. This episode explains how cultures are emergent, not created. Common sense it would seem, but that
doesn&rsquo;t seem to really stop people. I feel the same around the topic of <a href="/valuable-links-devops/">DevOps</a>.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://hearstartup.com/">StartUp</a><a href="http://feeds.hearstartup.com/hearstartup"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/startup.png" width="200">
A podcast about a podcast startup. It mixes so many of my favourite things into one show.
Fantastic storytelling about a medium I&rsquo;m passionate about and a domain that I want to learn more of. What connects
me to the show is that <a href="https://twitter.com/abexlumberg">Alex Blumberg</a> just wants to work on something he&rsquo;s passionate about, but has to wade through all
sorts of concerns completely separate from what he really wants to do, because that&rsquo;s business. Though this podcast
didn&rsquo;t depress me like the a16z podcast did, I found the material getting pretty old. It was starting to repeat many of
the lessons from the <a href="http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2008/04/podcast-1/">StackOverflow Podcast</a> (from 2008). Also, more North American podcast content isn&rsquo;t
something I really want more of.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://hearstartup.com/episodes/gbm3498ruf7abd4owt4xs20uck1cvn">Startups are Risky Business</a> &ndash; This gave me insight around the different VC models. I used to think
that they are all looking for the 100x payoff. I need to learn more about the more modest investments out there.
Sometimes you can invest in something simply because you want it to exist.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://podcasts.thoughtbot.com/giantrobots">Giant Robots Smashing into Other Giant Robots</a><a href="http://podcasts.thoughtbot.com/giantrobots.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/giantrobots.jpg" width="200">
Not quite a technical podcast, but it shares stories from the software development world. I became a fan of
<a href="https://twitter.com/r00k">Ben Orenstein</a> when I saw him do a play-by-play screencast. He strikes me as someone I would enjoy
working with. I&rsquo;m weaning myself off of tech podcasts so this had to be removed.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://theshipshow.com/">The Ship Show</a><a href="http://theshipshow.com/podcast.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/shipshow.jpg" width="200">
Co-started by an old on-line friend of mine, <a href="https://twitter.com/buildscientist">Youssuf Elkalay</a>.
I like the conversational style of this show as a way to keep me in the loop in the world of <a href="/valuable-links-devops/">DevOps</a>.
Removed because I&rsquo;m trying to stay away from technical podcasts.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/">HealthyHacker</a><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/feed.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/healthyhacker.png" width="200">
This one is fairly new and I&rsquo;ve already become a fan. <a href="https://twitter.com/chrishunt">Chris Hunt</a>
delivers his show in a charming style. He discusses being healthy, and what&rsquo;s interesting in the software world. All to
the tune of a catchy theme song. Now I just need to get into the habit of doing the workout of the week. Removed for now
because of its technical base.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/2014/08/04/pineapple-in-your-pocket/">Pineapple in Your Pocket</a> &ndash; I try and use this memorization technique as frequently as possible!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.healthyhacker.com/2014/09/29/codecation/">Codecation</a> &ndash; The story of Chris and Ben meeting up for a codecation was inspiring. I would like to do
something similar at some point.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.npr.org/programs/ted-radio-hour/">TED Radio Hour</a><a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510298"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/ted-radio-hour.jpg" width="200">
Episodes are themed around TED talks of similar topics. It blends interviews with the speakers along with their talks.
I find this more rich than the talk on its own.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/2013/03/28/175609678/the-violence-within-us?showDate=2014-08-08">The Violence Within Us</a> &ndash; Sort of a scary episode, but it helps me understand that life is always in a
delicate balance. We&rsquo;ll never live in a world where everyone is good. I tend to be utopian in my thinking and this
provides a good dose of reality.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/programs/ted-radio-hour/321797073/what-is-original?showDate=2014-06-27">What is Original</a> &ndash; The thought of being unique and interesting is something everyone craves, but in the
end most of things are derivitive. This episode is good to pair with the 99% Invisible episode:
<a href="http://99percentinvisible.org/episode/duplitecture/">Duplitecture</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.npr.org/2013/10/06/229879937/identities?showDate=2014-02-21">Identities</a> &ndash; The next few generations of humans are going to have a much different concept about their
identity. We are more global and cross-cultural than ever before.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/tapestry/index.html">Tapestry</a><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/includes/tapestry.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/tapestry.jpg" width="200">
Getting into the spiritual side a bit. This show talks about culture and religion with an
open mind. The show reminds me to appreciate the differences between all of us on this rock. I used to listen to this
show all the time when I lived in Canada. I just recently subscribed to the podcast.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/tapestry/episode/2014/10/24/being-alone-views-from-a-mormon-feminist-poet-nikki-giovanni/">Being Alone</a> &ndash; The 2nd portion with <strong>Nikki Giovanni</strong> is so delightful. It&rsquo;s a candid conversation that
has so many quotable verses. I was walking the streets of Bangalore while listening to it and I had a huge smile on my
face the whole time.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/whitecoat/">White Coat Black Art</a><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/includes/whitecoat.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/whitecoat.jpg" width="200">
The health care system is usually a bit of a black box and this show provides some visibility into how things work. Like
tapestry, this was a show I used to listen to all the time when I lived in Canada. Recently subscribed to feel that
connection back to where I came from.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/radio/whitecoat/slow-code-1.2827708">Slow Code</a> &ndash; A conversation about health care professionals
minimaly applying &ldquo;Code Blue&rdquo; protocols when they know the patient won&rsquo;t survive or will survive at a considerable
cost. This episode made me remember that my job is pretty much pointless and to think about the people that do real
honest work out there.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/spark/index.html">Spark</a><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/podcasting/includes/spark.xml"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/spark.jpg" width="200">
A Canadian look into the technical world. Always nice to hear a Canadian perspective of what&rsquo;s going on. Hopefully
because it&rsquo;s created by the CBC, there isn&rsquo;t any product/partner agenda.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02nrwfk">BBC Peter Day&rsquo;s World of Business</a><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02nrwfk/episodes/downloads.rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/bbc-pdwob.jpg" width="200">
A show that does a good job of covering both sides around global trends or analysing specific environments. I find this
show a bit deeper than something like Freakanomics or Planet Money.</p>

<p><strong>Favourites:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p03qg5rq">Tax Transparency &ndash; Norway&rsquo;s Model</a> &ndash; Personally, I&rsquo;ve become fascinated with transparent systems. I like
the idea of everyone knowing what each other makes because it provides the knowledge required to make better
decisions. This episode provides a look into why this was imposed in Norway&rsquo;s past and some of the complexities that
have resulted in a more modern era.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.futilitycloset.com/category/podcast/">Futility Closet</a><a href="http://feedpress.me/futilitycloset"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/futilitycloset.png" width="200">
A show about curious events. They did a neat thing where they perform a lateral thinking puzzle with each episode. It
reminds me that sometimes truth is stranger than fiction and to always be curious about what is laid out in front of
you. I&rsquo;ve only listened to a few episodes so I don&rsquo;t have any favourites to list at the moment in time.</p>

<hr />

<h3><a href="http://www.hellointernet.fm/">Hello Internet</a><a href="http://www.hellointernet.fm/podcast?format=rss"><img src="http://scottmuc.com/images/feed-icon-28x28.png" class="podcast-image" /></a></h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/podcasts/hellointernet.png" width="200">
Most of the time I dislike drawn out conversational style podcasts but this one I enjoy listening to while doing tasks
(and I don&rsquo;t mind not absorbing the contents of the episode). The hosts are: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CGP_Grey">CGP Grey</a>, who entertains me with
his affinity for comfort and observing the world from a far. Often I find myself aligned with his views and enjoy his
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC2C_jShtL725hvbm1arSV9w">Youtube Channel</a> immensely. The other host is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brady_Haran">Brady Haran</a> who is energetic and curious. I
enjoy is enthusiasm around travel. I would love to have beer with these two which I know Grey would despise the idea and
Brady would love it. Their contrasting personalities and mutual respect for each other is why I&rsquo;ll stick with this
podcast even though the episodes are too long by my listening standards.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - Devops]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T02:17:52+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-devops</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Valuable Links for Devops</h2>

<p>TL;DR &ndash; Watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3KpPBnEtRj4">this</a> video and read <a href="https://sethvargo.com/the-ten-myths-of-devops/">the 10 myths of DevOps</a> (which also links to
what I now find is the best <a href="https://vimeo.com/101735253">video</a> on devops).</p>

<p>Since I first learned the term devops 4 years ago I&rsquo;ve gone through many leaps in understanding. I really wish I saw
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o7-IuYS0iSE">this video (history of devops)</a> before I got involved. As a software developer, I find delivering
frequently highly motivating. Devops is a set of principles and practices that aim to ensure delivery goes as smooth
as possible. I found this post, <a href="http://blog.devopsguys.com/2014/02/25/a-scientific-basis-for-devops-success/">A Scientific Basis For Devops Success</a>, to be a great introduction
to why devops is important.</p>

<h2>People</h2>

<p>This list isn&rsquo;t comprehensive, but you can&rsquo;t go wrong by reading what these people have to say:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://jedi.be/">Patrick Debois</a> &ndash; coined the term devops</li>
<li><a href="http://www.noahsussman.com/">Noah Sussman</a> &ndash; provides excellent insights around QA</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kitchensoap.com/">John Allspaw</a> &ndash; has many excellent posts on the culture of devops</li>
<li><a href="http://itrevolution.com/">Gene Kim</a> &ndash; co-author of The Phoenix Project</li>
<li><a href="http://continuousdelivery.com/">Jez Humble</a> &ndash; co-author of Continuous Delivery</li>
</ul>


<h2>Devops is not a Role</h2>

<p>It took me a while to realize that devops is not a role played on a team and that it&rsquo;s got more in commong with Agile in
the fact that it&rsquo;s a collection of principles rather than straight up proceesses.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.getchef.com/blog/2010/07/16/what-devops-means-to-me/">CAMS</a> &ndash; <a href="https://twitter.com/botchagalupe/">John Willis</a>&lsquo; posts a list of principles</li>
<li><a href="http://blog.lusis.org/blog/2013/06/04/devops-the-title-match/">Lusis' rant</a> &ndash; an excellent rant about the absurditity of devops being a role</li>
</ul>


<h2>Must Watch Videos</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3KpPBnEtRj4">The Devops Transformation</a> &ndash; <a href="https://twitter.com/benr/">Ben Rockwood</a> does a most
enlightening talk on the subject</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h5E--QSBVBY">Devops Demystified</a> &ndash; Another <strong>Ben Rockwood</strong> talk that is awesome</li>
</ul>


<h2>Events</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/">DevOpsDays</a></li>
<li><a href="http://devopssummit.com/">DevOps Summit</a></li>
<li><a href="http://web.experiencedevops.org/">Experience DevOps</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Mailing Lists</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://code.google.com/p/devops-toolchain/">Devops Toolchain</a></li>
<li><a href="http://devopsweekly.com/">Devops Weekly</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Tools</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.devopsbookmarks.com">Devops Bookmarks</a> &ndash; This is the ultimate one stop shop for all tools</li>
<li><a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/vagrant-packer-consul-serf">Vagrant, Packer, Consul, Serf</a> &ndash; Mitchell Hashimoto discusses some core concepts around devops tooling and
provides examples</li>
</ul>


<h2>Links (need sorting and or context)</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/garethbowles/managing-jenkins-with-jenkins-uc2013">http://www.slideshare.net/garethbowles/managing-jenkins-with-jenkins-uc2013</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/PeterLeschev/puppet-camp-melbourne-nov-2014-a-build-engineering-teams-journey-of-infrastructure-as-code">http://www.slideshare.net/PeterLeschev/puppet-camp-melbourne-nov-2014-a-build-engineering-teams-journey-of-infrastructure-as-code</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.gartner.com/technology/reprints.do?ct=140925&amp;id=1-22AAXZR&amp;st=sb">http://www.gartner.com/technology/reprints.do?ct=140925&amp;id=1-22AAXZR&amp;st=sb</a></li>
<li><a href="http://theagileadmin.com/2014/09/30/scrum-for-operations-just-add-devops/">http://theagileadmin.com/2014/09/30/scrum-for-operations-just-add-devops/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://sysadmincasts.com/">http://sysadmincasts.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vimeo.com/77207216">http://vimeo.com/77207216</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.binpress.com/blog/2014/09/09/binpress-podcast-episode-10-mitchell-hashimoto-hashicorp/">http://www.binpress.com/blog/2014/09/09/binpress-podcast-episode-10-mitchell-hashimoto-hashicorp/</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valuable Links - Vim]]></title>
    <link href="http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-vim/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-03T19:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://scottmuc.com/valuable-links-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>First Off &ndash; Introducing Valuable Links</h2>

<p>Today I&rsquo;ve decided to start something new. I tend to send my friends and colleagues
links about all sorts of things. Usually when they are pertinent to a problem they are
having, or to supplement a conversation I&rsquo;ve had with them. My usual process to reproduce
these links ends up being a search in: <a href="https://twitter.com/scottmuc/" title="My Twitter Feed">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://getpocket.com/users/scottmuc" title="My Pocket Feed">Pocket</a>, History, and my Bookmarks.</p>

<p>Also, when I share my links I tend to write a few sentences about them. It adds a personal
touch and a bit of context, so that&rsquo;s why I&rsquo;m exploring this channel for displaying them.
As opposed to using a bookmarking website.</p>

<h2>Valuable Links for Vim</h2>

<p>I would say I&rsquo;m a moderate <a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a> user. I have a simple <code>.vimrc</code> with few plugins. Learning
to be competent at <code>vim</code> has made my computing experience so much better. Here are a few
websites that have helped me out:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.danielmiessler.com/study/vim/" title="Daniel Miessler's Vim Primer">Vim Primer</a> &ndash; I can&rsquo;t think of a more thorough primer. Even after knowing
vim for a while I learned a lot from this article. Not only that, it helped reinforce
the things I knew already to better explain them.</li>
<li><a href="http://statico.github.io/vim.html" title="Vim After 11 Years">Vim After 11 Years</a> &ndash; A good story on someone&rsquo;s journey learning
vim for the last 11 years.</li>
<li><a href="http://vimgolf.com/" title="Vim Golf">Vim Golf</a> &ndash; Try and do the editing exercises in the minimum number of keystrokes.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/" title="Destroy All Software">Destroy All Software</a> &ndash; Watching <a href="https://twitter.com/garybernhardt" title="Gary's Twitter Feed">Gary Bernhardt</a> is a great
way to learn vim. His excellent screencasts have 3 episodes focused on Vim:
<a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts/catalog/file-navigation-in-vim" title="File Navigation in Vim">File Navigation in Vim</a>, <a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts/catalog/some-vim-tips" title="Some Vim Tips">Some Vim Tips</a>, and
<a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts/catalog/the-vimrc" title="The vimrc">The vimrc</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h3>My Own Tips</h3>

<ul>
<li>Disable the arrow keys. They just encourage bad habits. For me, I had to use the
<code>h</code>, <code>j</code>, <code>l</code>, and <code>l</code> out of necessity. I travel a lot, and writing code on an
airplane is difficult if you have to move your hand to the arrow keys. The key is
not to do this too early otherwise you&rsquo;ll be frustrated like <a href="http://yehudakatz.com/2010/07/29/everyone-who-tried-to-convince-me-to-use-vim-was-wrong/">Yehuda Katz</a>.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t use a premade vim configuration. Things like <a href="https://github.com/carlhuda/janus" title="Janus">Janus</a> make it easy
for vim to behave more like <a href="http://macromates.com/" title="TextMate">TextMate</a> or <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/" title="Sublime Editor">Sublime</a> (both great
editors), but if that&rsquo;s what you want, why not just use them? Instead, strive to
keep your <code>.vimrc</code> your own and rely on plugins to get the benefits of the excellent
work that&rsquo;s been done by other people. <a href="http://blog.clifreeder.com/blog/2012/07/08/leaving-janus-for-vim/" title="Leaving Janus">Clif Reeder</a> articulates when
to leave Janus quite well. <a href="http://www.benorenstein.com/blog/your-first-vimrc-should-be-nearly-empty/" title="Minimal .vimrc">Ben Orenstein</a> supports this tip too.</li>
<li>Keep it simple! The more you stray from default, the more dependant you are on
your own configuration. Use plugins in order to extend functionality. If you can&rsquo;t
explain every line of your own <code>.vimrc</code> then either figure it out, or remove it.</li>
<li>As you grow more comfortable, start using vim everywhere. If you use <strong>gmail</strong>, turn
on the keyboard shortcuts (some of them are vim like). If you&rsquo;re using Chrome,
install <a href="http://vimium.github.io/">Vimium</a>. It allows you to navigate the browser
as if it&rsquo;s vim. There&rsquo;s even
<a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/59ca71b3-a4a3-46ca-8fe1-0e90e3f79329">VsVim</a>
for Visual Studio users!</li>
</ul>


<p>Admittedly, I still have a lot to learn. I&rsquo;m by no means an expert.</p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong> &ndash; I&rsquo;m a &ldquo;learn it the hard way&rdquo; type of person. So that may explain
my thoughts on the subject.</p>

<p>Hope you enjoyed the first of what could be many &ldquo;valuable links&rdquo; posts.</p>

<h3>Addendum</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://dougblack.io/words/a-good-vimrc.html">A Good Vimrc</a></li>
<li><a href="http://nvie.com/posts/how-i-boosted-my-vim/">How I Boosted My Vim</a></li>
<li><a href="http://stevelosh.com/blog/2010/09/coming-home-to-vim/">Coming Home to Vim</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
