<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>links on More Muc Than You Can Handle</title>
    <link>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/categories/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in links on More Muc Than You Can Handle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 16:16:51 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scottmuc.com/hugo/categories/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Valuable Links - Git</title>
      <link>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2019-06-30-valuable-links-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 16:16:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2019-06-30-valuable-links-git/</guid>
      <description>Why a links post about Git? There are plenty of resources, right? Exactly! There&amp;rsquo;s almost too many resources around Git and you can reach a profiency in Git with just a few.
For fun, check out the results of this search for git books vs svn books. Hopefully this post will help you to never need to go through that list.
Some Opinions It&amp;rsquo;s funny to me that git is a tool one can become skilled at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuable Links - TLS</title>
      <link>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2017-03-06-valuable-links-tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 21:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2017-03-06-valuable-links-tls/</guid>
      <description>This is embarassing to admit but I have to re-learn Transport Layer Security (TLS) on a continuous basis. This post is my cheatsheet to remembering all the itty bitty details, which I&amp;rsquo;ll forgot shortly after I do whatever TLS related task I have on my plate.
What&amp;rsquo;s TLS you ask? Take 9 minutes to listen to this fantastic episode on Public key cryptography which will prime (hah!) you up for the rest of the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuable Links - Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2014-10-16-valuable-links-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 11:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2014-10-16-valuable-links-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>{% img right /images/blog/podcasts/podcast.jpg 300 %} It&amp;rsquo;s quite surprising that I haven&amp;rsquo;t really brought up the topic of podcasts on my blog considering that I&amp;rsquo;ve been consuming them for almost 10 years! My methods and taste have changed a lot over the years. I want a place to point people when asked about what podcasts I listen to, and with a little more context than just a pure list.
Software / Tools A podcast is such a simple concept (from the technical side) that it allows for a lot of tools and applications to be created around the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuable Links - Devops</title>
      <link>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2014-02-24-valuable-links-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 05:17:52 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2014-02-24-valuable-links-devops/</guid>
      <description>Valuable Links for Devops TL;DR - Watch this video and read the 10 myths of DevOps (which also links to what I now find is the best video on devops).
Since I first learned the term devops 4 years ago I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through many leaps in understanding. I really wish I saw this video (history of devops) before I got involved. As a software developer, I find delivering frequently highly motivating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuable Links - Vim</title>
      <link>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2013-11-03-valuable-links-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scottmuc.com/hugo/blog/2013-11-03-valuable-links-vim/</guid>
      <description>First Off - Introducing Valuable Links Today I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start something new. I tend to send my friends and colleagues links about all sorts of things. Usually when they are pertinent to a problem they are having, or to supplement a conversation I&amp;rsquo;ve had with them. My usual process to reproduce these links ends up being a search in: Twitter, Pocket, History, and my Bookmarks.
Also, when I share my links I tend to write a few sentences about them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
